<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1" scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
		<eadid mainagencycode="nic" countrycode="us" publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections//TEXT(US::NIC::RMA01948::Guide to the Cornell University museum items)//EN">RMA01948</eadid>
		<filedesc>
			<titlestmt>
				<titleproper>Guide to the Cornell University museum items,<date>[ca.
						1869-1992]</date></titleproper>
				<titleproper type="sort">Cornell University museum items</titleproper>
				<author>Compiled by RMC Staff</author>
			</titlestmt>
			<publicationstmt>
				<publisher>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University
					Library</publisher>
				<date>July 2009</date>
			</publicationstmt>
			<notestmt>
				<note audience="internal">
					<p>
						<subject>ezrac</subject>
						<subject>rghis</subject>
						<subject>physc</subject>
						<subject>euro</subject>
						<subject>finart</subject>
						<subject>sport</subject>
						<subject>easia</subject>
						<subject>agric</subject>
					</p>
				</note>
			</notestmt>
		</filedesc>
		<profiledesc>
			<creation>Finding aid encoded by Evan Fay Earle, <date>July 2009</date></creation>
		</profiledesc>
	</eadheader>
	<frontmatter>
		<titlepage>
			<titleproper>Guide to the Cornell University Museum Items,<lb/><date type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">[ca. 1869-1992]</date></titleproper>
			<num>Collection Number: 47-7-1948</num>
			<publisher>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections <lb/>Cornell University
				Library</publisher>
			<list type="deflist">
				<defitem>
					<label>Contact Information:</label>
					<item> Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections<lb/> 2B Carl A. Kroch
						Library<lb/> Cornell University<lb/> Ithaca, NY 14853<lb/> (607)
						255-3530<lb/> Fax: (607) 255-9524<lb/><extref href="mailto:rareref@cornell.edu">rareref@cornell.edu</extref><lb/><extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu">http://rmc.library.cornell.edu</extref><lb/></item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>Compiled by:</label>
					<item>RMC Staff</item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>Date completed:</label>
					<item>Various</item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>EAD encoding:</label>
					<item>Evan Fay Earle, July 2009</item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>Date modified:</label>
					<item>RMC staff, September 2015</item>
				</defitem> 
			</list>
			<date>© 2009 Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University
				Library</date>
		</titlepage>
	</frontmatter>
	<archdesc level="collection">
		<did>
			<head id="a1">DESCRIPTIVE SUMMARY</head>
			<unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="MARC 245">Cornell University museum items,
					<unitdate encodinganalog="MARC 245" type="inclusive">[ca. 1869-1992]</unitdate>
			</unittitle>
			<unitid label="Collection Number:">47-7-1948</unitid>
			<origination label="Creator:">
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110">Cornell University.</corpname>
			</origination>
			<physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Memorabilia</physdesc>
			<repository label="Repository:">Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell
				University Library</repository>
			<abstract label="Abstract:">Includes two Cornell plaques, one ca.1907, depicting Ezra
				Cornell; a red cap bearing a "C" with the initials "UFBT"; an original Uris Library
				Reading Room chair; a rubber mold for the Cornell Seal; and a bronze medallion
				bearing a likeness of Ezra Cornell. A set of twelve mulberry colored Wedgwood plates
				depicting Cornell University buildings; scenes depicted are McGraw Tower (Library
				Tower), Willard Straight Hall, the War Memorial, Baker Laboratory of Chemistry, Sage
				Chapel, McGraw Hall, the Schoellkopf Crescent, Ezra Cornell Statue, Balch Hall,
				Myron Taylor Hall, Goldwin Smith Hall and Sibley Dome. A Class of 1958 cloth badge;
				a Class of 1921 scarf; five caps, two from the Class of 1929, one from the Class of
				1921, one from the Class of 1923, one undated; straw hat from the Class of 1934;
				nine reunion jackets, three from the Class of 1929, two from the Class of 1921, and
				one each from the Classes of 1916, 1923, 1925 (red, white and blue), and 1927; one
				polo shirt from 1923; a Cornell spoon; four Cornell service pins, ca. 1955-1970; two
				mugs from 1912; a 14" Cornell pencil; a 3"x4" "Cornell Library Club" printing plate;
				a cigarette case belonging to Ralph Gordon; a trowel wielded by President Edmund
				Ezra Day June 22 1946 on the Day Hall cornerstone.</abstract>
			<langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="041" langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial>
		</did>
		<scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520">
			<head id="a3">COLLECTION DESCRIPTION</head>
			<p>Includes two Cornell plaques, one ca.1907, depicting Ezra Cornell; a red cap bearing
				a "C" with the initials "UFBT"; an original Uris Library Reading Room chair; a
				rubber mold for the Cornell Seal; and a bronze medallion bearing a likeness of Ezra
				Cornell. A set of twelve mulberry colored Wedgwood plates depicting Cornell University
				buildings; scenes depicted are McGraw Tower (Library Tower), Willard Straight Hall,
				the War Memorial, Baker Laboratory of Chemistry, Sage Chapel, McGraw Hall, the
				Schoellkopf Crescent, Ezra Cornell Statue, Balch Hall, Myron Taylor Hall, Goldwin
				Smith Hall and Sibley Dome. A Class of 1958 cloth badge; a Class of 1921 scarf; five
				caps, two from the Class of 1929, one from the Class of 1921, one from the Class of
				1923, one undated; straw hat from the Class of 1934; nine reunion jackets, three
				from the Class of 1929, two from the Class of 1921, and one each from the Classes of
				1916, 1923, 1925 (red, white and blue), and 1927; one polo shirt from 1923; a
				Cornell spoon; four Cornell service pins, ca. 1955-1970; two mugs from 1912; a 14"
				Cornell pencil; a 3"x4" "Cornell Library Club" printing plate; a cigarette case
				belonging to Ralph Gordon; a trowel wielded by President Edmund Ezra Day June 22
				1946 on the Day Hall cornerstone.</p>
			<p>Cornell plaque with wood shield and brass mounted seal, ca. 1927, belonging to
				Clarence Ames Dayton; 3 posters for Farmers Week, 1910; mail slot and restroom sign
				from Roberts Hall; graffiti sample from Roberts Hall; and a Cornell banner from a
				member of the Class of 1925.</p>
			<p>Also, library seal, n.d.; brass plaque that marked the site of early faculty
				residences; a set of portraits of Cornell University presidents from Andrew Dickson
				White to Dale Corson; a printing block for a map of Cornell University during World
				War II, "drawn by Ralph G. Warner with acknowledgments to Ellen Edmonsen's map made
				in 1928"; a Cornell banner; a wood water pipe, c. 1875, 6'x6", removed from East
				Avenue, near Sage College; illuminated poem "The Hill" by Albert W. Smith; a "C"
				megaphone; 3" pewter owl with Cornell crest; two baseball bats, on one is recorded
				"Cornell 8 Harvard 5 Ithaca, May 7, 1898" (Kelton White, '01); cane of Thomas A.
				Hamilton, '69; King of Hearts Cornell postcard; Cornell souvenir plate made by
				Rowland and Marcellus Company; carte de visite holder, Junior Promenade, 1902; c.
				1930s chart: Rate of Forgetting; 1918 watch fob; gold pin with Cornell emblem;
				Cornell bottle cap remover; red felt pillow with white lettering and leather Cornell
				shield; a Cornell University lock, 1890; a Cornell cadet helmet, 1890. Two pots
				crafted by Elijah Cornell, an 1891 Senior Ball medal, invitation, and bow tie, Class
				of 1923 cow, Book and Bowl key owned by Lord Keith Murray; Cornell Campus Store bag,
				straw hat, pillow, and bird cigar snuffer.</p>
			<p>Collection includes an historical set of three photographs recollecting the baseball
				accomplishment of Franklin W. Olin, and describes his home run of circa 175 yards
				from near Morrill Hall to near Sage Chapel; Cornell University floor runner; a
				pennant; a Cornell corncob pipe; a miscellany of Cornell buttons. Slides of Sage
				College; University of Philippines honorary plate for Dr. Emil Q. Javier. Also,
				Class of 1921 tie and shirt, Class of 1930 button, decals, coasters, pennants, a
				wooden wall plaque, a Reis Tennis Center flyer, and a t-shirt (C.U. in
				Philadelphia); large Cornell Seal press; three College of Architecture medals; a
				Balch Hall dining room plate; Sage Hall dining room plate; Class of 1932 reunion
				vest; Class of 1921 scarf and tie. Includes a Cornell stein, and a framed drawing of
				a Cornell "C" perched between the gorges, by David Seccombe.</p>
			<p>Also, items relating to Franklin W. Olin, University benefactor, include his
				appointment as a Corporal in the Cornell Corps of Cadets (May 5, 1882) signed by
				Andrew Dickson White; a framed display of various ribbons won by Olin for athletic
				accomplishment and Field Day feats and victories. Two brass plaques, for Clara
				Dickson White and Horace White, parents of Andrew Dickson White.</p>
			<p>Also, glassware with Cornell insignia: 6 brandy snifters, 12 large water glasses, 19
				smaller water glasses, 9 high ball glasses, 1 Cornell mug, 1934; Wedgewood China
				with Cornell insignia-4 green tea cups, 5 green saucers, 6 blue tea cups and
				saucers, 5 red tea cups and saucers.</p>
			<p>Also, plaque of Ezra Cornell presented by the Chinese Cornell Alumni of North China
				in commemoration of Cornell's semi-centennial in June 1919 and a medallion of McGraw
				Tower.</p>
			<p>Kroch Library construction t-shirt, 1992.</p>
			<p>Demitasse spoons from Hotel Ezra Cornell and two with the Clock Tower on them.</p>
			<p>Piece of Willard Straight Hall elm tree stump mounted in wooden box.</p>
			<p>"Hats Off to Hunter!" hat, signed by President Hunter R. Rawlings, April 28,
				2003.</p>
			<p>"Flapper" dress worn by Mrs. Lyman P. Wilson to the inaugural dinner for President
				Livingston Farrand, held in Risley Hall dining room and attended by the Cornell
				faculty, 1921. Also, top hat from Brooks Brothers in hat box.</p>
			<p>A man's stick pin with an enameled pennant at the top. The pennant is waving in the
				breeze and has carnellian color on the top half and white on the bottom half and the
				word CORNELL overprinted on the center.</p>
			<p>Junior Smoker committee poster, 1906 (framed).</p>
			<p>Also one mug "College of Agriculture and Life Sciences/We grow the ivy."</p>
			<p>Two silver bracelets: one 1.5" cuff with Cornell seal, one .5" with seal and images
				of winter sports (hockey, skiing, snowshoes, toboggan) belonging to Professor Loren
				C. Petry.</p>
			<p>Also, one lantern slide projector.</p>
			<p>Cornell mugs presented to Commencement volunteers, 1993, 1996, 1997, 1999, 2001,
				2002, 2003.</p>
			<p>Framed first day covers of Liberty Hyde Bailey and Justin Smith Morrill presented to
				Frank Rhodes.</p>
			<p>1909 ceramic Cornell mug and miniature silver-plate Cornell mug owned by William Leo O'Hara (Class of 1909).  Also 1901 ceramic Cornell mug.</p>
			<p>Cornell red leather sewing kit.</p>
			<p>Framed poem, "The Hill," by Albert W. Smith.</p>
			<p>Pennsylvania Railroad brakeman’s flag, retrieved by Cornellian John Kent '48 after the Cornell Football victory of Penn in November 1948. Has score carved on it and comes with Kent’s account of the event and some notes on Cornell football teams of that era.</p>
			<p>Souvenir plate of Libe Tower, American Decorators, Inc., n.d.</p>
			<p>Cornell Laundry bag issued to freshmen in 1952</p>
			<p>McGraw Tower pewter bookends, custom designed by 15 Steps in Ithaca, and originally given to Library staff and later to donors and friends.</p>
			<p>Class of 1941 wool blazer belonging to Ray S. Watson '41.</p>
			<p>Bronze Ezra Cornell seal door knocker.</p>
		</scopecontent>
		<controlaccess>
			<head id="a7">SUBJECTS</head>
			<controlaccess>
				<head>Names: </head>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110">Cornell University.</corpname>
				<persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Cornell, Elijah. </persname>
				<persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Cornell, Ezra, 1807-1874.</persname>
				<persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Day, Edmund Ezra, 1883-1951.</persname>
				<persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Dayton, Clarence Ames. </persname>
				<persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Farrand, Livingston, 1867-1939.</persname>
				<persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Hamilton, Thomas A. </persname>
				<persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Javier, Emil Q. </persname>
				<persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Murray of Newhaven, Keith Anderson Hope,
					1903-</persname>
				<persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Olin, Franklin W. </persname>
				<persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Petry, Loren C.(Loren Clifford), b.
					1887.</persname>
				<persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Smith, Albert W. (Albert William), 1856-1942.</persname>
				<persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">White, Kelton. </persname>
				<persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Wilson, Lyman P., </persname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Baker Laboratory of Chemistry (Cornell
					University)</corpname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Balch Hall (Cornell University)</corpname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Cornell University--Insignia.</corpname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Cornell University.Class of 1923.</corpname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Cornell University.Class of 1921.</corpname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Cornell University.Class of 1930.</corpname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Cornell University.Class of 1988.</corpname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Cornell University.Class of 1934.</corpname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Cornell University.Class of 1925.</corpname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Cornell University.Class of 1941.</corpname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Cornell University.War Memorial.</corpname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Goldwin Smith Hall (Cornell
					University)</corpname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">McGraw Hall (Cornell University)</corpname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">McGraw Tower (Cornell University)</corpname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Myron Taylor Hall (Cornell
					University)</corpname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Sage Chapel (Cornell University)</corpname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Schoellkopf Memorial Stadium (Cornell
					University)</corpname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Sibley Dome (Cornell University)</corpname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Willard Straight Hall (Ithaca, N.Y.)</corpname>
			</controlaccess>
			<controlaccess>
				<head>Subjects:</head>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Glassware--United States.</subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Chairs.</subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Wedgwood ware.</subject>
			</controlaccess>
			<controlaccess>
				<head>Form and Genre Terms:</head>
				<genreform encodinganalog="MARC 655" source="aat">T-shirts.</genreform>
				<genreform encodinganalog="MARC 655" source="aat">Chemise dresses.</genreform>
				<genreform encodinganalog="MARC 655" source="aat">Beadwork.</genreform>
			</controlaccess>
		</controlaccess>
		<descgrp>
			<head id="a8">INFORMATION FOR USERS</head>
			<prefercite>
				<head>Cite As:</head>
				<p>Cornell University museum items, #47-7-1948. Division of Rare and Manuscript
					Collections, Cornell University Library.</p>
			</prefercite>
		</descgrp>
		<odd type="notes">
			<head id="a5">NOTES</head>
			<p>McGraw Tower (Library Tower) Wedgwood plate is cracked.</p>
		</odd>
		<dsc type="combined">
			<head>CONTAINER LIST</head>
			<c01 level="series">
				<did>
					<unittitle>
						<extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/EAD/pdf_guides/RMA01948.pdf">Link to a partial finding aid. PDF file.</extref>
					</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Not all the material in the collection is covered by this guide.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
		</dsc>
	</archdesc>
</ead>
