<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../styles/style.xsl" ?>
			<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
	<eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1"
		scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
		<eadid mainagencycode="nic" countrycode="us"
			publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections//TEXT(US::NIC::RMA03934::Guide to the Lourdes Benería papers)//EN"
			>RMA03934.xml</eadid>
		<filedesc>
			<titlestmt>
				<titleproper>Guide to the Lourdes Benería
					papers,<date>1974-2008.</date></titleproper>
				<titleproper type="sort">Benería, Lourdes papers</titleproper>
				<author>Compiled by RMC Staff</author>
			</titlestmt>
			<publicationstmt>
				<publisher>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University
					Library</publisher>
				<date>November 2011</date>
			</publicationstmt>
			<notestmt>
				<note audience="internal">
					<p><subject>plan</subject></p>
				</note>
			</notestmt>
		</filedesc>
		<profiledesc>
			<creation>Finding aid encoded by RMC Staff, <date>November 2011</date></creation>
		</profiledesc>
	</eadheader>
	<frontmatter>
		<titlepage>
			<titleproper>Guide to the Lourdes Benería Papers,<lb/><date type="inclusive"
					encodinganalog="245$f">1974-2008.</date></titleproper>
			<num>Collection Number: 15-2-3934</num>
			<publisher>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections <lb/>Cornell University
				Library</publisher>
			<list type="deflist">
				<defitem>
					<label>Contact Information:</label>
					<item> Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections<lb/> 2B Carl A. Kroch
						Library<lb/> Cornell University<lb/> Ithaca, NY 14853<lb/> (607)
						255-3530<lb/> Fax: (607) 255-9524<lb/><extref
							href="mailto:rareref@cornell.edu"
							>rareref@cornell.edu</extref><lb/><extref
							href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu"
							>http://rmc.library.cornell.edu</extref><lb/></item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>Compiled by:</label>
					<item>RMC Staff</item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>Date completed:</label>
					<item>November 2011</item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>EAD encoding:</label>
					<item>Allison Arnold, November 2011</item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>Date modified:</label>
					<item>RMC Staff, November 2011</item>
				</defitem>
			</list>
			<date>© 2011 Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University
				Library</date>
		</titlepage>
	</frontmatter>
	<archdesc level="collection">
		<did>
			<head id="a1">DESCRIPTIVE SUMMARY</head>
			<unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="MARC 245">Lourdes Benería papers, <unitdate
					encodinganalog="MARC 245" type="inclusive">1974-2008.</unitdate>
			</unittitle>
			<unitid label="Collection Number:">15-2-3934</unitid>
			<origination label="Creator:"><persname encodinganalog="100" normal="Benería, Lourdes ">
				Benería </persname></origination>
			<physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="MARC 300">2 cubic feet.</physdesc>
			<physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Correspondence, publications</physdesc>
			<repository label="Repository:">Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell
				University Library</repository>
			<abstract label="Abstract:">Includes subject files, conference proceedings, lecture
				notes, related to her career at Cornell University and her work concerning labor,
				women's work, gender and development, globalization, and Latin American development.
				</abstract>
			<langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="041"
					langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial>
		</did>
		<bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
			<head id="a2" altrender="biography">BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE </head>
			<p>Lourdes Benería is a Professor Emerita in Cornell University's Department of City and Regional Planning. She was born in Catalonia, Spain and received her Licenciatura from the University of Barcelona in 1961. She studied economics at Columbia University, earning a M.Ph. in 1974 and a Ph.D.in 1975. She was an assistant and then associate professor at Rutgers University from 1975-1986. She began teaching at Cornell University's Department of City and Regional Planning in 1987 with a dual appointment in Gender, Feminist and Sexuality Studies. She was the first woman tenured in the Department of City and Regional Planning. Among other courses, she taught "International Institutions", "Public and Spatial Economics" and "Globalization and Development." At Cornell, at various times, she directed the Latin American Studies Program, the Gender and Global Change Program and the International Studies Program. She has been a visiting faculty member or guest lecturer at Columbia University, Rutgers University, the New School University and other universities in the United States and in Spain. 
				
				<lb/>Benería's work and publications have focused on issues related to labor and the informal economy, women's work, gender and development, globalization, and Latin American development. This work has led her at various times to serve as president of the International Association for Feminist Economics (IAFFE), associate editor of Feminist Economics and The European Journal of Development Research, and a member of the Editorial Board of Economia Crítica among other positions. Parallel to her academic work, Beneria has been involved in activities of international organizations such as the International Labor Organization (ILO), United Nations Development Fund for Women (UNIFEM), and the United Nations Development Programme (UNDP). She was part of a team of international observers in Nicaragua for their elections in 1990. She served on the International Advisory Committee for the UNIFEM report on World's Women's Progress/2000; was a member of the International Advisory Board for the ILO's Global Programme on Socioeconomic Security (2000–04); and, was a member of UNDP's Directory of Appointed Experts on Poverty in Latin America and the Caribbean. Beneria is a recipient of the Narcis Monturiol Award given by the Catalan government for her contribution to the social sciences.
			</p>
		</bioghist>
		<scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520">
			<head id="a3">COLLECTION DESCRIPTION</head>
			<p>Includes subject files, conference proceedings, lecture notes, related to her career
				at Cornell University and her work concerning labor, women's work, gender and
				development, globalization, and Latin American development. Also publications and
				notes related to the Nicaraguan Institute for Women (INIM)and the 1990 Nicaraguan
				election.</p>
		</scopecontent>
		<controlaccess>
			<head id="a7">SUBJECTS</head>
			<controlaccess>
				<head>Names: </head>
				<persname encodinganalog="MARC 100">Benería, Lourdes</persname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Cornell University--Faculty.</corpname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Cornell University.College of Architecture, Art,
					and Planning.</corpname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 710">Nicaraguan Institute for Women
					(INIM).</corpname>
			</controlaccess>
			<controlaccess>
				<head>Subjects:</head>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Women in development.</subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Women--Employment.</subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Feminist economics.</subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Labor policy--Latin America.</subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Sex discrimination against women--Economic
					aspects--Latin America.</subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Women in rural development.</subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Globalization.</subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Elections--Nicaragua.</subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Labor market--Developing countries.</subject>
			</controlaccess>
		</controlaccess>
		<descgrp>
			<head id="a8">INFORMATION FOR USERS</head>
			<prefercite>
				<head>Cite As:</head>
				<p>Lourdes Benería papers, #15-2-3934. Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections,
					Cornell University Library.</p>
			</prefercite>
		</descgrp>
		<dsc type="combined">
			<head>CONTAINER LIST</head>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">1</container>
					<unitdate>1985-1992</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Publication "The Crossroads of Class and Gender"</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Documents related to "The Crossroads of Class and Gender": Book Contract, Correspondence with Publishers, Publication Announcements, Book Advertisements, Book Reviews, Correspondence regarding Spanish translation.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">2</container>
					<unitdate>2003</unitdate>
					<unittitle>International Association of Feminist Economics (IAFFE) Presidency</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>IAFFE Bulletin of January 2003, Brochure, Proposal to SIDA "Furthering Research on Cutting-Edge Issues in Feminist Economics: 'Gender and Aging'", Board Meeting Minutes January 2, 2003.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">3</container>
					<unitdate>2004-2005</unitdate>
					<unittitle>International Association of Feminist Economics (IAFFE) Strategic Plan</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>"A Final Report with Recommendations Related to IAFFE's Future Structure and Sustainability" by Susan Kenny Stevens, Ph.D., Consultant with LarsonAllen Public Service Group, 2004.<lb/>
					Email correspondence regarding the Strategic Planning Committee's Final Report, 2005.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">4</container>
					<unitdate>2003-2004</unitdate>
					<unittitle>International Association of Feminist Economics (IAFFE) Consultancy and Ford Proposal</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Proposal to the Ford Foundation for Funding of the Strategic Plan Report by LarsonAllen.<lb/>
					Email Correspondence, Invoices, Strategic Planning Committee Meeting Notes.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">5</container>
					<unitdate>1987-1995</unitdate>
					<unittitle>September 19th Garment Workers</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p> "This material could be interesting for historians working on Mexico (and maybe other social scientists). It's not easy to find it."-A note from Lourdes Benería.<lb/>
					Newsletters, Publications, Correspondence, and Articles from: Interhemispheric Resource Center, Interchange/Woman to Woman, The "19th of September" Garment Workers Union, American Friends Service Committee-Listen Real Loud, Women's Project, Correspondencia (a Mexican Newsletter-in English, multiple issues), "Working Women and the 19th of September, Mexican Garment Workers Union: The Significance of Gender" by Teresa Carrillo, 1988.</p>				
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">6</container>
					<unitdate>October 1998- November 1998</unitdate>
					<unittitle>World Bank Consultancy Letters and Initial Documents - "Brazil Gender Review"</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>"Consultancy for the World Bank to review the Bank's programs on gender related to: education, labor, health, violence against women, and other issues in Brazil. Draft report included. October 20-November 18, 1988."-A note from Lourdes Benería.<lb/>
					Correspondence, Notes, List of Interviews and Consultations, Tables, References, Draft of "Brazil Gender Review."</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">7</container>
					<unitdate>1993-1999</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Smith-Corona Study</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>"Smith-Corona Project: Final paper published in Economic Development Quarterly, Vol. 15, No1 (2001) and updated for my book "Gender, Development and Globalization" Routledge, 2003, Chapter 4."<lb/>
					Project Proposal for "The Impact of Industrial Relocation on Rural Communities."<lb/>
					"Planning Study of the City of Cortland," 1994, This report was produced by a class of 32 entering professional students in Cornell University's Department of City and Regional Planning.<lb/>
					Newspaper Clippings, CARDI Newsletter, Correspondence, Email Correspondence.<lb/>
					Interview Notes with laid-off workers.<lb/>
					Revision notes from Economic Development Quarterly.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">8</container>
					<unitdate>1993-1999</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Smith-Corona Study: Questionnaires</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Economic Restructuring and Community Development: Questionnaire for Smith-Corona Workers.<lb/>
					Economic Restructuring and Community Development: Follow-Up Questionnaire for Smith-Corona Workers.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">9</container>
					<unitdate>1993-1999</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Cortland: General Info 1</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Sample Surveys and Complied Results from the Cayuga-Cortland Private Industry Council, used with the Corona employees: Dislocated Worker, Occupational Interests, Training Interests.<lb/>
					"Statement of Gary and Evelyn Allen", Former Employees of Smith Corona Corporation At a Hearing Before the Subcommittee on Labor... The Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification (WARN) Act, February 23, 1993.<lb/>
					Newspaper Clippings, Correspondence, Meeting Minutes.<lb/>
					"Social Cost Analysis of Layoffs of Smith Corona Workers in NY" prepared by the Midwest Center for Labor Research, October 1992.<lb/>
					Tompkins/Cortland Labor Coalition Bulletin regarding plant closure.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">10</container>
					<unitdate>1993-1999</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Cortland: General Info 2</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Citations in Newspaper Articles Database.<lb/>
					Plant Shutdown Bibliography.<lb/>
					"The Effects of Advance Notice on Displaced Manufacturing Workers:A Case Study" by Allison Zippay, 1993.<lb/>
					Charts, Graphs, Tables, Demographic and Economic Data, Maps.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">11</container>
					<unitdate>1960-1975</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Anti-Franco Activities (1960's and Early 1970's) 1</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Newspaper Clippings and Copies (English, Spanish, French, and British), Articles, Correspondence, Documents.<lb/>
					U.S. Committee for a Democratic Spain, U.S. Committee for the Carabanchel 10, The Public Prosecutor: The Court of Public Order: Madrid, The Spanish Ambassador to the United States.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">12</container>
					<unitdate>1960-1975</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Anti-Franco Activities (1960's and Early 1970's) 2</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Newspaper Clippings and Copies (English, Spanish, French, and British), Articles, Correspondence, Documents.<lb/>
					U.S. Committee for a Democratic Spain, U.S. Committee for the Carabanchel 10.<lb/>
					Statement on the Carabanchel Ten by Eugene Stockwell, Noam Chomsky, Monsignor Charles Owen Rice, Henry Foner, Angela Davis, Edward Barsky, Ossie Davis, Paul Sweeky, Haywaood Burns, Eugene McCarthy, Bella Abzug, Ramsey Clark, Leon J. Davis, Salvador Luria, David Livingston, Albert Szent-Gyorgi.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">13</container>
					<unitdate>1983-1991</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Wenner-Gren Foundation for Anthropological Research Grant</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Documents relating to a Petition for Grant-in-Aid from the Wenner-Gren Foundation for Anthropological Research.<lb/>
					Petition for Grant-in-Aid, Correspondence, Acceptance Letter, Bibliography, Financial Accounting.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">14</container>
					<unitdate>1996-1998</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Woodrow Wilson Application for Residential Fellowship</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Application for the Residential Fellowship, Correspondence, Acceptance Letter, Pamphlet for the Woodrow Wilson Center International Center for Scholars, List of Publications, Project Proposal ("Toward Human Development: Gender and the Global Economy"), New Fellow Announcement, Program Assessment, Address List of 1997-1998 Fellows and Guest Scholars.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">15</container>
					<unitdate>1984-1985</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Report for the United Nations on "Apoyo A La Oficina De La Mujer," Nicaragua, 1985</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Correspondence from the United Nations Office for the Integration of Women in Development and Acceptance Letter for Consultation from the United Nations Development Programme.<lb/>
					Project Report: "Apoyo A La Oficina De La Mujer"- in Spanish.<lb/>
					Notes about the Project, Documents from the Republica De Nicaragua-Oficina de la Mujer.<lb/>
					Report: Assessment for the Project "Apoyo A La Oficina De La Mujer" (NIC/84/W01) Presented to VFDW (Report of the consultancy mission undertaken by Lourdes Benería to assess the work plan to be carried out by the Women's Office, Managua, Nicaragua, January 1985)- English Copy and Spanish Translation.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">16</container>
					<unitdate>1984</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Illich-"Work and Culture; Meditations on Ivan Illich's 'Gender'"</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Copy of "Work and Culture; Meditations on Ivan Illich's 'Gender'" by Lourdes Benería, Department of Economics, Rutgers University. (Paper prepared for the Symposium on "Work in 1984--Emancipation or Derogation?", University of Karlstad, Sweden, June 17-20, 1984. Paper published in B. Gustavsson, ed, "Work in the 1980's", London.)<lb/>
					Notes on Illich on "Gender" NYU Seminar, 1/27/1984.</p>			
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">17</container>
					<unitdate>1980-1986</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Lectures and Talks</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Handwritten and Printed Lectures and Talks given at Conferences, Classes, and Events in the Americas and Europe, the majority in English, some in Spanish.<lb/>
					Topics include Feminism, Gender, Development, Economics, Globalization, Reproduction, Women's Work.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">18</container>
					<unitdate>1987-1988</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Lectures and Talks</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Handwritten and Printed Lectures and Talks given at Conferences, Classes, and Events in the Americas and Europe, the majority in English, some in Spanish.<lb/>
						Topics include Feminism, Gender, Development, Economics, Globalization, Reproduction, Women's Work.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">19</container>
					<unitdate>1989-1990</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Lectures and Talks</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Handwritten and Printed Lectures and Talks given at Conferences, Classes, and Events in the Americas and Europe, the majority in English, some in Spanish.<lb/>
						Topics include Feminism, Gender, Development, Economics, Globalization, Reproduction, Women's Work.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">20</container>
					<unitdate>1991-1992</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Lectures and Talks</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Handwritten and Printed Lectures and Talks given at Conferences, Classes, and Events in the Americas and Europe, the majority in English, some in Spanish.<lb/>
						Topics include Feminism, Gender, Development, Economics, Globalization, Reproduction, Women's Work.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">21</container>
					<unitdate>1993</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Lectures and Talks</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Handwritten and Printed Lectures and Talks given at Conferences, Classes, and Events in the Americas and Europe, the majority in English, some in Spanish.<lb/>
						Topics include Feminism, Gender, Development, Economics, Globalization, Reproduction, Women's Work.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">22</container>
					<unitdate>1994-1995</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Lectures and Talks</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Handwritten and Printed Lectures and Talks given at Conferences, Classes, and Events in the Americas and Europe, the majority in English, some in Spanish.<lb/>
						Topics include Feminism, Gender, Development, Economics, Globalization, Reproduction, Women's Work.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">23</container>
					<unitdate>1996-1997</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Lectures and Talks</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Handwritten and Printed Lectures and Talks given at Conferences, Classes, and Events in the Americas and Europe, the majority in English, some in Spanish.<lb/>
						Topics include Feminism, Gender, Development, Economics, Globalization, Reproduction, Women's Work.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">24</container>
					<unitdate>1998-1999</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Lectures and Talks</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Handwritten and Printed Lectures and Talks given at Conferences, Classes, and Events in the Americas and Europe, the majority in English, some in Spanish.<lb/>
						Topics include Feminism, Gender, Development, Economics, Globalization, Reproduction, Women's Work.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">25</container>
					<unitdate>2000-2001</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Lectures and Talks</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Handwritten and Printed Lectures and Talks given at Conferences, Classes, and Events in the Americas and Europe, the majority in English, some in Spanish.<lb/>
						Topics include Feminism, Gender, Development, Economics, Globalization, Reproduction, Women's Work.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">26</container>
					<unitdate>2002-2004</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Lectures and Talks</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Handwritten and Printed Lectures and Talks given at Conferences, Classes, and Events in the Americas and Europe, the majority in English, some in Spanish.<lb/>
					Topics include Feminism, Gender, Development, Economics, Globalization, Reproduction, Women's Work.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">27</container>
					<unitdate>2006-2007</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Lectures and Talks</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Handwritten and Printed Lectures and Talks given at Conferences, Classes, and Events in the Americas and Europe, the majority in English, some in Spanish.<lb/>
					Topics include Feminism, Gender, Development, Economics, Globalization, Reproduction, Women's Work.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">1</container>
					<unitdate>1978-1979</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Paper for the Cambridge Journal of Economics "Production and Reproduction"</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Correspondence with the Cambridge Journal of Economics, Working Paper - ILO, Suggestions for Revision, Final Draft</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">2</container>
					<unitdate>1980</unitdate>
					<unittitle>United Nations - World Conference of the Decade for Women on the theme of Equality, Development and Peace, Bella Centre, Copenhagen, 1980</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>"Reflections on the Copenhagen Conference" by Lourdes Benería. Introduction- "If you did not attend the UN Copenhagen Conference and were confused by the conflicting reports that made it to the media, you have one minor consolation: those of us who went to Copenhagen last July felt confused too." (This is a revised version of two talks on the Copenhagen Conference given at The New School for Social Research and at the Center for the Study of Human Rights, Columbia University, Fall 1980.)<lb/>
					"A Feminist View of Copenhagen" by Irene Tinker.<lb/>
					"Women of Europe", Brussels, March/April 1980 - no. 14 (A bulletin published by the Commission of the European Communities)<lb/>
					"What They Did Not Tell You About the UN Copenhagen Conferences" by Charlotte Bunch<lb/>
					"Set in an enormous glass topped forum on the outskirts of Copenhagen..." by Caren Grown<lb/>
					"Forum80" Newspaper, Copenhagen, July 14-17, 1980 and July 21-24, 1980</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01><c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">3</container>
					<unitdate>1981-1984</unitdate>
					<unittitle>SSRC Workshop and Research Grant - "Household Dynamics," Mexico</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Work on the 2nd part of research for the book "The Crossroads of Class and Gender; Subcontracting and Household Dynamics in Mexico City" Chicago University Press, 1987.<lb/>
					Invitation to the workshop on Social Inequality and Gender Relations in Latin America, Mexico City, 1983.<lb/>
					"Subcontracting Links and Gender Relations" Abstract.<lb/>
					"A brief summary of my research in Mexcio City" with Martha Roldán.<lb/>			
					"Entrevista Para Empresas Y Talleres" - questionnaire used in research.<lb/>
					Application for Advanced Research Grant.<lb/>
					Correspondence related to research grant funding from the Joint Committee on Latin American Studies of the American Council of Learned Societies and the Social Science Research Council.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01><c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">4</container>
					<unitdate>1984-1986</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Paper for The Brookings Institution "Gender and the Dynamics of Subcontracting in Mexico City"</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Correspondence regarding participation in The Brookings Institution Conference on Gender in the Work Place and subsequent publication.<lb/>
					Abstract and Vitae.
					Revised Copy of the Final Paper "Gender and the Dynamics of Subcontracting in Mexico City"</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01><c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">5</container>
					<unitdate>1986-1988</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Publication "Women, Households and the Economy"</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Correspondence between Authors and Publisher.<lb/>
					Publishing Contract with Rutgers University Press.<lb/>
					List of Authors of "Women, Households and the Economy."<lb/>
					Advertisements, Reviews, Financial Documents.<lb/>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">6</container>
					<unitdate>1988-1989</unitdate>
					<unittitle>UNIFEM: Costa Rica/Panama Reports</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Correspondence related to UNDP Office for Project Services assignment, criteria and payment.<lb/>
					Original contract documents.<lb/>
					Correspondence with Roxana Volio of UNIFEM (in Spanish).<lb/>
					Appraisal: RLA/87/PRO2 Women's Studies in Central America Short Training and Perfection Courses.<lb/>
					"Evaluacion Proyecto CSUCS/UNIFEM RLA/87/W05 Estudios de La Mujer en Centroamerica" (in Spanish) March 1989.<lb/>
					"Evaluacion Proyecto CSUCS/UNIFEM RLA/87/W05 Primer Modulo Subordinacion de la Mujer. Informe del tercer curso." (in Spanish) Panama, October-November 1988.<lb/>
					"Proyecto CSUCS/UNIFEM RLA/87/W05 Informe del Primer Curso de "Subordinacion de la Mujer". (in Spanish) San Jose, Costa Rica, April 1988.<lb/>
					"Evaluacion Proyecto CSUCS/UNIFEM RLA/87/W05 Estudios de La Mujer en Centroamerica, Primer Modulo - Subordinacion de la Mujer. Informe del Segundo Curso." (in Spanish) Tegucigalpa, Honduras. July-August 1988.<lb/>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">7</container>
					<unitdate>1989</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Summer Institute in Gender and Development, Halifax, Canada, June 1988.</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>List of Invited Speakers, Resource People and Special Guests.<lb/>
					Schedule, Biographies, Correspondence, Application Information and Application.<lb/>
					Summary of Discussion Paper "When the Margins Meet: Thoughts Arising from Women's Economic Lives in Newfoundland" - Porter.<lb/>
					The Revolving Chair: A feminist teaching strategy.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01><c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">8</container>
					<unitdate>1989</unitdate>
					<unittitle>ILO Workshop on Labor Markets and Structural Adjustment, Geneva, 1989</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Conference Schedule, Handwritten Session Notes, List of Participants.<lb/>
					November 29 - December 1, 1989.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01><c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">9</container>
					<unitdate>1989-1992</unitdate>
					<unittitle> Publication "Accounting for Women's Work: The Progress of Two Decades"</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Correspondence and suggestions for revision related to "Accounting for Women's Work: The Progress of Two Decades" from American University, Michigan State University, Institute of Ethnology - Taiwan and others.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01><c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">10</container>
					<unitdate>1991</unitdate>
					<unittitle>UN - Meeting of High-level Experts on Social Development Indicators, Rabat, April 1991</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Correspondence regarding "Meeting of High-level Experts on Social Development Indicators, Rabat, 8-11 April 1991" organized by the UN.<lb/>
					Invitation, Discussion of publication.<lb/>
					"The Measurement of Women's Economic Activities: Assessing the Theoretical and Practical Work of Two Decades" by Lourdes Benería.<lb/>
					"La Mesure de L'activité économique des femmes: évaluation du travail théorique et pratique de deux décennies." par Lourdes Benería (in French).</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01><c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">11</container>
					<unitdate>1991-1996</unitdate>
					<unittitle>UCLA Conference - Learning from Latin America: Women's Struggles for Livelihood, Los Angeles, California, 1992</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Correspondence (with John Friedmann) regarding participation in the UCLA Conference "Learning from Latin America: Women's Struggles for Livelihood", 1990-1992.<lb/>
					Correspondence regarding paper "Contextualizing Women's Struggles for Livelihood: The Foreign Debt Crisis and the Social Costs of Adjustment".<lb/>
					Copy of "Contextualizing Women's Struggles for Livelihood: The Foreign Debt Crisis and the Social Costs of Adjustment", 1992.<lb/>
					Copy of Conference Program, 1992.<lb/>
					Correspondence (with Jonathan Friedlander) regarding particiaption in the UCLA Conference "Structural Adjustment: Comparative Perspectives", 1996.<lb/>
					List of Latin American Participants, 1996.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01><c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">12</container>
					<unitdate>1992-1993</unitdate>
					<unittitle>National Committee on US-China Relations, Trip to China</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Correspondence regarding participation in study team on Economic and Social Development in China's Hinterland.<lb/>
					Mission schedule and list of participants.<lb/>
					Handwritten notes.<lb/>
					Pamphlet from Xinxing Company Sichuan.<lb/>	
					"Economic Development and Human Rights in China's Interior" co-authored by Lourdes Benería, 1993.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">13</container>
					<unitdate>1993</unitdate>
					<unittitle>University of Wisconsin Conference - Sustainable Development with Equity in the 1990s: Policies and Alternatives, 1993</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Correspondence regarding participation in the conference on "Sustainable Development with Equity in the 1990s: Policies and Alternatives".<lb/>
					Conference Schedule, List of Participants, Contact Information.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">14</container>
					<unitdate>1993</unitdate>
					<unittitle>African National Congress Workshop on Unpaid Labor and Economic Policy, Johannesburg, South Africa, 1993</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Correspondence regarding participation in the workshop "Unpaid labour and Economic Policy" organized by the African National Congress - Commission on the Emancipation of Women.<lb/>
					List of Participants, Copy of "Accounting for Women's Work: The Progress of Two Decades", Workshop Proposal, Draft of Published Proceedings of the Workshop, Handwritten notes.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">15</container>
					<unitdate>1993-1994</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Salt Lake City Paper</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Correspondence with the University of Utah.<lb/>
					"Gender, Adjustment and Macroeconomic Models" by Cagatay, Elson and Grown - Proposal to the Ford Foundation, 1993.<lb/>
					Handwritten Notes from "2nd Meeting", Salt Lake City, 1994.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">16</container>
					<unitdate>1993-1994</unitdate>
					<unittitle>UNRISD Project - Economic Restructuring and New Social Policies</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Correspondence regarding UNRISD's research project "Economic Restructuring and New Social Policies".<lb/>
					Project Proposal.<lb/>
					Copy of "Structural Adjustment and Social Emergency Funds: The Cases of Honduras, Mexico and Nicaragua" by Lourdes Benería and Brendy Mendoza. Paper published in "The European Journal of Development Research, Vol 7, No.1 (June 1995) and reprinted in Adjustment and Social Sector Restructuring".</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">17</container>
					<unitdate>1994-1995</unitdate>
					<unittitle>UNDP - Human Development Report and Development Index Meetings, 1995 and 1996</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Correspondence related to contribution to the 1995 and 1996 Human Development Reports.<lb/>
					Notes on Meeting of HDR96, April 22, 1995.<lb/>
					1996 Human Development Report Proposed Outline.<lb/>
					Endorsement Form for a new indicator of progress and correspondence from Redefining Progress.<lb/>
					List of Participants of Brainstorming Meeting on HDR95, September 22, 1994.<lb/>
					Copy of "Engendering Political Economy" by Meghnad Desai, September 1994.<lb/>
					"Notes on the Outline of the 1995 Human development Report by Professor Antonella Picchio, Department of Political Economy, University of Modena, Italy"</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">18</container>
					<unitdate>1994</unitdate>
					<unittitle>North-South Institute Conference, Ottawa, Canada, 1994</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Correspondence regarding participation in the "Expert Group Meeting on Women and Global Economic Restructuring".<lb/>
					Questions for the group meeting, from Lourdes Benería.<lb/>
					Meeting Information and Agenda, Participant Address List.<lb/>	
					Questionnaire Responses.<lb/>
					"Expert Group Meeting on Women and Global Economic Restructuring,  June 20-22, 1994, Ottawa, Canada, Final Report".</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">19</container>
					<unitdate>1994-1995</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Swedish International Development Authority Workshop - A Vision for Gender and Development Cooperation, Stockholm, Sweden, 1995</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Correspondence related to Workshop "A Vision for Gender and Development Cooperation," January 30-February 3, 1995, Stockholm, Sweden.<lb/>
					Participant Contact List.<lb/>
					"A Vision for Gender and Development Cooperation" by Lourdes Benería, written for the conference, with hand-written additions.<lb/>
					Background information on the workshop.<lb/>
					Draft of workshop result paper "Towards Gender-Equitable and Sustainable Human Development" and revision notes.<lb/>
					"Individual Vision Papers Prepared for the Think-Tank Workshop 'A Vision for Gender and Development Cooperation'"<lb/>
					Correspondence related to SIDA Workshop on "Gender, Macroeconomics and Poverty," May 31st-June 2, 1995.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">20</container>
					<unitdate>1995</unitdate>
					<unittitle> Universidad Nacional De Colombia Conference - "Debates Feministas Frente Al Nuevo Siglo," Bogota, Columbia, 1995</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Correspondence related to the Universidad Nacional De Colombia Conference "Debates Feministas Frente Al Nuevo Siglo: Mujeres, Democracia y Desarrollo en America Latina," (in Spanish) November 20, 1995.<lb/>
					Conference program (in Spanish).<lb/>
					Handwritten notes (in Spanish).</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">21</container>
					<unitdate>1995</unitdate>
					<unittitle>UNDP Workshop on Poverty Elimination, New York City, 1995</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Correspondence related to UNDP "Workshop on Selective Approaches and Practices for Eliminating Poverty," October 30-November 1, 1995, New York City.<lb/>
					Workshop Information: Terms of Reference - Consultancy on Gender and Poverty, Outline of Facilitators, Resource People and Sessions.<lb/>
					An Annotated Outline "Engendering Measures to Eradicate Poverty" submitted by Savitri Bisnath, August 25, 1995.<lb/>
					Bionote of Lourdes Bernería for UNDP.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">22</container>
					<unitdate>1996</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Harvard Conference on "Gender, Development and Macroeconomics," Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1996</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Correspondence related to Harvard Conference on "Gender, Development and Macroeconomics," Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1996, from The John D. and Catherine T. MacArthur Foundation and the Harvard Institute for International Development.<lb/>
					Preliminary Agenda, Agenda, Dinner Seating Arrangement, Conference Announcement, DoubleTree Guest Suites-Conference Guest List, Participant List.<lb/>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">23</container>
					<unitdate>1996-1997</unitdate>
					<unittitle>MacArthur Grant Application - Sabbatical Year</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Correspondence with, application to and project description of the John D. and Catherine T. MacArthur Foundation- Program on Peace and International Cooperation- Research and Writing Grants for Individuals.<lb/>
					Final Report to the Foundation on the results of the grant-funded work: list of publications and completed book "Gender, Development and Globalization: Economics as if People Mattered."<lb/>
					Foundation Pamphlet and Reporting Guidelines.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">24</container>
					<unitdate>1997-1997</unitdate>
					<unittitle>1997 UNDP Human Development Report Advisory Panel</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Correspondence related to the 1997 UNDP Poverty and Human Development Report and the Advisory Panel Meeting.<lb/>
					Annotated Outline of the 1997 UNDP Report.
					Revision notes on the Draft of the 1997 UNDP Report.
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">25</container>
					<unitdate>1996-1998</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Radcliffe Public Policy Institute Fellowship</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Correspondence related to appointment as a Radcliffe College Public Policy Fellow (July 1, 1996-June 30, 1997).<lb/>
					Orientation Schedule for Fellows, Address List of Fellows and Visiting Professor, RPPI Staff Phone List.<lb/>
					"Brief Description of Research Plans for Fellowship Year."<lb/>
					"Project Description" (From the MacArthur Proposal).<lb/>
					Radcliffe Public Policy Institute Policy Seminar Series Pamphlet 1997-1998, and other publications from RPPI.<lb/>
					Meeting Notes.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">26</container>
					<unitdate>1998</unitdate>
					<unittitle>UN Workshop - World Survey on the Role of Women in Development, Geneva</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>List of workshop participants and contact information.<lb/>
					Correspondence regarding reimbursement for travel expenses.<lb/>
					Working Draft "Chapter III. Major World Trends, Section D. Migration: aspects of labour mobility" prepared by the International Research and Training Insititute for the Advancement of Women (INSTRAW).</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">27</container>
					<unitdate>1998</unitdate>
					<unittitle>University of Rochester Conference - Forum 98: Setting a Course for Women into the 21st Century, Seneca Falls, New York, 1998.</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Correspondence regarding participation in the conference "Forum 98: Setting a Course for Women into the 21st Century" organized by the University of Rochester and Hobart and William Smith Colleges with major funding from the Ford Foundation and others.<lb/>
					Conference Brochure and Program.<lb/>
					Handwritten notes for lecture given on July 15, 1998.<lb/>
					Xerox "Figure 4.2 - Most of women's work remains unpaid, unrecognized and undervalued. SNA and non-SNA work."<lb/>
					Xerox from UN Human Development Report 1995 "Table A2.3 - Women and Economic Opportunities."
					Copy of newspaper article from the Rochester Democrat and Chronicle "The Cradle Rocks: Birthplace of Women's Rights Prepares for big year."<lb/>
					Copies of the Declaration of Sentiments and Declaration of Sentiments reaffirmation statement.<lb/>
					Copy of Universal Declaration of Human Rights<lb/>
					Copy of "The Three State Strategy for ERA Ammendment - Summary"</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">28</container>
					<unitdate>1998</unitdate>
					<unittitle>World Bank Workshop - "Gender and Development," Washington, D.C., April 2-3, 1998</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Correspondence related to participation in the World Bank Workshop "Gender and Development."<lb/>
					Workshop Agenda.<lb/>
					Summary of presentation given in the panel discussion with revision notes and final version.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">29</container>
					<unitdate>1998</unitdate>
					<unittitle>CUNY Conference - "Which Way for Women and Development? Debating Concepts, Strategies and Directions for the 21st Century," NYC, October 15-17, 1998</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Correspondence related to participation in the conference "Which Way for Women and Development? Debating Concepts, Strategies and Directions for the 21st Century."<lb/>
					Conference Program.<lb/>
					Documents: Conference Proposal and Proposed Panels.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">30</container>
					<unitdate>1998-2001</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Book "Gender and Development: Theoretical, Empirical and Practical Approaches"</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Correspondence with Edward Elgar Publishing relating to "Gender and Development: Theoretical, Empirical and Practical Approaches."<lb/>
					Proposed Chapters and Contributors.<lb/>
					Editor's Promotion Form.<lb/>
					Publishing Contracts.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01><c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">31</container>
					<unitdate>1999</unitdate>
					<unittitle>World Bank, ABCDE Conference, Paris, France, 1999</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Correspondence and documents related to participation in the "Annual Bank Conference on Development Economics (ABCDE)."<lb/>
					Registration form, draft conference program and draft agenda.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01><c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">32</container>
					<unitdate>1999</unitdate>
					<unittitle>PROMEC Conference "Capitalismo Hoy: Exploraciones Criticas en America Latina y el Mundo," Cochabamba, Bolivia, 1999</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Correspondence and documents related to participation in the PROMEC (Proyesto de Mejoramiento de Formacion en Economia) conference "Capitalismo Hoy: Exploraciones Criticas en America Latina y el Mundo" (in Spanish).<lb/>
					Conference Program and handwritten notes (in Spanish).</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01><c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">33</container>
					<unitdate>2000</unitdate>
					<unittitle>University of Illinois - "WID Symposium 2000: Women, Gender, and Development - Risks and Rights in the 21st Century," Illinois, 2000</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Correspondence and documents related to participation in the University of Illinois Conference "WID Symposium 2000: Women, Gender, and Development - Risks and Rights in the 21st Century."<lb/>
					Conference program.<lb/>
					Lecture flyer for "Changing Employment Structures and Economic Insecurity."</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01><c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">34</container>
					<unitdate>1999-2000</unitdate>
					<unittitle>ILO Meeting of the International Advisory Board of the Socio-Economic Programme, Bellagio, Italy</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Correspondence related to participation in International Labour Organisation's International Advisory Board of the Socio-Economic Programme. <lb/>
					Meeting agenda and outline of program.<lb/>
					Overhead projector slides "Unemployment Rate" and "Educational Opportunity" and "Income Before and After - Smith Corona Workers."<lb/>
					Handwritten lecture notes.<lb/>
					Preliminary draft copy of paper "Gender Dimensions of Socio-Economic In/Security," written for the meeting of the ILO's International Advisory Board of the Socio-Economic Programme.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01><c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">35</container>
					<unitdate>2000-2002</unitdate>
					<unittitle>UN - Committee for Development Policy</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Correspondence related to appointment to and member of the UN Economic and Social Council's Committee for Development Policy.<lb/>
					Meeting documents.<lb/>
					Biographical information on the nominees for appointment to the Committee for Development Policy.<lb/>
					Document "Issues Note - Round Table- New York- 14 February 2002- ECOSOC High-Level Segment 2002 - The Contribution of Human Resources Development: Including the areas of health and education, to the process of development."<lb/>
					Publications from the UN Economic and Social Council Commission on the Status of Women: Discrimination against women and girls in Afghanistan and Implications of the reforms of mechanisms in the human rights area for communications concerning the status of women.<lb/>
					Annotated Agenda and Programme of Work: Financing Global Social Development Symposium, New York, 7 February, 2002.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01><c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">36</container>
					<unitdate>2001</unitdate>
					<unittitle>ILO Meeting of the Infocus Programme on Socio-Economic Security - International Advisory Board, Bellagio, Italy, 2001.</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Correspondence and documents regarding participation in the ILO Meeting of the Infocus Programme on Socio-Economic Security - International Advisory Board, Bellagio, Italy, 2001.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01><c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">37</container>
					<unitdate>2002</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Cornell University Conference "Rethinking Labor Market Formalization," Ithaca, New York, October 2002</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Correspondence and documents related to organizing the Cornell University Conference "Rethinking Labor Market Formalization; Poverty, Precarious Jobs and Social Protection," Ithaca, New York, October 2002.<lb/>
					Conference Program.<lb/>
					Table of Contents and Contributors for Related Publication.<lb/>
					ILO Document "Decent Work and the Informal Economy" by Lin Lean Lim.<lb/>
					Paper "Rethinking Labour Market Informalization: Precarious Jobs, Poverty and Social Protection" by John Langmore.<lb/>
					One page document regarding the potential closure of the college and redistribution of the departments within Cornell University's College of Architecture, Art and Planning.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01><c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">38</container>
					<unitdate>2002</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Institut für Stadt- und Regionalforschung (ISR) Conference "Globalization and Urban Studies: How to study the metropolis in transition?" Vienna, Conference, October 2002</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Correspondence related to participation in the Institut für Stadt- und Regionalforschung (ISR) Conference "Globalization and Urban Studies: How to study the metropolis in transition?" Vienna, Conference, October 2002<lb/>
					Workshop Agenda.<lb/>
					Abstract "Labor Market Informalization and the Changing Landscapes of Cities" by Lourdes Benería and Susanna Schaller.<lb/>
					Conference document containing abstracts from all of the participants.<lb/>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">39</container>
					<unitdate>2002</unitdate>
					<unittitle>DAW Working Group Session at "Day of Dialogue on Gender and Financing for Development", New York, February 25, 2002</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Correspondence and documents related to participation in the DAW Working Group Session at "Day of Dialogue on Gender and Financing for Development", New York, February 25, 2002<lb/>
					Publication of the UN Economic and Social Council "Thematic issues before the Commission on the Status of Women," 3 January 2002.<lb/>
					"Aide Memoire" for the Day of Dialogue.<lb/>
					Document "What kind of development should be financed?" by Cecilia Lopez Montaño, Alma Espino, and Rosalba Todaro, 2001. Excerpt: "This document was written as a reaction to the absence of gender perspective in the Financing for Development Conference debates and preparatory documents."<lb/>
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">40</container>
					<unitdate>2002</unitdate>
					<unittitle>UNIFEM Conference "Gender and Trade in the Context of Financing for Development," Monterrey, Mexico, 2002</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Correspondence related to participation in the UNIFEM-UNDP-UNCTAD Conference "Gender and Trade in the Context of Financing for Development," at the International Conference on Financing for Development, Monterrey, Mexico, 2002.<lb/>
					Excerpt from correspondence sent to Lourdes Benería related to the International Conference on Financing for Development:<lb/>
						"'...the UN will be eaten for breakfast by the Bretton Woods institutions... this is, in reality, the transnational corporate agenda in drag.'"<lb/>
					Handwritten notes.<lb/>
					Proposal for the UNIFEM-UNDP-UNCTAD Conference "Gender and Trade in the Context of Financing for Development" at the International Conference on Financing for Development.<lb/>
					Conference schedule (in Spanish and in English) for the International Conference on Financing for Development.<lb/>
					Document "Remarks by Hon. Trevor Manuel at the Conference."<lb/>
					Document "Linking Doha, Monterrey and Johannesburg: A global deal to eradicate poverty and inequality and promote sustainable development."<lb/>
					Document "Statement of Concern" - Issued by Development Alternatives with Women for a New Era (DAWN), International Gender and Trade Network (IGTN), Cartagena Feminist Initiative, Red de Educacion Popular Entre Mujeres (REPEM), and endorsed by the Women's Caucus. The "Statement of Concern" documents the isolation and disregard for the perspective of civil society organizations during the International Conference on Financing for Development. Excerpt: "Time has almost run out for this conference to make a real differenc in realizing the MDGs [Millenium Develompent Goals] within a Human Rights Framework."</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">41</container>
					<unitdate>2004</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Universal Forum of Cultures Conference "Vivir y Convivir: Forum Mundial de las Mujeres," Barcelona, Spain, July, 2004</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Correspondence (in Catalan and Spanish) related to participation in the Universal Forum of Cultures Conference "Vivir y Convivir: Forum Mundial de las Mujeres," Barcelona, Spain, July, 2004.<lb/>
					Conference Schedule.<lb/>
					Document "El Treball No Remunerat: Historia d'un Projecte de Contabilitzacio" (in Catalan) with handwritten edits (in Catalan).<lb/>
					Figures and Tables regarding the relationship between the formal and informal economy and women's work.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">42</container>
					<unitdate>2005</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Report for Institute de la Mujer (INAM): "Diagnostico de Genero de Honduras: Aspectos Economicos"</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Paper "Diagnostico de Genero de Honduras: Aspectos Economicos," (in Spanish) Institute de la Mujer, Honduras, July 2005.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<unitid label="Video ">VHS Tape</unitid>
					<unitdate></unitdate>
					<unittitle>WS360 "Street Stories: Bosnia"</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>VHS Video of a broadcast of the CBS News magazine "Street Stories" with Peter Van Sant. This episode is recorded in Bosnia. He interviews war victims and a war criminal.<lb/>
						"Used in a course."- written on an attached note.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="series">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1, 2</container>
					<unittitle>1990 Elections Nicaragua</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>"Member of delegation (organized by Hemisphere Initiatives) to observe the 1990 Nicaraguan elections in which the Sandinistas lost." -A note from Lourdes Benería.</p>
				</scopecontent>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						
						<unitdate>1982</unitdate>
						<unittitle>"Food Systems Monograph: A Preliminary Analysis of the Nicaraguan Food System - A progress report of research being carried out under UNRISD's project 'Food Systems and Society,'"</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Book by Solon Barraclough.<lb/>
						</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1987</unitdate>
						<unittitle>"Yo fui un Contra: Historia de un 'Paladín de la Libertad'"</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Book (in Spanish) by Elizabeth Reimann.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1982</unitdate>
						<unittitle>"What Difference Could a Revolution Make?- Food and Farming in the New Nicaragua"</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Book by Joseph Collins.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1981</unitdate>
						<unittitle>"Sobre La Insurreccion"</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Book (in Spanish) by Humberto Ortega Saavedra.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1987</unitdate>
						<unittitle>"Mujer y Agroexportación en Nicaragua"</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Book (in Spanish) edited by Instituto Nicaraguense de la Mujer.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1980</unitdate>
						<unittitle>"Carlos, El Amanecer ya no es una Tentacion"</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Book (in Spanish) by Tomás Borge, Serie Testimonio -  Coleccion Nuestros Paises - Casa de las Americas.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1989</unitdate>
						<unittitle>"Construccion de la Democracia en Nicaragua"</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Book (in Spanish) by the Escuela de Sociología Universidad Cenrtroamericana.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1986</unitdate>
						<unittitle>"La Economia Mixta en Nicaragua: Proyecto o Realidad - Una Vision de Academicos y Politicos Nacionales"</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Book (in Spanish) by the Centro de Investigacion y Asesoria Socio-Economica y Fundacion Friedrich Ebert Stiftung.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1987</unitdate>
						<unittitle>"El FSLN y la Mujer en la Revolución Popular Sandinista"</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publication (in Spanish) by Dirrección Nacional Frent Sandinista de Liberación Nacional and published by Editorial Vanguardia.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1987</unitdate>
						<unittitle>"Revista Nicaraguense de Ciencias Sociales"</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publication (in Spanish) de la Asociacion Nicaraguense de Clientificos Sociales, Ano 2 - No. 2.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1987</unitdate>
						<unittitle>"Cuadernos de Investigacion 1"</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publication (in Spanish) - Includes articles on "El concepto de productividad," "Crisis alimentaria y participacion popular," "Las vendedoras de los mercados."</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1986</unitdate>
						<unittitle>"Informes: 10 Anos de Investigaciones Sobre la Mujer en Nicaragua 1976-1986"</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publication (in Spanish) by the Oficina de la Mujer, Ministerio de la Presidencia, 1986.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1987</unitdate>
						<unittitle>"Informe: Inventario de Proyectos para la Mujer en Nicaragua"</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publication (in Spanish) by the Oficina de la Mujer, Ministerio de la Presidencia, 1987.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1987</unitdate>
						<unittitle>"Realidad y Perspectiva: Bibliografia nacional anotada sobre la Mujer en Nicaragua"</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publication (in Spanish) by the Oficina de la Mujer, Ministerio de la Presidencia, 1987.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
			<c02 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">43</container>
					<unitdate>1990</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Nicaragua: Newspaper Articles by and about Lourdes Benería </unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Clippings and photocopies of newspaper articles about the Nicaraguan Elections by or about Lourdes Benería. In Spanish and in English.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c02><c02 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">44</container>
					<unitdate>1988-1990</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Nicaragua: Women</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Journal, book and newspaper articles about Nicaraguan women.<lb/>
					"Women in Nicaragua" by Beth Stevens, 1988.<lb/>
					"La rebeldia de las mujeres nicaragüenses: semillero de una nueva democracia" (in Spanish) by Ana Criquillion, 1989.<lb/>
					"Mujer y Derechos Politicos" (in Spanish) by Milu Vargas Escobar, 1989.<lb/>
					"Mujer y Partidos Políticos" (in Spanish) by Patricia Vargas Fernandez, Milu Vargas Escobar, and Josefina Ramos Mendoza.<lb/>
					"The Situation of Women in Nicaragua" by Malena de Montis and Mercedes Olivera for El Centro De Investigacion y Accion Participative (CIAP), 1989.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c02><c02 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">45</container>
					<unitdate>1989</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Nicaragua: UNO and FSLN Platforms</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Newsprint pamphlets.
					"Programa de Govierno de la Unión Nacional Opositora UNO" (Union Nacional Opositora) (in Spanish).<lb/>
					"Frente Sandinista de Liberacion Nacional (FSLN) Plataforma Electoral (1990-1997) !Todo Sera Mejor!" (in Spanish).</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c02><c02 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">46</container>
					<unitdate>1989-1990</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Nicaragua: Newspaper Clippings</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Newspaper clippings (in Spanish and English) from NYTimes, la Semana Comica ("Semanario de Humor Marxismo Sexo y Violencia"), the Guardian ("Independant Radical Newsweekly").</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c02><c02 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">47</container>
					<unitdate>1990</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Nicaragua: Economia - Newspaper Clippings</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Newspaper clippings (in Spanish and English) NYTimes, La Cronica ("Por una socieddad mas justa, mas amplia, mas generosa"), La Prensa, and Barracida.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c02><c02 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">48</container>
					<unitdate>1989-1990</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Nicaragua: Travel Documents, Notes, Papers</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Copy of paper "Nicaragua: Elecciones/90" (in Spanish) by Lourdes Benería (1990) and publication request letter (in Spanish) dated February 19, 1990 to Sr. Angel Harguindey, Seccion de Colaboraciones, El Pais, Madrid, Spain.<lb/>
					Handwritten notes for lecture given at the CUSLAR Sister City Event, 1st Unitarian Church, February 22, 1990.<lb/>
					Bright orange, wire-bound, college ruled notebook containing hand written notes, names and addresses (in Spanish).<lb/>
					Correspondence related to the Hemisphere Initiatives.<lb/>
					Travel agenda, plane tickets, financial documentation, map of Nicaragua, newspaper clippings (in Spanish).
					Document "Latin American Studies Association Delegation to Observe the February 25, 1990 Nicaraguan Election, Interim Report, December 4, 1989."</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c02>
			<c02 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">49</container>
					<unitdate>1989</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Nicaragua: Economics - Papers and Publications</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Background Paper on Nicaraguan Economy and Politics from Hemisphere Initiatives.<lb/>
					Journal: "Análisis - Revista Económica de Nicaragua -  Computación - ?Hacia Dónde va Nicaragua?" No. 4 Diciembre 1989, Managua, Nicaragua.<lb/>
					Journal: "Análisis - Revista Económica de Nicaragua - ?Inflación bajo control?" No. 1 Agosto 1989, Managua, Nicaragua.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c02>
			<c02 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">50</container>
					<unitdate>1989-1990</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Nicaragua: Hemisphere Initiatives Documents</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Document "Establishing the Ground Rules: A Report on the Nicaraguan Electoral Process: August, 1989" by Hemisphere Initiatives, Boston, Massachusetts.<lb/>
					Hemisphere Initiatives Pamphlets, Correspondence regarding participation in the monitoring process.<lb/>
					Article "The Nicaraguan Elections: Observations Based Upon the January HI Delegation" by David Samuel Krusé, 1990.<lb/>
					Article/Letter from Dennis Gilbert about his impressions, 1990.<lb/>
					Article "Why the Sandinistas are Winning the Election" by David Samuel Krusé.<lb/>
					Article "Panama Invasion Gives Sandinistas Decisive Lead in Elections" by Elizabeth Dore, 1990.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c02>
			<c02 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">51</container>
					<unitdate>1989</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Nicaragua: Election Publications and Rules</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Booklet "Electoral Law and Reforms" by the Supreme Electoral Council.<lb/>
					Electoral Supreme Council Bulletin Number 1 Managua, Nicaragua, July-August-1989.<lb/>
					Electoral Supreme Council Bulletin Number 2 Managua, Nicaragua, July-1989.<lb/>
					"Rules for processing foreign donations to political parties, alliances of parties or petitioning associations." (in Spanish and English) Consejo Supremo Electoral Boletín Informativo Managua, Nicaragua, Noviembre de 1989.<lb/>
					"Procedures for the filing of complaints or accusations:"(in Spanish and English) Consejo Supremo Electoral Boletín Informativo Managua, Nicaragua, Noviembre de 1989.<lb/>
					"Rules of Electoral Ethics" Supreme Electoral Council Bulletin Managua, Nicaragua, October 1989.<lb/>
					"Regulation on International Observation of the Electoral Process" Supreme Electoral Council Bulletin Managua, Nicaragua, October 1989.<lb/>
					Newsprint Booklet "Manual de Educación Cívica y Capacitación Electoral No. 2 Votacion y Escrutinio" (in Spanish) Consejo Supremo Electoral.<lb/>
					Pamphlet "Minstructivo Sobre las Funciones de los Fiscales" Consejo Supremo Electoral.<lb/>
					Newprint booklet "Plataforma Electoral del FSLN (1990-1997) !Todo Será Mejor! - el 25 en la 5" (in Spanish).
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c02>
			<c02 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">52</container>
					<unitdate>1979-1990</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Nicaragua: Newsletters, Papers, Reports, Articles</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Article "The CIA's Blueprint for Nicaragua" by Philip Agee in CoverntAction, Number 6 (October 1979).<lb/>
					Newletter #12 from Mardy Townsend of "Clergy and Laity Concerned," Nicaragua, November 12, 1990.<lb/>
					News Release "Hotline - Witness for Peace," October 20, 1989.<lb/>	
					News Release "Hotline - Witness for Peace," November 16, 1989.<lb/>
					News Release "Hotline - Witness for Peace," January 11, 1990.<lb/>
					Book Excerpt "Chapter 4: Nicaragua" from Confronting Revolution: Security Through Diplomacy in Central America.<lb/>
					Document of Alejandro Bendana, Secretary General Nicaragua Foreign Ministry, Talk before a meeting of Nicaragua solidarity activists, 25 March, 1990.<lb/>
					Article "Clase, Estado y Etnicidad en las Costa Atlantica de Nicaragua" by Carlos M. Vilas, 1989 for a Panel on Democacy and Popular Participation in Nicaragua.<lb/>
					Article "Plan Basico de Gobierno - Partido Social Cristiano Nicaraguense (PSC) - La Alternativa Cristiana" by Erick Ramirez Penavente, Managua, Nicaragua.<lb/>
					"Report of an Economic Mission to the Government of Nicaragua" (marked "Confidential - Not for quotation") by D. Kruse, 5 April, 1989.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c02>
			
		
			</c01>
		</dsc>
	</archdesc>
</ead>
