<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<!-- Transformed with v1v2002_4_cornell.xsl -->

<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../dtds/ead.dtd">
	 
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../styles/style.xsl" ?>
<ead>
   <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1" scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
      <eadid mainagencycode="nic" countrycode="us" publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections//TEXT(US::NIC::RMM06803::Henry F. Dobyns papers)//EN">RMM06803.xml</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Henry F. Dobyns papers, 1960s.</titleproper>
            <titleproper type="sort">Dobyns, Henry F.</titleproper>
            <author>Compiled by Sarah Keen</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library</publisher>
            <date>May 2008</date>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note audience="internal">
               <p> 
				
                  <subject>socsc</subject>
			 
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>Finding aid encoded by Sarah Keen, <date>May 2008</date>
         </creation>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change encodinganalog="583">
            <date normal="2007-05-29">2007-05-29</date>
            <item>converted from EAD 1.0 to EAD 2002 </item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <frontmatter>
      <titlepage>
         <titleproper>Guide to the Henry F. Dobyns Papers,<lb/>1960s.</titleproper>
         <num>Collection Number: 6803</num>
         <publisher>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections <lb/>Cornell University Library</publisher>
         <list type="deflist">
            <defitem>
               <label>Contact Information:</label>
               <item>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections<lb/>
2B Carl A. Kroch Library<lb/>
Cornell University<lb/>
Ithaca, NY 14853<lb/>
(607) 255-3530<lb/>
Fax: (607) 255-9524<lb/>
<extref href="mailto:rareref@cornell.edu">rareref@cornell.edu</extref>
                  <lb/>
<extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu">http://rmc.library.cornell.edu</extref>
                  <lb/></item>
            </defitem>
            <defitem>
               <label>Compiled by:</label>
               <item>Sarah Keen</item>
            </defitem>
            <defitem>
               <label>Date completed:</label>
               <item>May 2008</item>
            </defitem>
            <defitem>
               <label>EAD encoding:</label>
               <item>Sarah Keen, May 2008</item>
            </defitem>
         </list>
         <date>© 2008 Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library</date>
      </titlepage>
   </frontmatter>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <head id="a1">DESCRIPTIVE SUMMARY</head>
         <unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="MARC 245">Henry F. Dobyns papers, 
		<unitdate type="inclusive" encodinganalog="MARC 245">1960s.</unitdate>
		
         </unittitle>
         <unitid label="Collection Number:">6803</unitid>
         <origination label="Creator:"> 
		  
            <persname encodinganalog="100" normal="Dobyns, Henry F. ">Henry F. Dobyns </persname>
		
         </origination>
         <physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="MARC 300">6 card file boxes.</physdesc>
         <repository label="Repository:">Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library</repository>
         <langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="041" langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
         <head id="a2" altrender="biography">BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE </head>
         <p>Dr. Henry Dobyns joined the Cornell Peru Project as its Research Coordinator in 1960, after receiving his Ph.D. from Cornell. In 1962, he returned to campus to participate in training Peace Corps volunteers to work in Peru. The Peace Corps also contracted with Cornell to have the CPP advise Peace Corps officials in Lima and to evaluate their impact on the communities. He was the Coordinator of the Comparative Studies of Cultural Change program and the Associate Director of the Cornell Peru Project from 1963-1966. In 1966 he became the Director of the project following the death of Allan R. Holmberg, the previous director.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520">
         <head id="a3">COLLECTION DESCRIPTION</head>
         <p>Copies of field notes compiled in Human Relations Area Files categories; typed newspaper articles about haciendas; cards comprising a Vicos census carried out in 1957-1959 by Dr. Mario C. Vázquez. Typing of notes was carried out by young women students in the Peruvian National School of Social Work, who began working for the CPP in 1960, recruited by Dr. Cara E. Richards (who was in charge of a fertility study directed by Dr. J. Mayone Stycos).</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <head id="a7">SUBJECTS</head>
         <controlaccess>
            <head>Names: </head>
            <persname encodinganalog="MARC 100">Dobyns, Henry F.</persname>
            <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Cornell Peru Project.</corpname>
            <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Human Relations Area Files, inc.</corpname>
         </controlaccess>
         <controlaccess>
            <head>Subjects:</head>
            <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Anthropological research.</subject>
            <subject encodinganalog="MARC 651">Vicos (Peru).</subject>
         </controlaccess>
         <controlaccess>
            <head>Form and Genre Terms:</head>
            <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="MARC 655">Field notes.</genreform>
         </controlaccess>
      </controlaccess>
      <descgrp type="admininfo">
         <head id="a8">INFORMATION FOR USERS</head>
         <prefercite>
            <head>Cite As:</head>
            <p>Henry F. Dobyns papers, #6803. Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library.</p>
         </prefercite>
      </descgrp>
      <relatedmaterial>
         <head id="a5">RELATED MATERIALS</head>
         <p>Allan R. Holmberg collection on Peru, circa 1946-1966. #14-25-1529.</p>
         <p>Paul L. Doughty collection of Vicos photographs, 1960-1969. #6734.</p>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <dsc type="combined">
         <head>CONTAINER LIST</head>
         <c01 level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Field notes, Cornell Peru Project</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">1</container>
                  <unittitle>Henry Dobyns' Lima file</unittitle>
                  <abstract>159 Personal History R-Z; 161 Population - 165 Mortality A-G</abstract>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">2</container>
                  <unittitle>Henry Dobyns' Lima file</unittitle>
                  <abstract>165 Mortality G-Y - 23</abstract>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">3</container>
                  <unittitle>Henry Dobyns' Lima file</unittitle>
                  <abstract>231 domesticated animals, 232 Applied animal science, 233 Animal husbandry, 235 Poultry raising, 236 wool production, 237 Animal byproducts<lb/> 24, 241 Tillage, 242 Agricultural science, 243 cereal agriculture, 244 vegetable production, 245 Arboriculture, 246 Forage crops, 247 Floriculture<lb/> 25, 256 Cereal industry, 257 Confection industries<lb/> 26. 262 Diet, 263 Condiments, 264 Eating, 265 Food service industries<lb/> 27, 271 Water, thirst, 272 beverages, non-alcoholic, 273 alcoholic beverages, 275 Drinking establishments <lb/> 452 Credit, 453 Banking, 454 Saving and investment, 455 Speculation, 456 Insurance, 458 Business cycles<lb/> 46 Labor. 462 Division of labor by sex., 463 Occupational specialization, 464 Labor supply and employment, 465 Wages and salaries, 466 Labor relations, 467 Labor organization, 468 Collective bargaining<lb/> 47 Business and Industrial organization, 471 Ownership and Control of capital, 473 Corporate organization, 474
				Cooperative organization, 475 state enterprise, 476 Mutual aid,477 Competition<lb/> 48 Travel and Transportation<lb/> 54 Entertainment</abstract>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">4</container>
                  <unittitle>Henry Dobyns' Lima file</unittitle>
                  <abstract>57 Interpersonal relations; 58 Marriage; 59 Family<lb/> 62 Community, 621 Community structure, 622 Headmen, 623 Councils, 624 Local officials, 625 Police, 626 Social control, 627 Informal In-group justice<lb/> 63 Territorial organization, 631 Territorial hierarchy, 632 Towns, 633 Cities, 634 Districts<lb/> 641 Citizenship, 642 Constitution, 643 Chief executive, 645 Cabinet, 646 Parliament</abstract>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">5</container>
                  <unittitle>Henry Dobyns' Lima file</unittitle>
                  <abstract>647 Administrative agencies, 648 International relations<lb/> 651 Taxation, 652 Public finance, 653 Public works, 654 Research and development, 655 Government enterprises, 656 Government regulations, 657 Public Welfare, 658 Public Education, 659 Miscellaneous Government Activities<lb/> 66 Political Behavior, 661 Exploitation, 662 Political intrigue, 663 Public service, 664 Pressure politics, 665 Political parties, 666 Elections, 667 Political machines, 669 Revolution<lb/> 671 Legal norms, 672 Liability, 673 Wrongs, 675 Contracts, 676 Agency, 679<lb/> 681 Sanctions, 682 Offenses against life, 683 Offenses against the person, 684 Sex and marital offenses, 685 Property offenses, 686 Nonfulfillment of obligations, 689 Social offenses<lb/> 691 Litigation, 692 judicial authority, 693 Legal and judicial personnel, 694 Initiation of judicial proceedings, 695 Trial procedure, 696 Execution of justice, 697 Prisons and jails<lb/> 70 Armed forces, 702 Recruitment and
				training<lb/> 726 Warfare, 727 Aftermath of combat<lb/> 731 Disasters, 732 Defectives, 733 Alcoholism and drug addiction, 734 Invalidism, 735 Poverty, 736 Dependency<lb/> 741 Philanthropic foundations, 742 Medical research, 743 Hospitals and clinics, 744 Public health and sanitation, 746 Public assistance, 747 Private welfare agencies, 748 Social work<lb/> 75, 751 Preventive medicine, 752 Bodily injuries, 753 Theory of disease, 754 Sorcery, 755 Magical and Mental therapy, 757 Medical therapy, 758 Medical care, 759 Medical personnel<lb/> 76 Death, 761 Life and death, 763 dylng, 764 Funeral, 766 Deviant Mortuary Practices, 768 Social readjustments to death, 769 Cult of the dead<lb/> 77 Religious beliefs, 771 General character of religion, 772 Cosmology, 773 Mythology, 774 Animism, 775 Eschatology, 776 Spirits and gods, 777 Luck and chance, 778 Sacred objects and place<lb/> 781 Religious experience </abstract>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">6</container>
                  <unittitle>Henry Dobyns' Lima file</unittitle>
                  <abstract>782 Propitiation, 783 Purification and expiation, 786 Orgies, 787 Revelation and divination, 788 Ritual.<lb/> 790 Ecclesiastical Organization, 791 Magicians and diviners, 792 Holy men, 793 Priesthood, 794 Congregations, 796 Organized ceremonial, 797 Missions.<lb/> 802 Numeration, 804 Weights and measures, 805 Ordering of time<lb/> 821 Ethnometeorology, 824 Ethnobotany, 826 Ethnoanatomy, 827 Ethnophysiology, 828 Ethnopsychology, 829 Ethnosociology<lb/> 836 Premarital sex relations, 837 Extramarital sex relations<lb/> 844 Childbifth, 847 Abortion and infanticide, 848 Illegitimacy.<lb/> 851 Social placement, 852 Ceremonial during infancy and childhood, 853 Infant feeding, 854 Infant care, 855 Child care, 856 Development and maturation, 857 Childhood activities, 858 Status of children<lb/> 861 Techniques of inculcation, 863 Cleanliness training, 864 Sex training, 866 Aggression training, 868 Transmission of skills<lb/> 871 Educational system, 872 Elementary
				education, 873 Liberal arts education, 874 Vocational education, 875 x 2 Teachers, 876 Educational theory and methods<lb/> 882 Status of adolescents, 883 Adolescent activities, 885 Adulthood, 886 Senescence, 888 Activities for the aged.</abstract>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>