<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
			
<ead>
	<eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1"
		scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
		<eadid mainagencycode="nic" countrycode="us"
			publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections//TEXT(US::NIC::RMM08493::Guide to the Randi Ward collection)//EN"
			>RMM08493.xml</eadid>
		<filedesc>
			<titlestmt>
				<titleproper>Guide to the Randi Ward collection,
					<date>2012-2014.</date></titleproper>
				<titleproper type="sort">Ward, Randi collection</titleproper>
				<author>Compiled by RMC Staff</author>
			</titlestmt>
			<publicationstmt>
				<publisher>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University
					Library</publisher>
				<date>February 2015</date>
			</publicationstmt>
			<notestmt>
				<note audience="internal">
					<p><subject>euro</subject>
						<subject>liter</subject></p>
				</note>
			</notestmt>
		</filedesc>
		<profiledesc>
			<creation>Finding aid encoded by RMC Staff, <date>February 2015</date></creation>
		</profiledesc>
	</eadheader>
	<frontmatter>
		<titlepage>
			<titleproper>Guide to the Randi Ward Collection,<lb/><date type="inclusive"
					encodinganalog="245$f">2012-Present</date></titleproper>
			<num>Collection Number: 8493</num>
			<publisher>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections <lb/>Cornell University
				Library</publisher>
			<list type="deflist">
				<defitem>
					<label>Contact Information:</label>
					<item> Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections<lb/> 2B Carl A. Kroch
						Library<lb/> Cornell University<lb/> Ithaca, NY 14853<lb/> (607)
						255-3530<lb/> Fax: (607) 255-9524<lb/><extref
							href="mailto:rareref@cornell.edu"
							>rareref@cornell.edu</extref><lb/><extref
							href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu"
							>http://rmc.library.cornell.edu</extref><lb/></item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>Compiled by:</label>
					<item>RMC Staff</item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>Date completed:</label>
					<item>February 2015</item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>EAD encoding:</label>
					<item>RMC Staff, February 2015</item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>Date modified:</label>
					<item>RMC Staff, June 2015</item>
				</defitem>
			</list>
			<date>© 2015 Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University
				Library</date>
		</titlepage>
	</frontmatter>
	<archdesc level="collection">
		<did>
			<head id="a1">DESCRIPTIVE SUMMARY</head>
			<unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="MARC 245">Randi Ward collection, <unitdate
					encodinganalog="MARC 245" type="inclusive">2012-Present</unitdate>
			</unittitle>
			<unitid label="Collection Number:">8493</unitid>
			<origination label="Creator:"><persname encodinganalog="100" normal="Ward, Randi   "
					>Ward, Randi </persname></origination>
			<physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="MARC 300">.2 cubic feet</physdesc>
			<physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Publications</physdesc>
			<repository label="Repository:">Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell
				University Library</repository>
			<abstract label="Abstract:">Publications featuring translations from Faroese and
				Icelandic by Randi Ward.</abstract>
			<langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="041"
					langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial>
		</did>
		<bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
			<head id="a2" altrender="biography">BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE </head>
			<p>Randi Ward is a writer, translator and photographer from West Virginia.</p>
		</bioghist>
		<scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520">
			<head id="a3">COLLECTION DESCRIPTION</head>
			<p>Publications featuring translations from Faroese and Icelandic and photography by
				Randi Ward. Also several CDs.</p>
		</scopecontent>
		<controlaccess>
			<head id="a7">SUBJECTS</head>
			<controlaccess>
				<head>Names: </head>
				<persname encodinganalog="MARC 100">Ward, Randi </persname>
			</controlaccess>
			<controlaccess>
				<head>Subjects:</head>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Faroese language</subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Faroese poetry</subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Icelandic poetry</subject>
			</controlaccess>
		</controlaccess>
		<descgrp>
			<head id="a8">INFORMATION FOR USERS</head>
			<prefercite>
				<head>Cite As:</head>
				<p>Randi Ward collection, #8493. Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections,
					Cornell University Library.</p>
			</prefercite>
		</descgrp>
		<dsc type="combined">
			<head>CONTAINER LIST</head>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<unitdate>Fall 2012</unitdate>
					<unittitle><title>Beloit Poetry Journal</title> Vol. 63 No.1 </unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Contains K. A. Hays, Liz Kay, Hannah K. galvin, Matthew Nienow, Jaydn DeWald,
						Richard Foerster, Ephraim Scott Sommers, Michael Bazzett, Randi Ward,
						Caitlin Dwyer, Lucy Anderton, Brendan Constantine, Greg Wrenn, Hadara
						Bar-Nadav, Roger Mitchell, Jeremy Bass, Stephen O’Connor, Allison
						Hutchcraft, Joel Peckham, Jeremy Glazier, Philip Metres </p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>

			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<unitdate>Fall 2012</unitdate>
					<unittitle><title>Cold Mountain Review</title> Vol. 41 No. 1 </unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Contains Erin Pushman, Sonya Lea, Ian Burkett, Rebecca Lauren, Hank Hudepohl,
						Chris Souza, William Palmer, Laura Paul Watson, Lisa Hammond, Heather
						Holliger, Catherine Tahmin, Bernadette Geyer, Alyse Bensel, Karen J. Weyant,
						Bill Brown, Elias Simpson, Sabrina Ito, Mike McGeehon, Z.G. Tomaszewski,
						Shivani Mehta, Terry Ann Thaxton, Elizabeth Hoover, Marsha Truman Cooper,
						Charlie Bondhus, Elizabeth Genovise, Julian Huffman, Randi Ward </p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<unitdate>Spring 2013</unitdate>
					<unittitle><title>The Bitter Oleander:</title> A Magazine of Contemporary
						International Poetry and Short Fiction Vol. 19 No. 1</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<unitdate>Fall 2013</unitdate>
					<unittitle><title>Cimarron Review</title> 185</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Contains William Olsen, Beth Marzoni, Vanessa Stauffer, Rebecca Lehmann,
						Holly Day, Lisa Furmanski, Francesc Parcerisas, Christine Steward-Nuñez,
						Sara E. Lamers, John McCullough, Daniel Saalfeld, Malcolm Guite, Hilary
						Vaughn Dobel, CJ Evans, Alyson Hagy, Andrew Ellis Bates, Kate Woodworth,
						Richard M. Lange </p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<unitdate>Fall/Winter 2013</unitdate>
					<unittitle><title>Fjords:</title> Arts and Literary Review Vol. 2 Issue 2
					</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Contains John McKernan, Ashley-Elizabeth Best, Christian Anton Gerard, George
						Moore, Yumi Sakugawa, Jacob M. Appel, Dan O’Brien, Sean Carswell, Robert
						Mengert, Paul David Adkins, Guðrið Helmsdal, Randi Ward, Tóriddyr Poulsen,
						Randi Ward, Seth Clabough, Robin Richardson, Christina Francine, Kayti
						Doolittle </p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<unitdate>2014</unitdate>
					<unittitle><title>Arcadia</title> 8 </unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Contains Joe Scott, Ilya Lyashevsky, Paul Catalano, Laura Birdsall, Harold
						Whit Williams, Carol Hamilton, John Palen, Laura E. Miller, Abbie J.
						Leavens, Peggy Aylsworth, Hannah Fischer, Edgar Kunz, Danielle Luther
						Luebbe, Joelle Schumacher </p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<unitdate>2014</unitdate>
					<unittitle><title>Skidrow Penthouse</title> #16</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<unitdate>Spring 2014</unitdate>
					<unittitle><title>Scandinavian Review</title> Celebrating 100 Years of the
						Scandinavian Review </unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p> </p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<unitdate>Summer 2014</unitdate>
					<unittitle><title>Beloit Poetry Journal</title> Vol. 64 No.4 </unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Contains Peter Leight, Liz Robbins, Daniel Bourne, Karl Plank, Claire
						Åkebrand, Tóroddur Poulsen, Laura McCullough, Jeff Ewing, Lauren Camp, Matt
						Salyer, Chera Hammons, Craig Finlay, Jessica Jacobs, Michael Broek </p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>

			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<unitid>CD-2173</unitid>
					<unitdate>2011</unitdate>
					<unittitle><title>Beyond the Grey</title> by Gudrid Hansdóttir</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<unitid>CD-2174</unitid>
					<unitdate>2012</unitdate>
					<unittitle><title>Dýrð Í dauðaþögn</title> by Ásgeir Trausti</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<unitdate>2011</unitdate>
					<unittitle><title>Stjørnudust</title> úr føroyskum yrkíngum í 200 ár
					</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Four volume anthology. Accompanied by <title>Kestrel </title>(Department of
						Language and Literature, Fairmont State University) postcard from Randi Ward
						featuring poem "Shade" from <title>Kestrel</title> issue 32. Anthology
						contains poem "Grannsíggin" by Ward (Faroese name: Randi á Ryggi) on p.
						124-125 of Volume I. Volume I also contains Símun av Skarði, Jóhanna Maria
						Skylv Hansen, Gudmundur Bruun, Bjørgfinnur Nielsen, Kári P, Katrin Reinert,
						Bergur Rønne Moberg, Jóannes Dalsgaard, Regin Dahl, Jóan Petur uppi í Trøð,
						Mina Reinert, Rasmus Effersøe, Hans Dávur Matras, Andrias Ziska, Oskar
						Hermannsson, Kim Simonsen, Gunnar Hoydal, Janus Djurhuus, Andrea í
						Norðradali, Poul Klein, Hans Andrias Djurhuus, Billa Hansen, Tummas N.
						Djurhuus, Hans J. Glerfoss, Malan Poulsen, Carl Jóhan Jensen, Marna Glerfoss
						á Kamarinum, Anna Mattsson, Jens Hendrik Djurhuus, Mina Reinert, Jacobsen
						Gata, Sigri M. Gaini, Louis Zachariassen, Martin Næs, Nólsoyar-Páll, Hans
						Dávur Matras, Jørgen Hammershaimb, Tóroddur Poulsen, Alexandur Weihe,
						Sólmundur Joensen, Nólsoyar-Páll, Jóhanna Maria Skylv Hansen, Jóannes
						Patursson, Tróndur Olsen, Hjalmar Hammershaimb, M. A. Jacobsen, Rannvá Skeel
						Johannesen, Katrin Reinert, Nancy Vesturbú, Jóanes Nielsen, Hans Dalsgaard,
						Sólrún Michelsen, Rasmus Rasmussen, Oddfíður M. Rasmussen, Jnley á
						Løgmansbø, Ebba Henze, Sólrún Michelsen, Nancy Vesturbú, Martin Næs,
						Sjóvarbóndin, Esmar Jacobsen Gata, Anna Sofía á Rípuni, Bernhard Brim, Hans
						J. Glerfoss, Jákup Berg, Bjørgfinnur Nielsen, Rasmus Effersøe, Arnbjørn
						Ólavsson Dalsgarð, Arnbjørn Danielsen, Símun Mikal Zachariassen, Louis
						Zachariassen, Óðin Ódn, Karsten Hoydal, Dunganon, Dánial Hoydal, Heðin M.
						Klein, S. P. Zachariassen, Axel Tórgarð, M. S. Viðstein, Bernhard Brim,
						Hjalmar Hammershaimb, Kvívíks-Jógvan, Hans Daalsgard, Petur Jensen,
						Fríðrikur Peterson, Ólavur Uti í Stovuni, Heðin M. Klein, Marjun Syderbø
						Kjelnæs, Rikard Long, Tóroddur Poulsen, Jónley á løgmansbø, Vida
						Akselsdóttir Højgaard, Olivar á Ryggi, Agnar Artúvertin, Mikkjal á Ryggi,
						Ólavur Michelsen, Martin Joensen, Rói Patursson, Hanus Kamban, Valdemar á
						Løgmansbø, Kim Simonsen, Sigurð Joensen, Sonja Schneider, Pól F Joensen,
						Oskar Hermannsson, Oddfriður M. Rasmussen, Jóannes Dalsgaard, Tróondur
						Olsen, Jógvan Nolsø, Hanus Debes Joensen, Martin Joensen, Tummas N.
						Djurhuus, Glerfoss á Kamarinum, Arnbjørn Ólavsson Dalsgarð, Hanus Kamban,
						Anna Mattsson, Valdemar á Løgmansbø, Christian Matras, Rói Patursson, Agnar
						Artúvertin, Jóanes Nielsen, Olivar á Ryggi, Gunnar Hoydal, Poul Klein,
						Bergur Rønne Moberg, Símun an Skarði, M. A. Jacobsen, Astrid Joensen, Guðrið
						Helmsdal, Símun Mikal Zachariassen, Fríðrikur Peterson, Jakob Jakoben,
						Alexandur Kristiansen, Hjørdis Djurhuss, Vida Akselsdóttir Hjøgaard, William
						Heinesen, Steinbjørn B. Jacobsen, Jøorgen Hammershaimb, Regin Dahl, Elsa í
						Nýggjustovu, Heðin Brú, Guðrið Helmsdal, Gudmundur Bruun, M. S. Viðstein,
						Jákup Dahl, Maria Eide Petersen, William Heinesen, Andrias Ziska, Nyholm
						Debess, Astrid Poulsen, Rikard Long, and Marjun Syderbø Kjelnæs. </p>
					<p>Volume II contains Stev, Rói Patursson, Regin Dahl, Bernhard Brim, Astrid
						Pálsson, Guðrið Helmsdal, Pól F Joensen, Martin Joensen, Gandaørindi, Hans
						J. Glerfoss, Hans Andrias Djurhuus, Sigri M. Gaini, Kvæðabrot, Tummas N.
						Djurhuus, Hjørdis Djurhuus, Bernhard Brim, Sigri M. Gaini, Rikard Long, Jóan
						Christian Poulsen, Alexandur Kristiansen, Gunnar Hoydal, Carl Jóhan Jensen,
						Christian Matras, Malan Poulsen, Tóroddur Poulsen, Kristin í Geil, Heðin M.
						Klein, Karsten Hoydal, Símun an Skarði, Danisspæl, Martin Joensen, and
						Karsten Hoydal. </p>
					<p>Volume III contains Sigurð Joensen, Heðin M. Klein, Regin Dahl, Elsa í
						Nýggjustovu, Malan Poulsen, Sigurð Joensen, Rói Patursson. Astrid Joensen,
						Esmar Jacobsen Gata, Janus Djurhuus, Símun av Skarði, Guðrið Helmsdal, Jákup
						Hansen, Sigga Due Sørensen, Christian Matras, Jóhanna Maria Skylv Hansen,
						Hanus Debes Joensen, Karsten Hoydal, Hans Andrias Djurhuus, Kristian Osvald
						Viderø, Halgikvæði, Poul F. Joensen, and Astrid Joensen. </p>
					<p>Volume IV contains Mikkjal á Ryggi, Steinbjørn B. Jacobsen, Hans Andrias
						Djurhuus, Oskar Hermannsson, Andrias í Norðradali, Chr. Matras, J, Bernhard
						Brim, Símun av Skarði, and Sigurð Joensen.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<unitid>CD-2175</unitid>
					<unitdate>2015</unitdate>
					<unittitle><title>Bridges</title> by Eivør</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Lyrics for "Tides" written by Randi Ward.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<unitdate>2015</unitdate>
					<unittitle><title>Mantis</title> A Journal of Poetry, Criticism, and
						Translation, Issue 13</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Randi Ward contributes "On <title>December Morning</title>" pg. 76-77. Also
						contains Joe Betz, Natalie Shapero, Doug Ramspeck, Aaron Anstett, H. L. Hix,
						Keith Taylor, Meredith Davies Hadaway, C. W. Emerson, Stephen Massimilla, MJ
						Bender, Will Harris, Patrick Ryan Frank, Joe Delong, Alec Hershman, Emily
						Tuszynska, Benjamin S. Grossberg, Patricia Gray, Randall Brown, Monica
						Berlin, Matthew Stark, Jóhan Martin Christiansen, Kim Simonsen, Karen van
						Dyck, Eleanor Goodman, Ravi Shankar, Ha Poong Kim, Brett Foster, Michael
						Goldman, Darla Himeles, Robyn Newkumet, Fiona Sze-Lorrain, David Roderick,
						Kimberly Johnson, Jeffrey Skinner, Bruce Lack, and Zeeshan Sahil. </p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<unitdate>2013</unitdate>
					<unittitle><title>Lux</title> Vol. I</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Randi Ward contributes photos "PTSD" (pg. 24) and "Sycamore" (pg. 25). Also
						contains Gregory Robinson, David Emerson, Rick Moody, Roberta Borger, Derek
						Williams, Michelle Boyd, Erica Meiners, Celia Bland, Dianne Kornberg, Ram
						Devineni, Bianca Stone, Rachel James, David Prescott-Steed, Ken Cormier,
						Richard MacDonald, and Tim Kahl. </p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<unitdate>2014</unitdate>
					<unittitle><title>Lux</title> Vol. II</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Randi Ward contributes the photo "Lights Out" pg. 28. Also includes Chris
						George, Troy Jollimore, Andrew Keating, Jessica Hagy, Nick Flynn, Sarah
						Sentilles, Brandon Friend, Jason Griffin, Carne Griffiths, Courtney
						Hickerson, Mac Premo, Adrianna Dufay, Celia Bland, Dianne Kornberg, Giselle
						Potter, Courtney Hickerson, Donna Emerson, Matthew Cusick, Aaron McFavis,
						Jon Woowdward, </p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<unitdate>2015</unitdate>
					<unittitle><title>small po[r]tions</title> Issue 4</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Randi Ward contributes photos "Meyegraine 51" (pg. 16) and "Meyegraine 65"
						(pg. 17). Also contains Colin Post, Josh Fomon, Nico Vassilakis, Theodore
						Worozbyt, Jennifer Arcuni, Jessica Cogar, Derek Pollard, Michael Flatt,
						Dylan W. Krieger, Ivan Faute, Kevin McLellan, Matt Trease, Valerie Wernet,
						Aeron Bergman, Alejandra Salinas, Jill Magi, Dennis Caswell, Wailana Kalama,
						Lora Straub, Philip Kobylarz, Jeremy Schmidt, and Genevieve Kaplan. </p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<unitdate>2015</unitdate>
					<unittitle><title>The Sonder Review</title> Issue 2</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Randi Ward contributes photos "Meyegraine" pg. 24 and pg. 34. Also contains
						Jessemy Neiger, Lynn Holmgren, Kayla Pongrac, Tim Kahl, Jane Williams, Lisa
						Taylor, Barbara Harroun, Nina Alvarez, Amy Feltman, Rohan Garg, Brian
						Barbeito, Alli Hurley, Adel Souto, Kristen Oberly, and Andi Tomassi. </p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<unitdate>2015</unitdate>
					<unittitle><title>South Loop Review</title> Fiction and Art, the Final
						Issue</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Randi Ward contributes photo and description "In the Belly of the Bjørn" pg.
						77. Also contains Allen Gee, Christopher Malcomb, Jad Atkins, Allie
						Rowbottom, Rebecca Huntman, Marcia Aldrich, J. David Stevens, Amy Bernhard,
						Sarah Minor, Kaori Fujimoto, Joey Franklin, Cory Brown, Cora Jacobs, Andrea
						Mele, Jonathan Mack, Adam Clayton-Holland, Karen Fisher, Austin Ream,
						Stephanie Jurusz, Susannah B. Mintz, Timothy Fernandez, Jeffrey S. Chapman,
						Tyler Gasek, Kristy Ramsey, Joris Soeding, Cora Jacobs, and Brian Ritchard.
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<unitdate>2015</unitdate>
					<unittitle><title>Vencil </title>tíðarrit fyri skaldskap á føroyskum, nr.
						15/2015, 8. árg.</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Randi Ward contributes “Seks yrkingar”: “Froskur,” “Á snórinum,” “Snarljós,”
						“Bað,” “Slóttur,” “Uppringing” (Óla Jákup Niclasen týddi) pg. 46-48. </p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<unitdate>December 2005</unitdate>
					<unittitle><title>Sigmunds kvæði yngra </title> (Randi Ward skipar): 1 CD-ROM
					</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder"/>
					<unitdate>2015</unitdate>
					<unittitle><title/>Miscellaneous correspondence from Randi Ward to Curator,
						Fiske Icelandic Collection</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Notes dated 01 September and 27 October 2015; holiday card for 2015. </p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
		</dsc>
	</archdesc>
</ead>
