<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../styles/style.xsl" ?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
  <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1"
    scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
    <eadid mainagencycode="nic" countrycode="us"
      publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections//TEXT(US::NIC::RMM06976::George Cornell Supplee papers)//EN"
      >RMM06976.xml</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the George Cornell Supplee
          papers,<date>1902-1948.</date></titleproper>
        <titleproper type="sort">Supplee, George Cornell papers</titleproper>
        <author>Compiled by RMC Staff</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University
          Library</publisher>
        <date>February 2012</date>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note audience="internal">
          <p>
            <subject>agric</subject>
          </p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Finding aid encoded by RMC Staff, <date>March 2012</date></creation>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter>
    <titlepage>
      <titleproper>Guide to the George Cornell Supplee Papers,<lb/><date type="inclusive"
        encodinganalog="245$f">1902-1948.</date></titleproper>
      <num>Collection Number: 6976</num>
      <publisher>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections <lb/>Cornell University
        Library</publisher>
      <list type="deflist">
        <defitem>
          <label>Contact Information:</label>
          <item> Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections<lb/> 2B Carl A. Kroch
            Library<lb/> Cornell University<lb/> Ithaca, NY 14853<lb/> (607)
            255-3530<lb/> Fax: (607) 255-9524<lb/><extref
              href="mailto:rareref@cornell.edu"
              >rareref@cornell.edu</extref><lb/><extref
                href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu"
                >http://rmc.library.cornell.edu</extref><lb/></item>
        </defitem>
        <defitem>
          <label>Compiled by:</label>
          <item>RMC Staff</item>
        </defitem>
        <defitem>
          <label>Date completed:</label>
          <item>March 2012</item>
        </defitem>
        <defitem>
          <label>EAD encoding:</label>
          <item>RMC Staff, March 2012</item>
        </defitem>
        <defitem>
          <label>Date modified:</label>
          <item>Jude Corina, June 2017</item>
        </defitem>
      </list>
      <date>© 2012 Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University
        Library</date>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head id="a1">DESCRIPTIVE SUMMARY</head>
      <unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="MARC 245">George Cornell Supplee papers,
        <unitdate encodinganalog="MARC 245" type="inclusive">1902-1948.</unitdate>
      </unittitle>
      <unitid label="Collection Number:">6976</unitid>
      <origination label="Creator:">
        <persname encodinganalog="100" normal="Supplee, George Cornell, 1889-1949.">George
          Cornell Supplee 1889-1949.</persname>
      </origination>
      <physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="MARC 300">.5 cubic feet.</physdesc>
      <physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Printed material, Publications</physdesc>
      <repository label="Repository:">Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell
        University Library</repository>
      <abstract label="Abstract:">Collection includes publications authored or co-authored by Supplee and some other of his papers.</abstract>
      <langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="041"
        langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial>
    </did>
    <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
      <head id="a2" altrender="biography">BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE </head>
      <p>George Cornell Supplee BS '13, MS '14, PhD '19 was a biochemist who worked in the
        milk industry. He was employed by the Casein Co. of America and the Dry Milk Co.
        where he managed a laboratory. The company was later absorbed into the Bordon Co. He
        later founded his own consulting group called the G. C. Supplee Research Corp. Several documents from his highschool give his name as George Charles Supplee.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520">
      <head id="a3">COLLECTION DESCRIPTION</head>
      <p>Collection includes a disbound volume containing publications authored or co-authored
        by Supplee, mostly pertaining to milk and nutrition. A chemistry book from his
        coursework at Cornell annoted by him throughout. Also his Cornell Ph.D diploma and
        various certificates.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <controlaccess>
      <head id="a7">SUBJECTS</head>
      <controlaccess>
        <head>Names: </head>
        <persname encodinganalog="MARC 100">Supplee, George Cornell,1889-1949.</persname>
        <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Supplee, George Cornell, 1889-1949.</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <head>Subjects:</head>
        <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Dairy bacteriology.</subject>
        <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Milk--Analysis.</subject>
        <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Milk--Microbiology.</subject>
        <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Vitamins.</subject>
      </controlaccess>
    </controlaccess>
    <descgrp>
      <head id="a8">INFORMATION FOR USERS</head>
      <prefercite>
        <head>Cite As:</head>
        <p>George Cornell Supplee papers, #6976. Division of Rare and Manuscript
          Collections, Cornell University Library.</p>
      </prefercite>
    </descgrp>
    
    <dsc type="combined"> 
      <head>CONTAINER LIST</head> 
     
      <c01 level="series"> 
        <did>          
         
                   <unittitle>Formerly bound volume of Supplee's publications</unittitle> 
        </did> 
        <scopecontent>
          <p>Various publications and reprints of which Supplee was an author. Many of the publications have additional authors as well.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      
        <c02 level="item"> 
          <did> 
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unitdate>April 1915</unitdate>
            <unittitle>Variations in the Tests for Fat in Cream and Skimmed Milk</unittitle> 
          </did>          
        </c02>   
        
        <c02 level="item"> 
          <did> 
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unitdate>November 1917</unitdate>
            <unittitle>Preliminary Note on Certain Changes in Some of the Nitrogenous Constituents of Milk Caused by Bacteria</unittitle> 
          </did>          
        </c02> 
        
        <c02 level="item"> 
          <did> 
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unitdate>November 1919</unitdate>
            <unittitle>The Lecithin Content of Butter and its Possible Relationship to the Fishy Flavor</unittitle> 
          </did>          
        </c02> 
        
        <c02 level="item"> 
          <did> 
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unitdate>December 1920</unitdate>
            <unittitle>Relation of Fodder to the Antiscorbutic Potency and Salt Content of Milk</unittitle> 
          </did>          
        </c02>  
        
        <c02 level="item"> 
          <did> 
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unitdate>July-October 1921</unitdate>
            <unittitle>Comparaison au point de vue nutritif des laits liquides et desseches; Variations in Bacteria Counts from Milk as Affected by Media and Incubation Temperature; Bacterial Quality of Machine and Hand Drawn Milk; Citric Acid Content of Milk and Milk Products</unittitle> 
          </did>          
        </c02> 
        
        <c02 level="item"> 
          <did> 
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unitdate>January-November 1922</unitdate>
            <unittitle>Fat Analysis of Milk Powder; Bacterial Content of Milk Powder; The Copper Content of Cows' Milk; Bacteria Counts of Milk Powder as Obtained by the Microscopic Method; Bacterial Counts of Milk as Obtained by Various Media; Constructive Policies and Methods for Milk Improvement</unittitle> 
          </did>          
        </c02> 
      
        <c02 level="item"> 
          <did> 
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unitdate>1923</unitdate>
            <unittitle>Copper as a Constituent in Woman's and Cow's Milk. Its Absorption and Excretion by the Infant; Report of Committee on Dairy Methods</unittitle> 
          </did>           
        </c02> 
      
        <c02 level="item"> 
          <did> 
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
            <unitdate>November 1924</unitdate>
            <unittitle>Report of Committee on Dairy Methods; The Keeping Quality of Dry Milk; Sur la solubilite de la poudre de lait</unittitle> 
          </did>          
        </c02> 
      
        <c02 level="item"> 
          <did> 
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">9</container>
            <unitdate>January-April 1925</unitdate>
            <unittitle>The Solubility of Milk Powder as Affected by Moisture Content; Dry Milk for School Service</unittitle> 
          </did>          
        </c02> 
      
        <c02 level="item"> 
          <did> 
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">10</container>
            <unitdate>January-May 1926</unitdate>
            <unittitle>Humidity Equilibria of Milk Powders; Variations in the Antiscorbutic Properties of Dry Milk; Method of Packing Food Products Container Therefor </unittitle> 
          </did>          
        </c02> 
      
        <c02 level="item"> 
          <did> 
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">11</container>
            <unitdate>January-September 1917</unitdate>
            <unittitle>Richesse en vitamines du lait liquide et du lait sec; The Use of Milk in Bread; Antirachitic Properties of Irradiated Dry Milk</unittitle> 
          </did>          
        </c02> 
      
        <c02 level="item"> 
          <did> 
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">12</container>
            <unitdate>September 1928</unitdate>
            <unittitle>The Concentrated Water Soluble Fraction of Milk as a Source of Vitamin B</unittitle> 
          </did>          
        </c02> 
      
        <c02 level="item"> 
          <did> 
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">13</container>
            <unitdate>May 1929</unitdate>
            <unittitle>The Bacteriology of Dry Milk</unittitle> 
          </did>          
        </c02> 
      
        <c02 level="item"> 
          <did> 
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">14</container>
            <unitdate>1930</unitdate>
            <unittitle>Seasonal Variations in Certain Inorganic Constituents of Dry Milk Produced in New York and Wisconsin;  The Action of Irradiated Ergosterol on Rats and Chickens</unittitle> 
          </did>          
        </c02> 
      
        <c02 level="item"> 
          <did> 
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">15</container>
            <unitdate>May-October 1931</unitdate>
            <unittitle>The Comparative Antirachitic and Calcifying Properties of Irradiated Milk and Milk Derivatives; The Effect of Ultraviolet Irradiation on the Antiscorbutic Vitamin of Liquid and Dry Milk; Method of Irradiating Milk Solids with Ultra-Violet Rays and the Product of Such Method; The Relative Antineuritic (Vitamin "B") Potency of Certain Milk Derivatives; The Growth-Promoting Properties (Vitamin B Complex) of the Concentrated Water-Soluble Portion of Milk</unittitle> 
          </did>          
        </c02> 
      
        <c02 level="item"> 
          <did> 
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">16</container>
            <unitdate>January-November 1932</unitdate>
            <unittitle>Le lait naturel liquide et le lait sec dans l'etiologie de certaines anemies; Irradiated Milk: The Energy Requirements for Antirachitic Activation; Irradiated Milk: The Amount of Vitamin D and its Rate of Formation; L'activation antirachitique du lait au point de vue physique et biologique; Irradiated Milk: The Amount of Energy Required to Prevent Rickets in Chickens; The Vitamin "B" and "G" Content of Dry Skimmed Milk and Dry Whey; Irradiated Milk: The Influence of the Intensity and Character of the Radiations on the Antirachitic Potency; The Prevention and Cure of Rickets through Irradiated Milk</unittitle> 
          </did>          
        </c02> 
      
        <c02 level="item"> 
          <did> 
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">17</container>
            <unitdate>March-October 1933</unitdate>
            <unittitle>Antirachitic Activation of Milk by Direct Irradiation with Ultra-Violet Rays; Vitamin A Content of Milk Irradiated by Various Carbon Arcs; The Irradiation of Milk with Ultra Violet Rays; Vitamin D Milk</unittitle> 
          </did>          
        </c02> 
      
        <c02 level="item"> 
          <did> 
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">18</container>
            <unitdate>1934</unitdate>
            <unittitle>Studies on the Iodine Content of Milk; Process of Producing Beta Lactose; The Cholesterol Content and the Antirachitic Activation of Milk Constituents; Irradiated Milk: The Transmission and Antirachitic Activation of Milk Films by Ultra-Violet Radiations; Irradiated Milk: The Influence of Fat Content and Time of Exposure on the Antirachitic Potency; Irradiated Milk: Characteristics of the Flowing Film Required for Optimum Efficiency of Antirachitic Activation; Irradiated Milk: The Reflecting Properties and Antirachitic Activation as Affected by the Impingment Angle of the Incident Radiation; A Vitamin B Deficient Ration; The Vitamin B Supplementation of Milk; Certain Foam Producing Substances of Milk; The Iodine Content of Milk as Affected by Feeding Iodized Dry Milk; Casein Vitamin-Free</unittitle> 
          </did>          
        </c02> 
      
        <c02 level="item"> 
          <did> 
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">19</container>
            <unitdate>July-November 1935</unitdate>
            <unittitle>Process of Making Vitamin-Containing Material ; Photochemical Phenomena Involved in Vitamin G (B2) Studies; The Value of the Recording Ultraviolet Meter in the Irradiation of Milk; Precipitation of Proteinaceous Matter by Chlorine</unittitle> 
          </did>          
        </c02> 
    
        <c02 level="item"> 
          <did> 
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">20</container>
            <unitdate>1936</unitdate>
            <unittitle>Irradiated Evaporated Milk: The Transmission and Antirachitic Activation of Evaporated Milk Films by Ultra-Violet Radiations; The Fluorometric Estimation of Lactoflavin; Lactoflavin {and C17H20N4O6}; Lactoflavin, A Possible Contaminant of Vitamin-Free Diets; Lactoflavin, A Necessary Growth-Promoting Dietary Factor; The Influence of Dextrin and Sucrose on Growth and Dermatitis; Labco Products for Biological Research {and Supplement A1}; The Influence of Milk Constituents on the Effectiveness of Vitamin D; Pellagra-like Syndrome in Chicks; Lactoflavin in Nutrition  </unittitle> 
          </did>          
        </c02> 
    
        <c02 level="item"> 
          <did> 
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">21</container>
            <unitdate>N1937</unitdate>
            <unittitle>Significance of Quantitative Relationships in Vitamin B Complex Studies</unittitle> 
          </did>          
        </c02> 
    
        <c02 level="item"> 
          <did> 
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">22</container>
            <unitdate>January-November 1938</unitdate>
            <unittitle>Method of Irradiation; A Standard Method for the Determination of Vitamin B1</unittitle> 
          </did>          
        </c02> 
    
        <c02 level="item"> 
          <did> 
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">23</container>
            <unitdate>1939</unitdate>
            <unittitle>Fluid Irradiator; Canine Pediatrics: a collection of discussions from Veterinary Medicine on Nutrition in Young Puppies; Determining Riboflavin; a Fluorometric and Biologial Method; American Pharmaceutical Manufacturers' Association Mid=year Meeting Address</unittitle> 
          </did>          
        </c02> 
    
        <c02 level="item"> 
          <did> 
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">24</container>
            <unitdate>1940</unitdate>
            <unittitle>Concentration and Isolation of Water-Soluble Vitamins; Treatment of Whey; Whey as a Source of Vitamins and Vitamin Products; Method of Producing Vitamin D Product; Apparatus for Irradiation; Method of Irradiating Liquids; Method of and Apparatus for Irradiating Liquids; The Effect of Complementing Factors on the Quantitative Response and Specificity of Vitamin B6; Equilibrium Solutions of Certain Lactose-Salt Mixtures; Riboflavin is a Catalyst Controlling the Efficiency of Cellular Oxidation; The Instantaneous Heat Treatment of Milk </unittitle> 
          </did>          
        </c02> 
    
        <c02 level="item"> 
          <did> 
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">25</container>
            <unitdate>November 1941</unitdate>
            <unittitle>Preparation of Vitamin B Concentrate; The Instantaneous Heat Treatment of Milk; Labco Products for Biological Research; Method for Purifying Lactoflavin; The Chemical Determination of Nicotinic Acid in Milk and Milk Derivatives; Factors Affecting the Gas Content of Milk; The Lethal Effectiveness of Ultra Violet Rays Applied to Milk;</unittitle> 
          </did>          
        </c02> 
    
        <c02 level="item"> 
          <did> 
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">26</container>
            <unitdate>March-July 1942</unitdate>
            <unittitle>Interrelated Vitamin Requirements: Kidney Damage, Adrenal Hemorrhage and Cardiac Failure Correlated with Inadequacy of Pantothenic Acid; Factors Affecting the Riboflavin Content of the Liver; The Inverse Ratio between Flouride in Food and Drink and Dental Caries; Interrelated Vitamin Requirements</unittitle> 
          </did>          
        </c02> 
    
        <c02 level="item"> 
          <did> 
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">27</container>
            <unitdate>May 1944</unitdate>
            <unittitle>Cardiotoxic Adreno-Sympathetic Activity in Vitamin B Deficiencies</unittitle> 
          </did>          
        </c02> 
    
        <c02 level="item"> 
          <did> 
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">28</container>
            <unitdate>June-August 1945</unitdate>
            <unittitle>The Varying Requirement for Choline for Normal Metabolism of Proteins (Casein, Lactalbumin, and Soy Protein) with Particular Reference to the Hepatico-Renal Syndrome; A Comparison of Choline, Betaine and Dimethyl-Aminoethanol in the Prevention of the Hepatico-Renal Syndrome; Liquid Treating Method</unittitle> 
          </did>          
        </c02> 
    
        <c02 level="item"> 
          <did> 
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">29</container>
            <unitdate>October 1946</unitdate>
            <unittitle>Differential Nitrogen Retention from Caseion, Lactalbumin, and Soy Protein, and Hydrolysates Therefrom</unittitle> 
          </did>          
        </c02> 
    
        <c02 level="item"> 
          <did> 
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">30</container>
            <unitdate>January 1948</unitdate>
            <unittitle>Chemical Research and the Milk Industry</unittitle> 
          </did>          
        </c02> 
    
      </c01>  
      
      <c01 level="file"> 
        <did> 
          <container type="box">1</container>
          <container type="folder">31</container>        
          <unittitle>Miscellaneous notes, obituary, photo, New York Academy of Sciences and American Public Health Association certificates and First Year Academic certificate from Penn Yan Academy..</unittitle> 
        </did>          
      </c01> 
      <c01 level="item"> 
        <did> 
          <container type="box">1</container>         
          <unitdate>1934</unitdate>
          <unittitle>Supplee's copy of <title>The Vitamin B Requirement of Man</title> by George R. Cowgill, published by Yale University Press. </unittitle> 
        </did><scopecontent><p>Stamped as from the The Dry Milk Company, Inc. Research Laboratories, Bainbridge, N.Y.</p></scopecontent>          
      </c01> 
      <c01 level="item"> 
        <did> 
          <container type="box">1</container>         
          <unitdate>1902</unitdate>
          <unittitle>Supplee's copy of the <title>Laboratory Manual to Accompany Clarke and Dennis's Elementary Chemistry</title> by L. M. Dennis and F. W. Clarke. </unittitle> 
        </did>     <scopecontent><p>Signed by Supplee with his 210 College Ave address from while at Cornell. The book is extensively annotated by Supplee.</p></scopecontent>     
      </c01> 
      <c01 level="file"> 
        <did> 
          <container type="map-case"></container>
          <container type="folder">1</container> 
          <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1909/1938">1909</unitdate>
          <unittitle>Penn Yan Academy diploma</unittitle> 
        </did>          
      </c01> 
      <c01 level="file"> 
        <did> 
          <container type="map-case"></container>
          <container type="folder">1</container> 
          <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1900">1900</unitdate>
          <unittitle>University of the State of New York regents diploma</unittitle> 
        </did>          
      </c01> 
      <c01 level="file"> 
        <did> 
          <container type="map-case"></container>
          <container type="folder">1</container> 
          <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1913">1913</unitdate>
          <unittitle>Cornell University Bachelor of Science diploma</unittitle> 
        </did>          
      </c01> 
      <c01 level="file"> 
        <did> 
          <container type="map-case"></container>
          <container type="folder">1</container> 
          <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1919">1919</unitdate>
          <unittitle>Cornell Doctor of Philosophy diploma</unittitle> 
        </did>          
      </c01> 
      <c01 level="file"> 
        <did> 
          <container type="map-case"></container>
          <container type="folder">1</container> 
          <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1920">1920</unitdate>
          <unittitle>The Society of the Sigma Xi</unittitle> 
        </did>          
      </c01> 
      <c01 level="file"> 
        <did> 
          <container type="map-case"></container>
          <container type="folder">1</container> 
          <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1936">1936</unitdate>
          <unittitle>American Medical Association Silver Medal at the Scientific Exhibit of the Kansas City Session</unittitle> 
        </did>          
      </c01> 
      <c01 level="file"> 
        <did> 
          <container type="map-case"></container>
          <container type="folder">1</container> 
          <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1938">1938</unitdate>
          <unittitle>American Institute of Chemists Fellow certificates</unittitle> 
        </did>          
      </c01> 
    </dsc> 
  </archdesc> 
</ead> 
