<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<!-- Transformed with v1v2002_4_cornell.xsl -->

<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../dtds/ead.dtd">
	 
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../styles/style.xsl" ?>
<ead>
   <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1"
      scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
      <eadid mainagencycode="nic" countrycode="us"
         publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections//TEXT(US::NIC::RMM09181::Clarence Bloomfield Moore collection)//EN"
         >RMM09181.xml</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Clarence Bloomfield Moore collection, 1891-1918.</titleproper>
            <titleproper type="sort">Moore, Clarence Bloomfield collection, 1891-1918</titleproper>
            <author>Compiled by Evan Fay Earle and Mary B. Davis</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University
               Library</publisher>
            <date>March 2006</date>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note audience="internal">
               <p>
                  <subject>nam</subject>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>Finding aid encoded by Evan Fay Earle, <date>March 2006</date>
         </creation>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change encodinganalog="583">
            <date normal="2007-05-29">2007-05-29</date>
            <item>converted from EAD 1.0 to EAD 2002 </item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <frontmatter>
      <titlepage>
         <titleproper>Guide to the Clarence Bloomfield Moore
            Collection,<lb/>1891-1918.</titleproper>
         <num>Collection Number: 9181</num>
         <publisher>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections <lb/>Cornell University
            Library</publisher>
         <list type="deflist">
            <defitem>
               <label>Contact Information:</label>
               <item>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections<lb/> 2B Carl A. Kroch Library<lb/>
                  Cornell University<lb/> Ithaca, NY 14853<lb/> (607) 255-3530<lb/> Fax: (607) 255-9524<lb/>
                  <extref href="mailto:rareref@cornell.edu">rareref@cornell.edu</extref>
                  <lb/>
                  <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu"
                     >http://rmc.library.cornell.edu</extref>
                  <lb/></item>
            </defitem>
            <defitem>
               <label>Compiled by:</label>
               <item>Evan Fay Earle and Mary B. Davis</item>
            </defitem>
            <defitem>
               <label>Date completed:</label>
               <item>March 2006</item>
            </defitem>
            <defitem>
               <label>EAD encoding:</label>
               <item>Evan Fay Earle March 2006</item>
            </defitem>
            <defitem>
               <label>Date modified:</label>
               <item>Evan Earle, August 2011</item>
            </defitem>
         </list>
         <date>© 2003 Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library</date>
      </titlepage>
   </frontmatter>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <head id="a1">DESCRIPTIVE SUMMARY</head>
         <unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="MARC 245">Clarence Bloomfield Moore collection,
               <unitdate type="inclusive" encodinganalog="MARC 245">1891-1918.</unitdate>
         </unittitle>
         <unitid label="Collection Number:">9181</unitid>
         <origination label="Creator:">
            <persname encodinganalog="100"
               normal="Moore, Clarence B.(Clarence Bloomfield), 1852-1936.">Clarence B.(Clarence
               Bloomfield), Moore 1852-1936.</persname>
         </origination>
         <physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="MARC 300">3 cubic ft., 45 v.</physdesc>
         <physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Correspondence, Diaries, Manuscripts</physdesc>
         <repository label="Repository:">Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell
            University Library</repository>
         <abstract label="Abstract:">Collection contains 45 field notebooks from Moore's
            southeastern archaeological investigations.</abstract>
         <langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="041"
               langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
         <head id="a2" altrender="biography">BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE </head>
         <p>Clarence B. Moore was a wealthy amateur archaeologist from Philadelphia who crisscrossed
            the rivers of the southeast each year in his steam-powered paddleboat, the Gopher,
            excavating sites near the shores in states ranging from Alabama to Tennessee. During his
            twenty years of investigations, Moore explored an astounding number of archaeological
            sites. He published the results of his investigations regularly, translating the field
            notes he kept in small journals into the larger, neatly written notebooks that he later
            used as the basis for his publications. During his excavations, Moore uncovered many
            artifacts associated with Indian burials that later ended up in museums. These artifacts
            are now subject to repatriation by tribal members working to reclaim their sacred
            heritage. Natives and non-natives alike rely on Moore's field notes, which can provide
            important clues about the history of an artifact, helping to further repatriation
            claims.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520">
         <head id="a3">COLLECTION DESCRIPTION</head>
         <p>Collection contains 45 field notebooks from Moore's southeastern archaeological
            investigations. Moore seems to have developed a system where he recorded his on-site
            information in a small notebook, and later transferred the data in a more polished
            form to larger notebooks which he then used as the text for his publications. The
            smaller notebooks often contain details which were eliminated from the larger texts.
            They have site lists appended. The large format notebooks include both site lists
            and alphabetical indices. Most of his field notes are from excavations in Alabama,
            Arkansas, Florida, Georgia, Kentucky, Louisiana, Mississippi, and Tennessee. He also
            conducted limited field work in Illinois, Indiana, Mississippi River, Missouri, and
            South Carolina. His notes contain information about the finds and the conditions
            under which they were excavated, providing locality data and details about the
            artifacts. Information includes sketches of the site, detailed information about
            layout and descriptions of unearthed objects, such as jewelry and pottery. Some
            notebooks also have weather reports for the days of the excavations. Also included
            is a dictionary of archaeological terms, with bibliographic citations, and some
            correspondence. Correspondents include Dr. Milo G. Miller and George W. Rossignol.
            Rossignol correspondence includes information regarding a proposed expedition to Red
            River, Texas and to Arkansas in 1899. Published guide included. Moore's publications
            based on his artifacts and field notes were housed in the Museum of the American
            Indian Library. The artifacts were located in the museum as well.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <head id="a7">SUBJECTS</head>
         <controlaccess>
            <head>Names: </head>
            <persname encodinganalog="MARC 100">Moore, Clarence B.1852-1936.</persname>
            <persname encodinganalog="MARC 700">Miller, Milo G. </persname>
            <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Rossignol, George W. </persname>
            <persname encodinganalog="MARC 700">Rossignol, George W. </persname>
            <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 710">Huntington Free Library.</corpname>
            <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Museum of the American Indian, Heye
               Foundation.</corpname>
         </controlaccess>
         <controlaccess>
            <head>Subjects:</head>
            <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Archaeologists.</subject>
            <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Indians of North America.</subject>
            <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Indians of North America--Antiquities.</subject>
            <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Indians of North America--Dwellings.</subject>
            <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Indians of North America--Funeral customs and
               rites.</subject>
            <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Archaeology--Dictionaries.</subject>
            <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Excavations (Archaeology).</subject>
            <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Excavations (Archaeology)--Middle West.</subject>
            <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Excavations (Archaeology)--Southern
               States.</subject>
            <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Excavations (Archaeology)--Alabama.</subject>
            <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Excavations (Archaeology)--Arkansas.</subject>
            <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Excavations (Archaeology)--Florida.</subject>
            <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Excavations (Archaeology)--Georgia.</subject>
            <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Excavations (Archaeology)--Illinois.</subject>
            <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Excavations (Archaeology)--Indiana.</subject>
            <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Excavations (Archaeology)--Kentucky.</subject>
            <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Excavations (Archaeology)--Louisiana.</subject>
            <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Excavations (Archaeology)--Missouri.</subject>
            <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Excavations (Archaeology)--South
               Carolina.</subject>
            <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Excavations (Archaeology)--Tennessee.</subject>
            <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Excavations (Archaeology)--United
               States.</subject>
            <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Mound-builders.</subject>
            <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Scientific expeditions--United States.</subject>
         </controlaccess>
         <controlaccess>
            <head>Places:</head>
            <geogname encodinganalog="MARC 651">Alabama--Antiquities.</geogname>
            <geogname encodinganalog="MARC 651">Arkansas--Antiquities.</geogname>
            <geogname encodinganalog="MARC 651">Florida--Antiquities.</geogname>
            <geogname encodinganalog="MARC 651">Georgia--Antiquities.</geogname>
            <geogname encodinganalog="MARC 651">Kentucky--Antiquities.</geogname>
            <geogname encodinganalog="MARC 651">Louisiana--Antiquities.</geogname>
            <geogname encodinganalog="MARC 651">Mississippi--Antiquities.</geogname>
            <geogname encodinganalog="MARC 651">Tennessee--Antiquities.</geogname>
            <geogname encodinganalog="MARC 651">Illinois--Antiquities.</geogname>
            <geogname encodinganalog="MARC 651">Indiana--Antiquities.</geogname>
            <geogname encodinganalog="MARC 651">Missouri--Antiquities.</geogname>
            <geogname encodinganalog="MARC 651">South Carolina--Antiquities.</geogname>
            <geogname encodinganalog="MARC 651">Texas--Antiquities.</geogname>
            <geogname encodinganalog="MARC 651">Coosa River (Ga. and Ala.)</geogname>
            <geogname encodinganalog="MARC 651">Mississippi River.</geogname>
         </controlaccess>
         <controlaccess>
            <head>Form and Genre Terms:</head>
            <genreform encodinganalog="MARC 655" source="aat">Field notes.</genreform>
         </controlaccess>
      </controlaccess>
      <descgrp type="admininfo">
         <head id="a8">INFORMATION FOR USERS</head>
         <prefercite>
            <head>Cite As:</head>
            <p>Clarence Bloomfield Moore collection, #9181. Division of Rare and Manuscript
               Collections, Cornell University Library.</p>
         </prefercite>
         <p>
            <emph render="bold">In Search of C.B. Moore.</emph> The field notes of Clarence B.
            Moore's southeastern archaeological explorations, 1891-1918, are a frequently referenced
            manuscript collection. Moore's expeditions, which spanned more than a quarter of a
            century and reached almost every navigable river in the southern United States, are
            well-known in the world of archaeology, but remarkably little has been published about
            the man and his work. </p>
         <p>A wealthy Philadelphian, he started his amateur archaeological work at the age of 40,
            navigating the southeastern rivers each year in a steam-powered paddle boat, the Gopher.
            Publishing the result of his excavations with impressive regularity, the volume of his
            work in the Southeast is astounding. Although artifacts he uncovered continue to surface
            in new public and private collections, a large part of his archaeological treasures
            originally were given to the Academy of Natural Sciences in Philadelphia. This
            collection, along with copies of his publications were sold to the Museum of the
            American Indian in 1929--a transaction which was conducted in secrecy, but publicized by
            H. Newell Wardle, then an assistant curator at the Academy. </p>
         <p>There is some consensus about Moore among archaeologists writing today about areas he
            previously excavated. Most comment on his amateur status. They agree that the amount of
            work he accomplished was remarkable by any standard, and many add that his methodology
            was advanced for his time. All are impressed by the regularity and quality of his
            publications, which were profusely illustrated with photographs taken by Moore (he was
            an award-winning photographer), and line drawings by Mary Louise Baker. Many cite these
            publications, issued regularly by the Academy of Natural Sciences in Philadelphia, as
            Moore's greatest contribution to southeastern archaeology. </p>
         <p>Neither searches of the literature on southeastern archaeology, nor phone conversations
            with archaeologists, archivists, and librarians from institutions all over the eastern
            United States yielded a published comprehensive analysis of Moore's work. The complex
            telephone network did unearth H. Newell Wardle's memorial to Moore, which the
            Philadelphia Anthropological Society has kindly allowed us to reprint. Miss Wardle, who
            resigned her position as assistant curator at the Academy of Natural Sciences when that
            institution sold its collection of Moore's archaeological treasures, remembered Moore
            with fondness, and penned the only detailed description of his archaeological
            explorations written to date. The needed comprehensive analysis of Moore's participation
            in southeastern archaeology has yet to be done. </p>
         <p>
            <emph render="bold">Clarence Bloomfield Moore (1852-1936) by H. Newell Wardle.</emph>
            Reprinted with permission from the Bulletin of the Philadelphia Anthropological Society,
            vol. 9, no. 2, (March 1956) </p>
         <p>Clarence Bloomfield Moore, son of Bloomfield Moore and Clara Jessup Moore, was born in
            Philadelphia on January 14, 1852. He received his B.A. from Harvard University in 1873
            and, in 1876, he traveled across South America, over the Andes and down the Amazon. </p>
         <p>Following the death of his father and the litigation which involved the estate, he was
            astonished to find that the systematic savings from his allowance, made at his father's
            suggestion and duplicated by him, gave him the means for a journey around the world. </p>
         <p>Before 1892, Clarence Moore had definitely settled upon what was to be his life work. He
            was then forty, and rather weary of life as a socialite, broken only by European travel
            and excursions for big-game hunting. After an accident on a safari, resulting in an eye
            injury, he turned to less dangerous field- work--the archaeological exploration of the
            Southeastern States, then but little known. [N.B. Moore reports in a Harvard College
            Anniversary Report that his eye injury was caused by a tennis ball.] Five papers on the
            Shell Heaps of the St. Johns River, hitherto unexplored, appeared in the American
            Naturalist, between November 1892 and June 1894. </p>
         <p>In 1893 Mr. Moore had associated with him Dr. Milo G. Miller, secretary, co-worker,
            physician, and friend, who was to remain his inseparable companion to the end of his
            scientific work. The archaeological campaigns were well organized: preliminary
            investigation of the territory, location of likely sites, and arrangements with owners:
            followed, in the spring, by the expedition. Summers were devoted to cleaning, repairing,
            photographing and studying the collection; the reports were written in the fall. </p>
         <p>The work began with the previously unexplored sand mounds of the St. Johns River,
            Florida (1894); in 1895 the sand mounds of Duval County, Murphy's River, and the
            Ocklawaha River were excavated. In succeeding years, the mounds of the Florida east
            coast, Georgia, and South Carolina were explored. By 1899 the expedition was back on the
            Gulf Coast, and reports on the Alabama River, the coast of northwest Florida and central
            Florida, each with its important treasure trove, were published. </p>
         <p>In 1903, Mr. Moore published four papers in the American Anthropologist, one of which,
            "Sheet Copper from the Mounds Not Necessarily of European Origin," led to a discussion
            by McGuire, Putnam, Dorsey, Willoughby, and Moorehead, first appearing fully in the
            Anthropologist and later assembled in a special imprint. Other articles in this period
            include "The So-Called Hoe-Shaped Implement" (1903), "Aboriginal Urn Burial in the
            United States" (1904), and "A Form of Urn Burial in Mobile Bay" (1905)--all in the
            American Anthropologist. </p>
         <p>Further plans for archaeological exploration led the expedition, in 1905, to the Black
            Warrior River to Moundville, Alabama where highly artistic objects in shell, pottery,
            stone, and copper, belonging to a great ceremonial center, were excavated. So strong was
            the feeling of Mexican affinity that Dr. J. Walter Fewkes urged that archaeological work
            should be carried on around the northern border of the Gulf; the expedition went on to
            Mobile Bay and Mississippi Sound but found no objects of similar artistic quality.
            However, Mr. Moore's boat, The Gopher, returned to Moundville the following year, and
            further digging was rewarded by the discovery of a large limestone bowl, with a head in
            relief on the rim and incised over the bottom; this piece was both beautiful and unique
            but not as breath-taking as the diorite duck effigy bowl, found the previous year. </p>
         <p>In 1908, work was carried on in the ancient cemeteries of Arkansas and Mississippi and
            was rewarded with red-and-buff-ware effigy vessels and incised bottles. In November
            1908, and from January to April 1909, the expedition explored the Oachita Valley in
            northeastern Louisiana and southeastern Arkansas. Here, too, was found a culture of high
            artistic merit and originality-- graceful bottles; painted and engraved effigy vessels,
            tripod and compound; stone and pottery effigy pipes. It was a major undertaking,
            requiring the greatest care, and it gave important results. The expedition of 1909-1910
            worked on the St. Francis, White, and Black Rivers, in Arkansas, finding jars in the
            form of human heads, kneeling human effigies, turtles and fish, and shell gorgets, in
            addition to other material. </p>
         <p>From November of 1910 until March of 1911, Mr. Moore worked along the Mississippi River.
            As usual, the region had been explored in the preceding months by Capt. Rayburn, of The
            Gopher, and permission had been obtained to dig at promising sites. Two objects, among
            the many of interest, stand out: an effigy limestone pipe, in the form of a crouching
            man, and a "teapot" vessel, representing a tortoise lying on its back, its head lifted
            and the tail tapering into a spout. (The "teapot" form, it must be noted, is of very
            limited distribution.) </p>
         <p>Mr. Moore's next expedition followed the Red River through Louisiana, to a point above
            Fulton, Arkansas, and consumed five months of 1911 and part of 1912. Notable, among
            other things, were Haley Mound and Foster Place, with their unusual grave furniture--to
            mention only two of a wealth of sites. In 1913, Mr. Moore undertook the re-study of the
            Tennessee River, on which a great deal had been published that needed clarification by
            careful field-work. The result was a report of 422 pages, with illustrations of much
            newly found material. </p>
         <p>The next investigations were along the Green River, Kentucky, and along the Lower Ohio
            River and Mississippi. Among the rewards were the very beautiful "bannerstones," often
            associated with long bone or antler hooks. Capt. Rayburn, of The Gopher, believed them
            to be implements for making nets, similar tools having been described by William
            Churchill as being employed by Polynesian women of New Britain, and he even demonstrated
            their use by making a net. Though not fully convinced, Mr. Moore refers to these
            "bannerstones" as "sizers." </p>
         <p>The Gopher next moved back to the Mississippi. Mr. Moore writes: "The end of the work on
            Green River, Kentucky, virtually completed for us the list of all rivers navigable by
            our steamer." One river, the Chocktawhatchee, in Alabama and northern Florida, had been
            recently opened by removal of a sand- bar. Hoping to obtain other examples of a rare
            type of ware, of which his expedition had encountered a sherd, Mr. Moore returned to the
            northwest Florida coast in 1917 and was rewarded by finding remarkable vessels of a rich
            red ware. </p>
         <p>Through more than a quarter of a century, Mr. Moore explored every accessible site where
            the Indians of the Southern States had made their homes and buried their dead. He
            carefully recorded the data and brought back the evidence to be preserved for all time,
            publishing the results of his investigations in twenty-one large volumes. Through his
            work, he made a magnificent contribution to our knowledge of the First Americans. </p>
         <p>In 1929, the Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia, which was the repository of
            much of this unique collection, was intent on modernizing its zoological exhibits and
            coveted the space devoted to the Science of Man (See Science, Aug. 2, 1929). To save his
            collection from utter destruction, Mr. Moore was obliged to consent to its sale by the
            Academy to the Museum of the American Indian in New York. The only part of this great
            collection which remains in Philadelphia is, I believe, a small lot from an early
            Florida expedition of 1892, given to the Wagner Institute, where it remains, with the
            exception of one piece which Mr. Moore brought back to add to his main collection. </p>
         <p>In his field-work and research, Mr. Moore sought and demanded accuracy. For his later
            reports, he was fortunate in having the beautiful and perfect drawings of Mary Louise
            Baker. Although Clarence B. Moore was in correspondence with many Americanists of his
            time, he was personally known to few. His superb reports were generously distributed to
            all in the field as well as to institutions, and he expected only a simple
            acknowledgment. None came from the Government ethnologist, Dr. W.J. McGee. When this was
            repeated, Mr. Moore sent him a self-addressed post-card with instructions: "If received,
            write `yes'; if not received, write `no'; if not wanted, write `nit'." That report was
            acknowledged. Generous by nature, he would go out of his way to help where he saw the
            need, but he preferred to make his gifts in his own fashion. </p>
         <p>Generally, Mr. Moore shunned the ladies, but he held warm friendships with a few. Miss
            Baker once asked him if he had seen Mrs. --- lately, referring to the widowed sister of
            a close friend, recently deceased. His reply was a shocked: "Why, I never call on the
            ladies! They might ask me to call again!" But once a year, he hired a carriage and pair,
            with special driver, in which he took an old lady on a drive through Fairmount Park. And
            also once a year, at Christmas time, it was his habit to give a formal dinner--not
            stag--at his home at 1321 Locust Street in Philadelphia. He died on March 24, 1936. </p>
         <p>
            <emph render="bold">Guide Information</emph>
         </p>
         <p>The field notes of Clarence B. Moore's southeastern archaeological investigations are in
            45 notebooks spanning the years 1892-1918. Moore seems to have developed a system where
            he recorded his on-site information in a small notebook, and later transferred the data
            in a more polished form to larger notebooks which he then used as the text for his
            publications. </p>
         <p>The smaller notebooks often contain details which were eliminated from the larger texts.
            They have site lists appended, which have been included in this guide. The large format
            notebooks include both site lists and alphabetical indices. Sites from the large
            notebooks are not listed in this guide because they are readily available in Moore's
            publications. A daily journal was kept in the large format notebooks, and journal entry
            dates and pagination are noted in this guide. </p>
         <p>If using the microfilm, the frames are not numbered, individual notebooks are. Page
            numbers have been included in this guide where appropriate to assist researchers in
            locating desired information. Total page numbers given for each notebook reflect the
            number of pages in the notebook rather than the number of pages actually used. Each roll
            contains a general index to the field notebooks by date, state, and country. Consult
            this index to determine which notebooks are relevant.</p>
      </descgrp>
      <relatedmaterial>
         <head id="a5">RELATED MATERIALS</head>
         <p>Microfilm available.</p>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <arrangement>
         <head>SERIES LIST</head>
         <p>
            <emph render="bold">
               <ref target="s1" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">Series I. Field Notebooks</ref>
            </emph>
            <lb/>
         </p>
         <p>
            <emph render="bold">
               <ref target="s2" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">Series II. Other Material</ref>
            </emph>
            <lb/>
         </p>
         <p>
            <emph render="bold">
               <ref target="s3" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">Series III. Guide to Notebooks by
                  Year</ref>
            </emph>
            <lb/>
         </p>
         <p>
            <emph render="bold">
               <ref target="s4" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">Series IV. Guide to Notebooks by
                  Location</ref>
            </emph>
            <lb/>
         </p>
      </arrangement>
      <dsc type="combined">
         <head>CONTAINER LIST</head>
         <c01 level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle id="s1">Series I. Field Notebooks</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 1</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1891</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Small notebook. 141p. St. John's River, Florida. Includes the following sites
                     in Volusia, Orange, Putnam, Brevard, and Lake counties: </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <list type="simple">
                        <item>Astor, Bird's Island, Black Hammock, Bluffton, Bryson Mound, Crow's
                           Bluff, Duval Blue Creek, Fort Taylor, Ginn's Grove, Halfway Mound,
                           Huntington's, Huntoon Island, Indian Fields, Lake Monroe, Lake Harney,
                           Mocassin Island, Mosquito Grove, Mount Royal, Mount Taylor, Mulberry
                           Mound, Orange Mound, Pawpaw Mound, Persimmon Mound, Possum Bluff,
                           Raulerson's, St. Francis, Starkes Grove, Thornhill Lake, Thursby's Blue
                           Spring, Tick Island, Turtle Mound, Volusia.</item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 1</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 2</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1892</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Large notebook. 192p. St. John's River sand mounds in Florida. Includes sites
                     in Orange, Volusia, Brevard, and Lake counties. Journal entries January 7,
                     1892-April 4, 1892. Excavation write-ups p.1-45; by site, p.51-120. [N.B. These
                     are a continuation of text from vol. 3, p.179.] Bookkeeping notes, p.189-192.
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 1</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 3</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1892</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Large notebook. 179p. St. John's River, Florida. Includes sites in Orange,
                     Lake, Volusia, Brevard, and Putnam counties. Entries begin with January 7,
                     1892. Excavation write- ups, p.1-179. [N.B. These are continued in vol. 2,
                     starting with p.51.] </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 1</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 4</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1892-1893</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Large notebook. 187p. St. John's River, Florida. Includes sites in Volusia,
                     Orange, Lake, and Putnam counties. Entries begin with November 13, 1892,
                     p.1-187. Includes journal entries, April 12, 1892-April 19, 1892 (1p.).
                     Continues journal entries November 10, 1892-April 19, 1893, p.188-226 </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 1</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 5</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1893-1894</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Large notebook. 118p. St. John's River, Florida, pt. 2. Includes sites in
                     Putnam, Lake, Duval, Clay, St. John's, Orange, Lake, and Volusia counties.
                     Entries begin with April 27, 1893, p.1-109. Alphabetical list of individuals
                     and institutions, p.110-115. Journal entries, September 27, 1893- April 19,
                     1894, p.193-228. Includes published letter from Moore to Dr. L.H. Harris,
                     describing a mound in Harris's orange grove in St. John's County, p.14-15.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 1</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 6</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1893-1894</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Small notebook. 176p. St. John's River, Florida. Entries begin September 27,
                     1893, p.1-106. Miscellaneous notes, p.166-176. Includes the following sites in
                     St. John's, Putnam, Clay, Duval, Volusia, Orange, Marion, and Lake
                     counties:</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <list type="simple">
                        <item>Bayard's Point, Beauclerc, Brown's Landing, Clark's Creek, Davenport
                           (Ocklawaha River), Deep Creek, Duval's, Fulton, Geiger's Mound, Ginn's
                           Grove, Grant Mound, Harris Mound, Hitchen's Creek, Julington Creek,
                           Juniper Creek, Mandarin Point, Mill Cove, Mount Royal, Mulberry Mound,
                           Orangedale, Palatka, Pecolata, Peter's Creek, Racey Point, Rice Creek,
                           Silver Springs, St. Augustine Road, St. John's Bluff, Switzerland,
                           Thornhill Lake, Thursby Mound, Tick's Island, Westonia.</item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 1</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 7</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1892-1893</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Small notebook. 178p. St. John's River, Florida. Entries begin November 13,
                     1892, p.1-137. Miscellaneous notes, p.176-8. Includes the following sites in
                     Lake, Volusia, Putnam, and Orange counties:</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <list type="simple">
                        <item>Astor, Cook's Ferry, De Leon Springs, Dunn Creek Horse Landing,
                           Duval's Blue Creek, Fort Florida, Ginn's Grove, Huntoon Island, Juniper
                           Creek, Kelly Grove, Mount Royal, Mulberry Mound, Murphy Island, Norwalk,
                           Orange Mound, Raulerson's, Tick Island.</item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 1</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 8</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1894-1895</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Large notebook. 252p. St. John's River and Ochlawaha River, Florida. Includes
                     sites in Derval, Putnam, Marion, and Lake counties. Entries begin November 25,
                     1894, p.1- 109. Includes journal entries, November 19, 1894-June 16, 1895,
                     p.228-252. Also has alphabetical listing of topics (i.e. aboriginal copper)
                     with page references, p.218-227. </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 2</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 9</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1894-1895</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Small notebook. 176p. Ocklawaha River and St. John's River, Florida. Entries
                     begin November 25, 1894, p.1-101; p.169-176. Includes the following sites in
                     Putnam, Marion, Lake, and Duvall counties:</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <list type="simple">
                        <item>
                           <emph render="italic">Ocklawaha River: </emph>Barclay's, Delk's Landing,
                           Ditch Creek, Emeralda, Fort Mason, Helena Mound, Higley, Indian Bluff,
                           Lake Eustis, Lanier, Palmetto Landing, Richmond Mound, Silver Springs,
                           Stark's Landing, Tavares, Umatilla, Yallaha. </item>
                        <item>
                           <emph render="italic">St. John's River: </emph>Alicia, Broward Mound,
                           Chaseville, Daniel's Landing, Floral Bluff, Gilbert Mound, Grant Mound,
                           Horseshoe Landing, Johnson Mound, Monroe Mound, Murphy's Island, Shields
                           Mound, South Grant Mound. </item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 2</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 10</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1895-1896</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Large notebook. 179p. Georgia coast. Includes sites in Camden and McIntosh
                     counties. Entries begin October 22, 1895, p.1-97. Includes journal entries
                     October 17, 1895-April 27, 1886, p.139-179. </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 2</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 11</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1896-1897</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Small notebook. 178p. Georgia coast. Entries begin November 25, 1896, p.1-178.
                     Includes the following sites in Bryan, Liberty and McIntosh counties:</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <list type="simple">
                        <item>Creighton Island, Crescent, Hopkins Mound, Kind New Ground Field, St.
                           Catherine's Island. </item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 2</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 12</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1896-1897</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Large notebook. 240p. Georgia coast. Includes sites in McIntosh, Belleville,
                     Chatham, Bryan, and Liberty counties. Beginning entry, Ossabow Island, undated.
                     p.1-215. Includes journal entries November 20, 1896-April 26, 1897, p.216-
                     240.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 2</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 13</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1897-1898</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Large notebook. 288p. South Carolina coast, including Savannah and Altamaha
                     Rivers. Includes sites in Beaufort, Chatham, Screven, Barnwell, Burke, Wayne,
                     Liberty, Tattnall, and Appling counties. Beginning entry, Bull Island, undated.
                     p.1-69. Includes journal entries November 15, 1897- April 27, 1898 and November
                     24, 1898-December 16, 1898, p.252- 288.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 2</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 14</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1897-1898</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Small notebook. 68p. South Carolina, Savannah River, and Altahama. Beginning
                     entry, Indian Hill, undated. p.1-68. Includes the following sites in South
                     Carolina and Georgia sites in Beaufort, Chatham, Screven, Barnwell, Liberty
                     (South Carolina and Georgia), Wayne, Tatnall, and Appling counties:</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <list type="simple">
                        <item>
                           <emph render="italic">South Carolina: </emph>Bluffton (Cressons), Burton
                           Hill, Port Royal Island, Calawassie Island, Hasell Point, Indian Hill,
                           Indian Hill, St. Helena Island, Little Island, Polleewahnee Island. </item>
                        <item>
                           <emph render="italic">Savannah River: </emph> Brooks Landing, Hudson's
                           Ferry, Mills Landing, Pipe Makers Creek.</item>
                        <item>
                           <emph render="italic">Altahama River: </emph>Beards Bluff, Buckhorn
                           Bluff, Darien, Gray's Landing, Hell's Shoals, Iron Mine, Joiner's Island,
                           Lake Bluff, Matlock's Water Pond, Mitchell's Lake, Old River, Reddish
                           Landing, Tilman's Ferry. </item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 2</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 15</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1899</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Small notebook. 155p. Mobile River, Alabama. Entries begin with February 8,
                     1899, p.1-85. Expedition accounts, p.86-94, 154-155. Includes the following
                     sites in Mobile, Wilcox, Montgomery, Dallas, Monroe, and Elmore counties: </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <list type="simple">
                        <item>Alabama River, Big Eddy Landing, Burford's Landing, Charlotte
                           Thompson's Place, Coal Bluff, Coosa River, Durand's Bend, Horseshoe Bend,
                           Hunter Place, Jackson's Bend, Little River Mound, Little River, Matthew's
                           Landing, Matthew's Place, Potts Landing, Taloosa and Coosa River,
                           Twenty-one Mile Landing, Webb's Landing. </item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 2</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 16</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1899</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Large notebook. 200p. Alabama and Mobile Rivers. Includes sites in Wilcox,
                     Montgomery, Elmore, Dallas, and Monroe counties. Beginning entry, Twenty-one
                     Mile Bluff, undated. p.11- 108. Accounting entries p.111-115. Includes journal
                     entries February 6, 1899-April 22, 1899, p.183-200. </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 2</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 17</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1900</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Large notebook. 202p. Florida west coast. Includes sites in Hillsboro, Lee,
                     Monroe, and Manatee counties. Beginning entry, mound near Riverview, undated.
                     p.1-47. Includes journal entries January 12, 1900-April 27, 1900,
                     p.178-202.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 3</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 18</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1901</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Small notebook. 134p. Northwest coast of Florida, Alabama, and Mississippi.
                     Beginning entry, Butler's Gin, undated. p.1-134. Includes the following sites
                     in Marengo, Baldwin, Pickens, Greene, and Sumter counties, Alabama; Washington,
                     Santa Rosa, and Walton counties, Florida; and Pickens and Lowndes counties,
                     Mississippi:</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <list type="simple">
                        <item>
                           <emph render="italic">Alabama: </emph>Bear Point, Birkley's Landing,
                           Blubber Creek, Bryan's Barn, Goose Pond, Kirkpatrick's Landing, Moscon,
                           Simmon's Landing, Spragin's Mill, Sucarnoochee Creek, Summerville. </item>
                        <item>
                           <emph render="italic">Florida: </emph>Basin Bayou, Black Creek, Camp
                           Walton, Choctawhatchee Bay, Don's Bayou, Freeport, Graveyard Point, Jolly
                           B, Maesta Creek, Point Washington. </item>
                        <item>
                           <emph render="italic">Mississippi: </emph>Butler's Gin, Chowder Spring,
                           Columbus, Crawford, Wyndham Landing.</item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 3</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 19</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1901</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Large notebook. 251p. Tombigbee River, Mississippi and Alabama. Includes sites
                     in Lowndes, Pickens, Greene, Sumter, Marengo, Baldwin, Santa Rosa, Walton, and
                     Washington counties. Pages of possible site locations, through p.10. Beginning
                     entry, mound at Butler's Gin, undated. p.22-126. Correspondence attached
                     p.252-253. Includes journal entries January 16, 1901- April 25, 1901,
                     p.232-251. </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 3</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 20</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1902</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Large notebook. 299p. Northwest coast of Florida. Includes sites in Franklin,
                     Cahoun, Washington, Lafayette, Levy, Wakulla, and Taylor counties. Pages of
                     possible site locations through p.2. Beginning entry, Cool Spring Mound,
                     undated. p.8- 230. Enclosures. Includes journal entries January 14, 1902-May
                     13, 1902, p.276-299. </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 3</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 21</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1902</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Small notebook. 110p. Entries p.1-110. Northwest coast of Florida. Includes the
                     following sites in Franklin, Wakulla, Taylor, Lafayette, and Levy counties:
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <list type="simple">
                        <item>Aucilla River, Econfenne River, Goodson's Fish Camp, Horseshoe Point,
                           Mound Field, Murphy's Landing, Nichols Mound, Ocklockonee Bay, Pine Key,
                           Shell Heap, Spring Creek, Steinhatchee River, Warrior River, Yent
                           Mound.</item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 3</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 22</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1902</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Small notebook. 176p. Apalachicola River, northwest Florida. Beginning entry,
                     Cool Spring Mound, undated. p.1-176. Includes the following sites in Franklin,
                     Bay, and Calhoun counties: </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <list type="simple">
                        <item>Alligator Bayon, Anderson's Bayou, Apalachiocola, Baker's Landing,
                           Bear Point, Burnt Mill Creek, Carabelle R. Mound, Cool Springs Mound,
                           Davis Point, Eleven-mile Point, Gotier Hammock, Green's Point, Hare
                           Hammock, Holley Mound, Huckleberry Landing, Indian Pass Point, Jackson
                           Mound, Laughton's Bayou, Magnolia Cemetry, Pearl Bayou, Pierce Mound,
                           Singer Mound, Sowell Mound, Strange's Landing, Tucker Mound.</item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 3</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 23</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1903</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Small notebook. 146p. Suwannee River, Apalachicola River, and Gulf Coast,
                     Florida. Entries begin with mound near the Brickyard. p.1-146. Includes the
                     following sites in Levy, Lafayette, Liberty, Calhoun, Gadsden, Jackson,
                     Hernando, Pasco, Hillsboro, and Citrus counties: </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <list type="simple">
                        <item>
                           <emph render="italic">Suwanee River: </emph> Fannings, Fayettesville,
                           Fowler's Landing, Jenning's Landing, Rocky Landing. </item>
                        <item>
                           <emph render="italic">Chipola River: </emph> Burgess Center, Chipola
                           Cut-off, Isabel Landing. <emph render="italic">Apalchicola River: </emph>
                           Aspalga, Atkins Landing, Blountstown, Brickyard Center, Bristol,
                           Chattahoochee Landing, Davis Field, Estiffanulga, Sampson's Landing, Yon
                           Mound. </item>
                        <item>
                           <emph render="italic">Gulf Coast: </emph> Bayport, Bear Landing, Cedar
                           Keys, Chassahowitzka River, Clear Water, Crystal River, Dry Creek, Gigger
                           Point, Hog Island, Indian Bend, Indian Creek, John's Pass, Long Key,
                           Pichlochascootie River, Rock Island, Wekiwachee River. </item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 3</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 24</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1903</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Large notebook. 300p. Suwannee River and Apalachicola Rivers, Florida. Includes
                     sites in Franklin, Calhoun, Liberty, Gadsden, Jackson, Lafayette, Levy,
                     Hillsboro, Citrus, Hernando, and Pasco counties. Notes and listing of possible
                     sites through p.3. Entries begin with mound on Brickyard Creek. p.11-132.
                     Includes journal entries January 13, 1903-April 18, 1903. p.281- 300. </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 4</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 25</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1904-1906</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Large notebook. 300p. Florida, Mississippi, Alabama. Includes sites in Hale,
                     Greene, Tuscaloosa, Clark, Washington, Choctaw, Marengo, Baldwin, and Mobile
                     counties, Alabama; Jackson county, Mississippi; and Osceola, DeSoto, and Lee
                     counties, Florida. Entries begin with Lauier mound. p.9-199. Includes journal
                     entries, January 11, 1904-April 21, 1904; December 29, 1904-April 25, 1905;
                     January 25, 1906-April 18, 1906. p.249-300. </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 4</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 26</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1905</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Small notebook. 181p. Lake Tohopekaliga, and Charlotte Harbor, Florida; Mobile
                     Bay, Alabama; Mississippi Sound, Mississippi; Lower Tombigbee, Alabama. Entries
                     begin January 11, 1905. p.1-181. Includes the following sites in Osceola and
                     Lee counties, Florida; Baldwin, Choctaw, Marengo, Hale, Greene, Tuscaloosa,
                     Clark, and Washington counties, Alabama; and Jackson and Harrison counties,
                     Mississippi: </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <list type="simple">
                        <item>
                           <emph render="italic">Lake Tohopekaliga and Charlotte Harbor: </emph>
                           Brown's Landing, Frier Cove, Kissimmee, Lanier Mound, Lee's Landing,
                           McCool's Landing, Pine Island, Punta Rassa, St. Elmo Landing. </item>
                        <item>
                           <emph render="italic">Mobile Bay and Simpson Island: </emph> Blakeley's,
                           Bon Secours River, Bottle Creek, Fish River, Seymour Bluff, Starke's
                           Wharf, Strong's Bayou. </item>
                        <item>
                           <emph render="italic">Lower Tombigbee: </emph> Baska Creek, Bass Landing,
                           Beaver's Creek, Breckenridge Landing, Carney's Bluff, Cox Landing,
                           Cut-off, Gaines Landing, Hook's Plantation, Horse Creek, Jackson's
                           Landing, Kimbell's Field, Malone's Gin, Payne's Woodyard, Peavey's
                           Landing, Powe's Landing, Rembert, Santa Bogue, Steiner's Landing, Three
                           River Landing, Walter's Plant. </item>
                        <item>
                           <emph render="italic">Black Warrior: </emph> Arcola, Bohannon's Landing,
                           Calvin's Landing, Candy's Landing, Lock No.7, McAlpin's Woodyard,
                           Moundville, Stephen's Bluff. </item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 4</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 27</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1905</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>. Small notebook. 77p. Flint River, Chattahoochee River, and Moundville.
                     Entries p.1-77. Includes the following sites in Decatur, Clay, and Quitmon
                     counties, Georgia; Jackson county, Florida, and Early, Houston, Henry, and
                     Russell counties, Alabama: </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <list type="simple">
                        <item>
                           <emph render="italic">Flint River: </emph> Kerr's Landing, Log Landing,
                           Munnerlyn's Landing. </item>
                        <item>
                           <emph render="italic">Chattahoochee River: </emph> Abercrombie Landing,
                           Columbia, Fort Gaines, Fullmore's Upper Landing, Georgetown, Hare's
                           Landing, Kemp's Landing Old Rambo Landing Purcell's Landing, Shoemaker
                           Landing, Starke's Clay Landing, Steammill Landing. </item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 4</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 28</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1906</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Small notebook. 88p. Moundville Revisited. Crystal River. Entries begin with
                     Crystal River revisited. p.1-88. </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 4</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 29</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1905-1906</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Large Notebook. 252p. Chattahoochee River and Flint River. Includes sites in
                     Jackson county, Florida; Decatur, Early, Clay, Quitman, Chattahoochee, Russell,
                     and Muscogee counties, Georgia; and Houston, Henry, and Barbour counties,
                     Alabama. Entries begin with mound near Kerr's Landing. p.5-62. Includes journal
                     entries November 7, 1905-December 10, 1905, p.246-252. </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel4</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 30</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1907-1908</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Large notebook. 198p. Yazoo, Sunflower, and Arkansas Rivers. Includes sites in
                     Washington, Warren, Issaquenna, Sharkey, Yazoo, Holmes, and Leflore counties,
                     Mississippi; and Arkansas, Jefferson, and Lincoln counties, Arkansas. Entries
                     begin with Blum mounds. p.1-112. Includes journal entries January 13,
                     1907-April 19, 1908, p.146-198. </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 4</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 31</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1908-1909</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Large notebook. 198p. Ouachita Valley, Little River, Bayou Bartholomew.
                     Includes sites in Catahoula, Caldwell, Ouachita, Grant, Franklin, and Morehouse
                     parishes, Louisiana; and Ashley, Bradley, Union, and Calhoun counties,
                     Arkansas. Entries begin November 18, 1908. p.7-165. Includes journal entries
                     November 6, 1908-April 26, 1909, p.171-198. </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 4</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 32</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1908</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Small notebook. 163p. Mississippi and Arkansas. Entries begin with Blum Mounds.
                     p.1-163. Includes the following sites in Sharkey, Yazoo, Holmes, Washington,
                     Leflore, Issaquenna, and Warren counties, Mississippi; Arkansas, Lincoln, and
                     Jefferson counties, Arkansas: </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <list type="simple">
                        <item>
                           <emph render="italic">Sunflower River: </emph> Anderson Landing, Bachelor
                           Retreat, Blum Mounds, Fairview Landing, Fairview Plantation, George Lake,
                           Spanish Fort Landing, Stalonia Landing, Wrong-end-up Landing. </item>
                        <item>
                           <emph render="italic">Yazoo River: </emph> Belzona, Carey Middleton Gin
                           Landing, Caruthers Landing, Clark's Ferry, Fort Place, Hayne's Bluff,
                           Honey Island, King's Crossing, Koalunsa, Leist Landing, Monterey,
                           O'Neill's Landing, Parker's Bayou, Silent Shade Landing, Stella, Tchula
                           Lake, Wasp Lake, Welsh Camp Landing, Yalobusha River. </item>
                        <item>
                           <emph render="italic">Arkansas River: </emph> Douglas, Greer, Menard
                           Mounds, Old River Landing, Sawyer's Landing. </item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 4</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 33</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1909-1910</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Small notebook. 151p. White River, Black River, and St. Francis River,
                     Arkansas. Entries begin with mound near Mt. Adams. p.1-151. Includes the
                     following sites in Prairie, Arkansas, White, Woodruff, Jackson, Lawrence,
                     Randolph, Lee, St. Francis, Independence, Cross, and Poinsett counties: </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <list type="simple">
                        <item>
                           <emph render="italic">White River: </emph> Atkinson Ferry, Chandler
                           Landing, Hames Place, King's Landing, Lindsay's Point, Mt. Adams, Negro
                           Hill, Taylor's Bayou, Teague Mound. </item>
                        <item>
                           <emph render="italic">Black River: </emph> Clover Bend, Cornpen Landing,
                           Elgin, Harter Knoll, Lauratown, Lindley Landing, Little Turkey Hill,
                           Mitchell's Log Camp Landing, Perkins Field, Tucker Bay, Upper Hovey
                           Place. </item>
                        <item>
                           <emph render="italic">St. Francis River: </emph> Bay Ferry, Big Eddy,
                           Castile Place, Catfish Mounds, Cummings Place, Forrest Place, Fortune
                           Mounds, Miller Place, Neeley's Ferry, Parkin's, Potter Place, Rose Mound,
                           Stott Place, Togo, Turkey Island, Turnbow Place, Whitehall Place. </item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 5</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 34</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1910-1911</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>. Small notebook. 134p. Mississippi River. Entries begin November 10, 1910,
                     p.1-134. Includes the following sites in Mississippi, Crittenden, Lee, Tunica,
                     Phillye's, Bolivar, Desha, Washington, and Warren counties; and Concordia and
                     Pointe Coupee parishes: </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <list type="simple">
                        <item>
                           <emph render="italic">Middle Mississippi Valley: </emph> Avenue, Bradley,
                           Commerce, Kent Place, Mount Place, Pecan Point, Rhodes, Stoffle Place. </item>
                        <item>
                           <emph render="italic">Lower Mississippi Valley: </emph> Glass, Glendale,
                           Nebletts, Oak Bend, Richland, Shadyside Landing, Shaw Fields. </item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 5</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 35</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1909-1910</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>. Large notebook. 200p. St. Frances River, White River, Black River, Arkansas.
                     Includes sites in Lee, St. Francis, Poinsett, Monroe, Arkansas, Prairie, White,
                     Woodruff, Jackson, Independence, Lawrence, and Randolph counties. Enclosure
                     lists counties in Alabama, Florida, and Mississippi. Entries begin with White
                     River. p.7-133. Includes journal entries November 9, 1909-April 25, 1910,
                     p.178-200. </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 5</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 36</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1910-1911</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">3</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Large notebook. 200p. Mississippi River Valley, Lower Mississippi, Red River.
                     Includes sites in Phillips, Lee, Crittenden, Mississippi, and Desha counties,
                     Arkansas; Tunica, Adams, Bolevar, and Washington counties, Mississippi; and
                     Pointe Coupee and Avoyelles parishes, Louisiana. Entries begin March 21, 1911.
                     p.7-127. Includes journal entries November 7, 1910- April 24, 1911, p.177-200.
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 5</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 37</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1911-1912</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">3</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Large notebook. 200p. Red River, Arkansas and Louisiana. Includes sites in
                     Miller, Lafayette, Hempstead, and Bowie counties, Arkansas; Pointe Coupee,
                     Avoyelles, Rapides, Grant, Red River, Bossier, and Caddo parishes, Louisiana.
                     Entries begin with notes. p.7-174. Includes journal entries November 6,
                     1911-April 26, 1912, p.177-200. </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 5</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 38</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1911-1912</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">3</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Small notebook. 179p. Red River. Entries begin with Keller Place. p.1-118.
                     Sketch on p.179. Includes the following sites in Pointe Coupee, Avoyelle,
                     Rapides, Grant, Red River, and Bossier parishes, Louisiana; and Miller,
                     Lafayette, and Hempsted counties, Arkansas: </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <list type="simple">
                        <item>
                           <emph render="italic">Red River: </emph> Battle's, Briar Bend, Byram
                           Ferry, Crenshaw, Diggs Bluff, Dooley Ferry, Dunn's, Fosters, Fridays,
                           Gahagan, Haley's, Haynes, Johnson's, Keller Place, L'Eau Noire Bayou,
                           Lacroix, Mayer's, McClure's Place, Moore's, Norman Landing, Saline Point,
                           Sulphur River, Taylortown, Thompson's. </item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 5</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 39</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1912-1913</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">3</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Small notebook. 180p. Ouachita Valley, Louisiana and Saline River, Arkansas.
                     Entries begin with Pritchard's Landing. p.1-85; p.180 has continuation.
                     Includes the following sites in Catahoula, Tensas, West Carroll, East,
                     Franklin, Madison, and Louisiana parishes; and Bradley county, Arkansas: </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <list type="simple">
                        <item>
                           <emph render="italic">Ouachita Valley: </emph> Alphenia Place, Crowfoot
                           Place, Dean Lake, Flynn's Place, Hope Landing, Insley Place, Jackson's
                           Place, Lake Place, Lower Jackson Place, Montgomery, Motley Place, Mott
                           Place, Poverty Point, Pritchard's Landing, Richardson Place, Stevens,
                           Turkey Point Landing. </item>
                        <item>
                           <emph render="italic">Saline River: </emph> Brooks Landing, Godfrey
                           Landing, Goulett Island, Hampton landing, Lowrie Landing, Moore's Mill,
                           Wherry's Landing, Wire Fence Landing. </item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 5</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 40</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1912-1913</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">3</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Large notebook. 200p. Saline River, Arkansas; Bayou d'Arbonne, Atchafalaya
                     River, and Tensas River, Louisiana. Includes sites in Ashley and Bradley
                     counties, Arkansas; and Union, Assumption, Ibeia, Iberville, St. Landry,
                     Concordia, Catahoula, Tensa, Madison, Franklin, East Carroll, and West Carroll
                     parishes, Louisiana. Entries begin with Goulett Island. p.9-158. Includes
                     journal entries November 9, 1912-April 23, 1913, p.174-200. </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 5</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 41</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1913-1914</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">3</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Large notebook. 298p. Tennessee River, Eastern Tennessee, Mississippi and
                     Alabama. Includes sites in Hamilton, James, Meigs, Rhea, Roane, Loudon, Blount,
                     Knox, Livingston, Lyon, Marshall, Stewart, Henry, Benton, Humphrey, Decatur,
                     Wayne, and Hardin counties, Tennessee; Tishomingo county, Mississippi; and
                     Lauderdale and Colbert counties, Alabama. Tennessee River entries p.7-238.
                     Includes journal entries November 3, 1913-April 29, 1914, p.268-298. </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 6</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 42</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1914</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">3</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Small notebook. 101p. Entries p.1-101. Includes the following sites in Rhea,
                     Meigs, Loudon, Blount, Knox, Roane, Stewart, Henry, Benton, Wayne, Hardin,
                     Harniston, Hamilton, and James counties, Tennessee; and Marshall county,
                     Kentucky: </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <list type="simple">
                        <item>
                           <emph render="italic">Tennessee River: </emph> Arthur Place, Barrett's
                           Ferry, Beech Creek, Bess Place, Citico Mound, Cooks Landing, Dickey
                           Place, Eldridge Place, Evan's Place, Gray's Place, Henson, Hiwassee
                           Island, Hodds Ferry, Hoyal Ferry, Huffine Ferry, Igou Ferry, Jackson
                           Place, Johnson Creek, Jones Place, Koger Island, Little River Shoals,
                           Lovelady Landing, North Carolina Landing, Perkins Bluff, Shipps Landing,
                           Sykes Place, Thompson, Wolf Island. </item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 6</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 43</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1914-1915</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">3</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Large notebook. 300p. Tennessee River. Includes sites in Stewart, Humphreys,
                     Benton, Marion, and Hamilton counties, Tennessee; and Decatur, Lauderdale,
                     Colbert, Lawrence, Limestone, Morgan, Alabama, Marshall, and Jackson counties,
                     Alabama. Notes p.7. Entries p.9-273. Includes journal entries November 4,
                     1914-April 28, 1915, p.275-300. </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 6</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 44</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1914-1915</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">3</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Small notebook. 148p. Citico revisited, Tennessee. Includes Citico mound and
                     Williams Landing, Hamilton County, Tennessee. Index, p.1. Entries p.3-148. </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 6</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Notebook # 45</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1915-1918</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">3</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Large notebook. 300p. Ohio River, Green River, Mississippi River. Includes
                     sites in Ballard, Livingston, Henderson, McLean, Ohio, Butler, Edmonson.
                     Fulton, and Hickman counties, Kentucky; Massac and Pope counties, Illinois;
                     Posey county, Indiana; Lauderdale county, Tennessee; New Madrid and Mississippi
                     counties, Missouri. Notes, p.7. Entries p.9-208. Includes journal entries
                     November 4, 1915-April 26, 1916; November 8, 1916-April 23, 1917; September 25,
                     1917- April 26, 1918, p.218-300. </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 6</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle id="s2">Series II. Other Material</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Printed guide and Catalogue</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <container type="box">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p><?xm-replace_text {p}??></p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Unnumbered notebook. </emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1891</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">3</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>Contains Cruise of the Osceola, p.1-77. Entries from January 21-February 23,
                     1891. Cruise of the Alligator. Entries from March 5-April 7, 1891, p.79-99.
                     Journal entries describe boat trips in Florida investigating potential
                     archaeological sites. </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 6</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Dictionary of Archaeological Terms. </emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <container type="box">3</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>240p. Includes alphabetical index of archaeological terms, with page
                     references. p.3-91. Terms are then defined. Includes bibliographic citations.
                     p.108-126. Notes on various books, p.224-240 </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 6</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Correspondence.</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1899</unitdate>
                  <container type="box">3</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>1899 correspondence from George W. Rossignol to Clarence B. Moore. Often
                     addressed to Dr. M.G. Miller. About a proposed expedition to the Coosa River in
                     Alabama and Georgia. May 17, 1899-August 1, 1899. Undated letters at end. </p>
               </scopecontent>
               <scopecontent>
                  <p>
                     <emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 6</emph>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle id="s3">Series III. Guide to Notebooks by Year</unittitle>
            </did>
            <scopecontent audience="external">
               <p>
                  <list type="deflist">
                     <defitem>
                        <label>
                           <emph render="bold">Notebook # - - - - - </emph>
                        </label>
                        <item>
                           <emph render="bold"> Years Covered</emph>
                        </item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label> 1</label>
                        <item>1891</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>2</label>
                        <item>1892</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label> 3</label>
                        <item>1892</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>4</label>
                        <item>1892-1893</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>5</label>
                        <item>1893-1894</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>6</label>
                        <item>1893-1894</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>7</label>
                        <item>1894</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>8</label>
                        <item>1894-1895</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>9</label>
                        <item>1894-1895</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>10</label>
                        <item>1895-1896</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>11</label>
                        <item>1896-1897</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>12</label>
                        <item>1896-1897</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>13</label>
                        <item>1897-1898</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>14</label>
                        <item>1897-1898</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>15</label>
                        <item>1899</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>16</label>
                        <item>1899</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>17</label>
                        <item>1900</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>18</label>
                        <item>1901</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>19</label>
                        <item>1901</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>20</label>
                        <item>1902</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>21</label>
                        <item>1902</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>22</label>
                        <item>1902</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>23</label>
                        <item>1903</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>24</label>
                        <item>1903</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>25</label>
                        <item>1904-1906</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>26</label>
                        <item>1905</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>27</label>
                        <item>1905</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>28</label>
                        <item>1906</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>29</label>
                        <item>1905-1906</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>30</label>
                        <item>1907-1908</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>31</label>
                        <item>1908-1909</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>32</label>
                        <item>1907-1908</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>33</label>
                        <item>1909-1910</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>34</label>
                        <item>1910-1911</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>35</label>
                        <item>1909-1910</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>36</label>
                        <item>1910-1911</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>37</label>
                        <item>1911-1912</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>38</label>
                        <item>1911-1912</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>39</label>
                        <item>1912-1913</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>40</label>
                        <item>1912-1913</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>41</label>
                        <item>1913-1914</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>42</label>
                        <item>1914</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>43</label>
                        <item>1914-1915</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>44</label>
                        <item>1914-1915</item>
                     </defitem>
                     <defitem>
                        <label>45</label>
                        <item>1915-1918</item>
                     </defitem>
                  </list>
               </p>
            </scopecontent>
         </c01>
         <c01 level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle id="s4">Series IV. Guide to Notebooks by Location</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Alabama</emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent audience="external">
                  <p>
                     <list type="deflist">
                        <defitem>
                           <label>
                              <emph render="bold">County - - - - - </emph>
                           </label>
                           <item>
                              <emph render="bold"> Notebook #</emph>
                           </item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Baldwin</label>
                           <item>18, 25, 26</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Barbour</label>
                           <item>29</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Choctaw</label>
                           <item>25, 26</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Clark</label>
                           <item>25, 26</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Colbert</label>
                           <item>43</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Dallas</label>
                           <item>15, 16</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Decatur</label>
                           <item>43</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Elmore</label>
                           <item>15, 16</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Greene</label>
                           <item>18, 19, 25, 26</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Hale</label>
                           <item>25, 26, 28, 29</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Henry</label>
                           <item>27, 29</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Houston</label>
                           <item>27, 29</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Jackson</label>
                           <item>43</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Lauderdale</label>
                           <item>43</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Lawrence</label>
                           <item>43</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Limestone</label>
                           <item>43</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Madison</label>
                           <item>43</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Marengo</label>
                           <item>18, 19, 25, 26</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Marshall</label>
                           <item>43</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Mobile</label>
                           <item>15, 16</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Monroe</label>
                           <item>15, 16</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Montgomery</label>
                           <item>15, 16</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Morgan</label>
                           <item>43</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Pickens</label>
                           <item>18, 19</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Russell</label>
                           <item>27</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Sumter</label>
                           <item>18, 19</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Tuscaloosa</label>
                           <item>25, 26</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Washington</label>
                           <item>25, 36</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Wilcox</label>
                           <item>15, 16</item>
                        </defitem>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Arkansas</emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent audience="external">
                  <p>
                     <list type="deflist">
                        <defitem>
                           <label>
                              <emph render="bold">County - - - - - </emph>
                           </label>
                           <item>
                              <emph render="bold"> Notebook #</emph>
                           </item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Arkansas</label>
                           <item>30, 32, 33, 35</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Ashley</label>
                           <item>31, 40</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Bowie</label>
                           <item>37</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Bradley</label>
                           <item>31, 39, 40</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Calhoun</label>
                           <item>31</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Crittenden</label>
                           <item>34, 36</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Cross</label>
                           <item>33, 35</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Desha</label>
                           <item>34, 36</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Hempstead</label>
                           <item>37, 38</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Independence</label>
                           <item>33, 35</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Jackson</label>
                           <item>33, 35</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Jefferson</label>
                           <item>30, 32</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Lafayette</label>
                           <item>37, 38</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Lawrence</label>
                           <item>33, 35</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Lee</label>
                           <item>33, 34, 35, 36</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Lincoln</label>
                           <item>30, 32</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Miller</label>
                           <item>37, 38</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Mississippi</label>
                           <item>34, 36</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Monroe</label>
                           <item>35</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Phillips</label>
                           <item>34, 36</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Poinsett</label>
                           <item>33, 35</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Prairie</label>
                           <item>33, 35</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Randolph</label>
                           <item>33, 35</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>St. Francis</label>
                           <item>33, 35</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Union</label>
                           <item>31</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Washington</label>
                           <item>34</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>White</label>
                           <item>33, 35</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Woodruff</label>
                           <item>33, 35</item>
                        </defitem>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Florida</emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent audience="external">
                  <p>
                     <list type="deflist">
                        <defitem>
                           <label>
                              <emph render="bold">County - - - - - </emph>
                           </label>
                           <item>
                              <emph render="bold"> Notebook #</emph>
                           </item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Baldwin</label>
                           <item>19</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Bay</label>
                           <item>22</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Brevard</label>
                           <item>1, 2, 3</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Calhoun</label>
                           <item>20, 22, 23, 24</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Citrus</label>
                           <item>21, 324</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Clay</label>
                           <item>5, 6</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Duval</label>
                           <item>5, 6, 8, 9</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Franklin</label>
                           <item>20, 21, 22, 23, 24</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Gadsden</label>
                           <item>23, 24</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Hernando</label>
                           <item>23, 24</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Hillsboro</label>
                           <item>17, 23, 24</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Jackson</label>
                           <item>23, 24, 27, 29</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Lafayette</label>
                           <item>20, 21, 23, 24</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Lake</label>
                           <item>1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Lee</label>
                           <item>17, 26</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Levy</label>
                           <item>20, 21, 23, 24</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Liberty</label>
                           <item>23, 24</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Manatee</label>
                           <item>17</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Marion</label>
                           <item>6, 8, 9</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Monroe</label>
                           <item>17</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Orange</label>
                           <item>1, 2, 3, 4, 6, 7</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Osceola</label>
                           <item>26</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Pasco</label>
                           <item>23, 24</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Putnam</label>
                           <item>1, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>St. Johns</label>
                           <item>5, 6</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Santa Rosa</label>
                           <item>18, 19</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Taylor</label>
                           <item>20, 21</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Volusia</label>
                           <item>1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Wakulla</label>
                           <item>20, 21</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Walton</label>
                           <item>18, 19</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Washington</label>
                           <item>18, 19, 20, 22</item>
                        </defitem>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Georgia</emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent audience="external">
                  <p>
                     <list type="deflist">
                        <defitem>
                           <label>
                              <emph render="bold">County - - - - - </emph>
                           </label>
                           <item>
                              <emph render="bold"> Notebook #</emph>
                           </item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Appling</label>
                           <item>13, 14</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Belleville</label>
                           <item>12</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Bryan</label>
                           <item>11, 12</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Camden</label>
                           <item>10</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Chatham</label>
                           <item>12, 13, 14</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Chattahochee</label>
                           <item>29</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Clay</label>
                           <item>27, 29</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Decautur</label>
                           <item>27, 29</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Early</label>
                           <item>27, 29</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Liberty</label>
                           <item>11, 12, 13, 14</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>McIntosh</label>
                           <item>10, 11, 12</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Muscogee</label>
                           <item>29</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Quitman</label>
                           <item>27, 29</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Russell</label>
                           <item>29</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Screven</label>
                           <item>13, 14</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Stewart</label>
                           <item>29</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Tattnall</label>
                           <item>13, 14</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Wayne</label>
                           <item>13, 14</item>
                        </defitem>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Illinois</emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent audience="external">
                  <p>
                     <list type="deflist">
                        <defitem>
                           <label>
                              <emph render="bold">County - - - - - </emph>
                           </label>
                           <item>
                              <emph render="bold"> Notebook #</emph>
                           </item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Massac</label>
                           <item>45</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Pope</label>
                           <item>45</item>
                        </defitem>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Indiana</emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent audience="external">
                  <p>
                     <list type="deflist">
                        <defitem>
                           <label>
                              <emph render="bold">County - - - - - </emph>
                           </label>
                           <item>
                              <emph render="bold"> Notebook #</emph>
                           </item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Posey</label>
                           <item>45</item>
                        </defitem>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Kentucky</emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent audience="external">
                  <p>
                     <list type="deflist">
                        <defitem>
                           <label>
                              <emph render="bold">County - - - - - </emph>
                           </label>
                           <item>
                              <emph render="bold"> Notebook #</emph>
                           </item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Ballard</label>
                           <item>45</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Butler</label>
                           <item>45</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Edmonson</label>
                           <item>45</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Fulton</label>
                           <item>45</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Henderson</label>
                           <item>45</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Hickman</label>
                           <item>45</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Livingston</label>
                           <item>45</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>McLean</label>
                           <item>45</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Marshall</label>
                           <item>42</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Ohio</label>
                           <item>45</item>
                        </defitem>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Louisiana</emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent audience="external">
                  <p>
                     <list type="deflist">
                        <defitem>
                           <label>
                              <emph render="bold">Parish - - - - - </emph>
                           </label>
                           <item>
                              <emph render="bold"> Notebook #</emph>
                           </item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Assumption</label>
                           <item>40</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Avoyelles</label>
                           <item>36, 37, 38</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Bossier</label>
                           <item>37, 38</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Caddo</label>
                           <item>37, 38</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Caldwell</label>
                           <item>31</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Catahoula</label>
                           <item>31, 39, 40</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Concordia</label>
                           <item>34, 36, 40</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>East Carroll</label>
                           <item>39, 40</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Franklin</label>
                           <item>31, 39, 40</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Grant</label>
                           <item>31, 37, 38</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Iberia</label>
                           <item>40</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Iberville</label>
                           <item>40</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Madison</label>
                           <item>39, 40</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Morehouse</label>
                           <item>31</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Ouachita</label>
                           <item>31</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Pointe Coupee</label>
                           <item>34, 36, 37, 38</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Rapides</label>
                           <item>37, 38</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Red River</label>
                           <item>38</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>St. Landry</label>
                           <item>40</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Tensas</label>
                           <item>39, 40</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>West Carroll</label>
                           <item>39, 40</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>West Feliciana</label>
                           <item>36</item>
                        </defitem>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Mississippi</emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent audience="external">
                  <p>
                     <list type="deflist">
                        <defitem>
                           <label>
                              <emph render="bold">County - - - - - </emph>
                           </label>
                           <item>
                              <emph render="bold"> Notebook #</emph>
                           </item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Adams</label>
                           <item>36</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Bolivar</label>
                           <item>34, 36</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Harrison</label>
                           <item>26</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Holmes</label>
                           <item>30</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Issaquena</label>
                           <item>30</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Jackson</label>
                           <item>26</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Leflore</label>
                           <item>30</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Lowndes</label>
                           <item>18, 19</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Pickens</label>
                           <item>18</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Sharkey</label>
                           <item>30, 32</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Tunica</label>
                           <item>34, 36</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Warren</label>
                           <item>30, 34, 36</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Washington</label>
                           <item>30, 32, 36</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Yazoo</label>
                           <item>30, 32</item>
                        </defitem>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Missouri</emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent audience="external">
                  <p>
                     <list type="deflist">
                        <defitem>
                           <label>
                              <emph render="bold">County - - - - - </emph>
                           </label>
                           <item>
                              <emph render="bold"> Notebook #</emph>
                           </item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Mississippi</label>
                           <item>45</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>New Madrid</label>
                           <item>35</item>
                        </defitem>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">South Carolina</emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent audience="external">
                  <p>
                     <list type="deflist">
                        <defitem>
                           <label>
                              <emph render="bold">County - - - - - </emph>
                           </label>
                           <item>
                              <emph render="bold"> Notebook #</emph>
                           </item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Barnwell</label>
                           <item>13, 14</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Beaufort</label>
                           <item>13, 14</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Burke</label>
                           <item>13</item>
                        </defitem>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02>
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Tennessee</emph>
                  </unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent audience="external">
                  <p>
                     <list type="deflist">
                        <defitem>
                           <label>
                              <emph render="bold">County - - - - - </emph>
                           </label>
                           <item>
                              <emph render="bold"> Notebook #</emph>
                           </item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Benton</label>
                           <item>42, 43</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Blount</label>
                           <item>41, 42</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Dyer</label>
                           <item>45</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Hamilton</label>
                           <item>41, 42, 43, 44</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Hardin</label>
                           <item>42</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Henry</label>
                           <item>42</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Humphreys</label>
                           <item>43</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>James</label>
                           <item>41, 42</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Knox</label>
                           <item>41, 42</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Lauderdale</label>
                           <item>45</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Loudon</label>
                           <item>41, 42</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Marion</label>
                           <item>43</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Meig</label>
                           <item>41, 42</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Rhea</label>
                           <item>41, 42</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Roane</label>
                           <item>41, 42</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Stewart</label>
                           <item>42, 43</item>
                        </defitem>
                        <defitem>
                           <label>Wayne</label>
                           <item>42</item>
                        </defitem>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
