<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<!-- Transformed with v1v2002_4_cornell.xsl -->

<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../dtds/ead.dtd">
	 
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../styles/style.xsl" ?>
<ead>
   <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1" scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
      <eadid mainagencycode="nic" countrycode="us" publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections//TEXT(US::NIC::RMM06033::First Baptist Church of Palmyra records)//EN">RMM06033.xml</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the First Baptist Church of Palmyra records,1835-1865.</titleproper>
            <titleproper type="sort">First Baptist Church of Palmyra records,1835-1865</titleproper>
            <author>Compiled by K.H.</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library</publisher>
            <date>June 2004</date>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note audience="internal">
               <p> 
				
                  <subject>relig</subject>
                  <subject>church</subject>
                  <subject>rghis</subject>
			 
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>Finding aid encoded by Andrea Hektor, <date>June 2004</date>
         </creation>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change encodinganalog="583">
            <date normal="2007-05-29">2007-05-29</date>
            <item>converted from EAD 1.0 to EAD 2002 </item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <frontmatter>
      <titlepage>
         <titleproper>Guide to the First Baptist Church Of Palmyra Records,<lb/>1835-1865.</titleproper>
         <num>Collection Number: 6033</num>
         <publisher>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections <lb/>Cornell University Library</publisher>
         <list type="deflist">
            <defitem>
               <label>Contact Information:</label>
               <item>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections<lb/>
2B Carl A. Kroch Library<lb/>
Cornell University<lb/>
Ithaca, NY 14853<lb/>
(607) 255-3530<lb/>
Fax: (607) 255-9524<lb/>
<extref href="mailto:rareref@cornell.edu">rareref@cornell.edu</extref>
                  <lb/>
<extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu">http://rmc.library.cornell.edu</extref>
                  <lb/></item>
            </defitem>
            <defitem>
               <label>Compiled by:</label>
               <item>K.H.</item>
            </defitem>
            <defitem>
               <label>Date completed:</label>
               <item>Dec. 1978<lb/>rev. July 1981</item>
            </defitem>
            <defitem>
               <label>EAD encoding:</label>
               <item>Andrea Hektor, June 2004</item>
            </defitem>
            <defitem> 
               <label>Date modified:</label> 
               <item>Marcie Farwell, February 2015</item> 
            </defitem> 
         </list>
         <date>© 2004 Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library</date>
      </titlepage>
   </frontmatter>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <head id="a1">DESCRIPTIVE SUMMARY</head>
         <unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="MARC 245">First Baptist Church of Palmyra records, 
		  <unitdate type="inclusive" encodinganalog="MARC 245">1835-1865.</unitdate>
		
         </unittitle>
         <unitid label="Collection Number:">6033</unitid>
         <origination label="Creator:"> 
		  
            <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110">First Baptist Church of Palmyra (Palmyra, N.Y.)</corpname>
		
         </origination>
         <physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="MARC 300">1 reel microfilm.</physdesc>
         <physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Microfilm</physdesc>
         <repository label="Repository:">Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library</repository>
         <abstract label="Abstract:">Minutes of monthly covenant meetings, yearly election of trustees, and quarterly financial meetings (1835-1865), discussing church discipline, revival seasons, and church finances, including the construction of a new church.</abstract>
         <langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="041" langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
         <head id="a2" altrender="organization">ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY </head>
         <p>The Baptist societies of Palmyra and Macedon villages (only 4-5 miles apart) held meetings together prior to 1835, but in February of that year they decided to hold separate meetings and to become separate religious societies. After certain financial arrangements, the separation was completed and the records in these volumes begin with a list of the Palmyra members and the statement of a church covenant.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520">
         <head id="a3">COLLECTION DESCRIPTION</head>
         <p>These two volumes contain minutes of monthly covenant meetings, yearly elections of trustees, and quarterly financial meeting minutes. The record begins in February 1835, and the last recorded meeting in the second volume was in November 1869. This Baptist society and church was a member of the Wayne Baptist Association, to which meetings they annually sent delegates.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <head id="a7">SUBJECTS</head>
         <controlaccess>
            <head>Names: </head>
            <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110">First Baptist Church of Palmyra (Palmyra, N.Y.)</corpname>
            <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Wayne Baptist Association.</corpname>
         </controlaccess>
         <controlaccess>
            <head>Subjects:</head>
            <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Church discipline.</subject>
            <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Revivals--New York (State)--Palmyra.</subject>
            <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Baptists--Societies.</subject>
            <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Baptist church buildings.</subject>
            <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Baptists--New York (State)--Palmyra.</subject>
         </controlaccess>
         <controlaccess>
            <head>Places:</head>
            <geogname encodinganalog="MARC 651">Wayne County (N.Y.)--Religious life and customs.</geogname>
            <geogname encodinganalog="MARC 651">Palmyra (N.Y.)--Religious life and customs.</geogname>
         </controlaccess>
         <controlaccess>
            <head>Form and Genre Terms:</head>
            <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="MARC 655">Minutes.</genreform>
         </controlaccess>
      </controlaccess>
      <descgrp type="admininfo">
         <head id="a8">INFORMATION FOR USERS</head>
         <prefercite>
            <head>Cite As:</head>
            <p>First Baptist Church of Palmyra records, #6033. Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library.</p>
         </prefercite>
      </descgrp>
      <dsc type="combined">
         <head>CONTAINER LIST</head>
         <c01 level="item">
            <did>
               <unitid>Item #1</unitid>
               <unittitle>Covenant and articles of faith, 
				<unitdate>January 13, 1833</unitdate>
			 
               </unittitle>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
               <p> January 16th 1833 they vote to adopt the "Whitesborough Resolutions" (with regard to Speculating, Free Masonry, etc.)</p>
               <p> February 1835 they divide into two societies.</p>
            </scopecontent>
         </c01>
         <c01 level="item">
            <did>
               <unitid>Item #2</unitid>
               <unittitle>A minute book, 
				<unitdate>1835-1840</unitdate>
			 
               </unittitle>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
               <p> Contents: This volume contains mostly covenant meeting minutes. The participants discussed religious experiences; admission, dismission and exclusion of members; disciplinary actions and necessary investigative committee reports; financial matters and the election of trustees; and delegates to the other churches for committees. The general procedure for disciplinary problems included a charge brought forth by a church member, a decision as to whether pr not a committee should be appointed to investigate and report, a trial of the accused member if necessary with witnesses and testimony, a final decision, which in several cases ended by "withdrawing the Right hand of fellowship" from the guilty individual.</p>
               <p> Several revivals occurred during the period covered by the first volume of minutes. For example, there was a "protracted meeting" in April 1836 and durin during that entire spring it is noted that "the Lord was evidently with us." There were also periods of lessened membership, sometimes following close behind the revival periods, as in September 1836: "the church appears to be in a cold state..." In December 1837 they note" "Had a reviving season" which may or may not necessarily mean a revival but appears to in this case, since in January 1839 an elder of the church "compared the present state of the church with what is was in January 1838 when we enjoyed a revival." In February 1839 the church bought the present lot on Canandaigua Street and built a brick meeting house. Once again, in April 1839, they "had a reviving time." </p>
            </scopecontent>
         </c01>
         <c01 level="item">
            <did>
               <unitid>Item #3</unitid>
               <unittitle>A minute book, 
				<unitdate>1841-1869</unitdate>
			 
               </unittitle>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
               <p> Contents: In the beginning of this volume is a sheet dated 1857 certifying Reverend Mudge as a gospel minister.</p>
               <p> In January 1841 the new meeting house on Canandaigua Street was dedicated and shortly afterwards there was another revival or "awakening in the church" (January 1841) in which they gained 30 new members.</p>
               <p> In this volume there follows a list of members with the usual categories after their names: Received by Baptism, by Letter, Restored, Dismissed by Letter, Excluded, Died/ Next is the "Articles of Faith."</p>
               <p> There appear to have been more revival seasons in early 1842, and in April of that year 70 new members enter the congregation.</p>
               <p> The disciplinary matters dealt with in the covenant meetings ranged from individual behavior, intemperance, marital probelms, business dealings or stirring up controversy among members. Sometimes the charge was as particular as: "They have borrowed some articles of their Neighbors which were not returned..." (January 1844). Often the crime was of a more dramatic nature, as in this testimony of a former landlady regarding a minister who abused his wife. "Mrs. P. sustained the charges by asserting a continual course of cruelty toward his wife while there; stating that he drove her from his room and causing her to Sleep on the floor, and laying violent hands on her." (September 1853).</p>
               <p> Often the charges are quite vaguely stated: "The first charges was thate A N was guilty of an Incendiary Spirite. Trying to stir up strife, etc." (February 1861).</p>
               <p> The church found itself in considerable debt in early 1861. Toward the end of that decade the situation had obviously improved since they decided to enlarge the building in 1869, by raising $12,000.</p>
               <p> The last entry in this volume is a list labelled "Association minutes from 1867-8" with a list of names and the same categories of baptism, etc. as the previous list.</p>
               <p> This is followed by another list entitled "Names of the Members of the Baptist Church in Palmyra, as they were at the commencement of the Association Year beginning October 1855" and it is the same type of list as before.</p>
               <p> The last entry is a copy of the "Revised Statutes of N.Y." called "An Act to provide for the incorporation of Religious Societies Passed April 5th 1813" and deals with the election, terms, and duties of trustees in the church. </p>
            </scopecontent>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>