<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<!-- Transformed with v1v2002_4_cornell.xsl -->

<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../dtds/ead.dtd">
	 
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../styles/style.xsl" ?>
<ead>
   <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1" scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
      <eadid mainagencycode="nic" countrycode="us" publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections//TEXT(US::NIC::RMM04711::La Forte collection)//EN">RMM04711.xml</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the La Forte collection, 1784-1797</titleproper>
            <titleproper type="sort">La Forte collection, 1784-1797</titleproper>
            <author>Compiled by Jean V. Callahan, Phil McCray</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell

			 University Library</publisher>
            <date>July 2000</date>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>

				
                  <subject>franc</subject>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>EAD encoding by Mireille Lee, July 2000. File last modified: 

		  <date>Dec. 4, 2001</date>
         </creation>
         <langusage> 
            <language>ENG</language> 
         </langusage>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change encodinganalog="583">
            <date normal="2007-05-29">2007-05-29</date>
            <item>converted from EAD 1.0 to EAD 2002 </item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <frontmatter>
      <titlepage>
         <titleproper>Guide to the La Forte collection,

		  <lb/>1784-1797</titleproper>
         <num>Collection Number: 4711</num>
         <publisher>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections <lb/>Cornell

		  University Library</publisher>
         <list type="deflist">
            <defitem>
               <label>Contact Information:</label>
               <item>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections<lb/>
2B Carl A. Kroch Library<lb/>
Cornell University<lb/>
Ithaca, NY 14853<lb/>
(607) 255-3530<lb/>
Fax: (607) 255-9524<lb/>
<extref href="mailto:rareref@cornell.edu">rareref@cornell.edu</extref>
                  <lb/>
<extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu">http://rmc.library.cornell.edu</extref>
                  <lb/></item>
            </defitem>
            <defitem>
               <label>Compiled by:</label>
               <item>Jean V. Callahan, Phil McCray</item>
            </defitem>
            <defitem>
               <label>Date completed:</label>
               <item>January 1996</item>
            </defitem>
            <defitem>
               <label>EAD encoding:</label>
               <item>Mireille Lee, July 2000</item>
            </defitem>
         </list>
         <date>© 2000 Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell

		  University Library</date>
      </titlepage>
   </frontmatter>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <head>DESCRIPTIVE SUMMARY</head>
         <unittitle label="Title:">La Forte collection, <unitdate type="inclusive">1784-1797</unitdate> 
         </unittitle>
         <unitid label="Collection Number:">4711</unitid>
         <origination label="Creator:"> 

		  
            <persname normal="La Forte, Benoist, b. 1761">Benoist La Forte, b.

			 1761</persname> 
         </origination>
         <physdesc label="Quantity:">6.2 cubic ft.</physdesc>
         <physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Letters, receipts, other

		  documents.</physdesc>
         <repository label="Repository:">Division of Rare and Manuscript

		  Collections, Cornell University Library</repository>
         <abstract label="Abstract:">Letters, receipts, and other documents

		  addressed to or received from officials in the <emph render="italic">Régie des

		  poudres et salpêtres</emph> in Paris and the departments and districts of

		  France, and saltpeter manufacturers, chiefly relating to gunpowder production.

		  Other topics covered include Parisian politics, the state of the French

		  economy, the shift to paper currency, and dissatisfaction among the

		  workers.</abstract>
         <langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="041" langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <bioghist>
         <head>BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE</head>
         <p>Benoist La Forte was a government administrator in France's newly

		  nationalized gunpowder industry during the period of the Revolution. Born in

		  Grenoble in 1761, he gave up practicing law in 1784 in order to study the

		  manufacture of gunpowder under the Commission of gunpowder (<emph render="italic">Régie des poudres et salpêtres</emph>), the governmental body

		  which had supplanted the private monopoly in 1775. Beginning in 1786 La Forte

		  held a series of government posts: he served briefly as comptroller for the

		  <emph render="italic">département</emph> of Montpellier, and then as

		  <emph render="italic">commissaire</emph> at Clermont-Ferrand, a post he held

		  through July 1787. In August of that year he was named <emph render="italic">commissaire des poudres et salpêtres</emph> for La Rochelle,

		  remaining there until November 1793, when the <emph render="italic">Régie des

		  poudres</emph> and the <emph render="italic">Comité de Salut Public</emph>

		  appointed him Inspector and then, in <emph render="italic">An</emph> III,

		  Inspector General for Vaucluse and neighboring <emph render="italic">départements</emph>. La Forte's promotion to Inspector

		  occurred around the same time that the <emph render="italic">Régie</emph>,

		  renamed <emph render="italic">l'Agence des poudres et salpêtres</emph>, was

		  undergoing substantial reforms in order to meet the demands of the Revolution

		  and the European war. On December 4, 1793, the National Convention, on the

		  recommendation of the <emph render="italic">Comité de Salut Public</emph>,

		  inaugurated a program of highly regulated de-centralization which required all

		  Frenchmen to participate in the production of gunpowder according to fixed

		  guidelines. The recently-annexed territory that became the

		  <emph render="italic">département</emph> of Vaucluse in 1793, rich in

		  saltpetre and furnished with several functional powder mills, promised to be an

		  especially exploitable area of France, and La Forte, apparently a valued

		  administrator, was named inspector for Vaucluse and given wide-ranging powers,

		  which increased in the following year. La Forte remained Inspector General

		  until May 1797 when, despite the protests of his superiors, he resigned his

		  post.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent>
         <head>COLLECTION DESCRIPTION</head>
         <p>The La Forte Collection contains correspondence, instructional

		  material, technical drawings, financial records and other official documents

		  drawn from the archives of Benoist La Forte, <emph render="italic">commissaire</emph> and then Inspector General for the French

		  Ministry of Gunpowder. The more than 3,000 items in the collection span the

		  period from 1784 to 1797, thus documenting the entirety of La Forte's training

		  and administrative career with the <emph render="italic">Régie des poudres et

		  salpêtres</emph>. There is a small number of printed items, and a good portion

		  of the incoming correspondence appears on paper with French Revolution

		  letterhead. The contents of the collection are arranged into three broad

		  categories: general documents and manuscripts dating from 1784 to 1797;

		  correspondence from 1786 to 1793; and correspondence from 1793 to 1797. There

		  is in addition some earlier correspondence from previous occupants of La

		  Forte's positions. Most of the pieces in the collection date from 1793-1797, a

		  period of rapid reform and expansion in French gunpowder manufacture during

		  which La Forte was Inspector for Vaucluse. Well-known figures whose names

		  appear in the collection include Antoine François de Fourcroy, and noted

		  chemists Antoine Laurent Lavoisier and Jean Antoine Claude Chaptal de

		  Chanteloup.</p>
         <p>Among the more general material there are documents concerning La

		  Forte, such as his letters of appointment, commissions, etc.; a chemistry

		  textbook from 1785 and notes -- from La Forte's years as a student and beyond

		  -- on various aspects of the science and technology of gunpowder manufacture;

		  and a set of instructions, disseminated throughout France, for Inspectors of

		  gunpowder and saltpetre, probably composed by Lavoisier and addressing every

		  aspect of the manufacturing process.</p>
         <p>A detailed record of La Forte's administration is provided by

		  summaries of its operations submitted annually to the <emph render="italic">Régie</emph> for the years 1787 to 1797. These reports gather

		  together correspondence to and from the <emph render="italic">Régie</emph>,

		  financial records, inventories, estimates for new construction, etc.

		  Complementing this archive is a series of annual accounts, many signed by

		  Lavoisier, and receipts from the <emph render="italic">Régie</emph>.</p>
         <p>Chief correspondents include the <emph render="italic">Régie des

		  poudres et salpêtres</emph> at the central office in Paris, headed by

		  Lavoisier and four other <emph render="italic">régisseurs</emph> (the

		  <emph render="italic">Régie</emph> became <emph render="italic">l'Agence des

		  poudres et salpêtres</emph> in 1794); the <emph render="italic">Comité de

		  Salut Public</emph>, for a time the chief executive organ of the revolutionary

		  government; the <emph render="italic">Representants du Peuple</emph>, who were

		  members of the National Assembly; government agents; government-appointed

		  instructors who were often the leading chemists of France; local

		  administrators, writing from all parts of France; and the salt and saltpetre

		  workers (<emph render="italic">saliniers</emph> and <emph render="italic">salpêtriers</emph>) representing the lowest ranks of the

		  gunpowder industry. Many of these functionaries were expedient, transiently

		  powerful creations of the revolutionary government, concerned with shoring up

		  support for the new republic, and enforcing the observation of revolutionary

		  legislation during a time of war.</p>
         <p>Topics covered include: methods of gunpowder manufacture;

		  technological improvements and administrative reform; results of production;

		  stimulating production; accounts; problems procuring raw materials (especially

		  saltpetre and combustibles) and equipment; fixing the price of saltpetre; the

		  construction of factories, refineries and workshops; abuses, such as the

		  clandestine production and private sale of saltpetre; accidents; the effect of

		  the Revolution on industry (including revolutionary surveillance and opposition

		  to revolutionary legislation); Parisian politics; the French economy; the shift

		  to paper currency; workers' salaries; and dissatisfaction among the

		  workers.</p>
         <p>Correspondence from the workers themselves, of which there is a

		  substantial amount, provides information about local administration, conditions

		  in the workshops, the effects of inflation on workers and production, and the

		  various technical and logistical problems encountered from day to day.</p>
         <p>Jean V. Callahan<lb/> January 22, 1996</p>
         <p>(Compiled with the aid of 

		<title>French Books and Manuscripts: 1700-1830, An Exhibition and

		  Description of Collections in Cornell University Library honoring Arthur H. and

		  Mary Marden Dean</title>. Ithaca: Cornell University Library, 1981.)</p>
         <p>The guide to the La Forte Collection was produced with funding

		  provided by the United States Department of Education grant Title II-C,

		  "Strengthening Research Library Resources"; <emph render="italic">The French

		  Revolution Collections at Cornell University: a Retrospective Conversion and

		  Preservation Project</emph>.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <head>SUBJECTS</head>
         <controlaccess>
            <head>Names:</head>
            <persname encodinganalog="MARC 100">La Forte, Benoist, b.

			 1761.</persname>
            <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Chaptal, Jean-Antoine-Claude, comte

			 de Chanteloup, 1756-1832.</persname>
            <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Fourcroy, Antoine-François de,

			 comte, 1755-1809.</persname>
            <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Lavoisier, Antoine Laurent,

			 1743-1794.</persname>
            <persname encodinganalog="MARC 700">Chaptal,

			 Jean-Antoine-Claude,--comte de Chanteloup,--1756-1832.</persname>
            <persname encodinganalog="MARC 700">Fourcroy, Antoine-François

			 de,--comte,-- 1755-1809.</persname>
            <persname encodinganalog="MARC 700">Lavoisier, Antoine

			 Laurent,--1743-1794.</persname>
            <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">France. Régie des poudres et

			 salpêtres.</corpname>
            <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">France.--Armé--Ordnance and

			 ordnance stores.</corpname>
         </controlaccess>
         <controlaccess>
            <head>Subjects:</head>
            <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="MARC 650">Currency

			 question--France.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="MARC 650">Paper

			 money--France.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="MARC 650">Assignats.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="MARC 650">Local

			 government--France.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="MARC 650">Finance,

			 Public--France--History.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="MARC 650">Local

			 government--France.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="MARC 650">Ordnance.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="MARC 650">Saltpeter.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="MARC 650">Gunpowder.</subject>
         </controlaccess>
         <controlaccess>
            <head>Places:</head>
            <geogname source="lcsh" encodinganalog="MARC 651">France--History--Revolution, 1789-1799.</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh" encodinganalog="MARC 651">France--History--Louis XVI, 1774-1793.</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh" encodinganalog="MARC 651">France--Politics and

			 government--1789-1799.</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh" encodinganalog="MARC 651">France--Politics and

			 government--1774-1793.</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh" encodinganalog="MARC 651">France--Economic

			 conditions--18th century.</geogname>
            <geogname source="lcsh" encodinganalog="MARC 651">Paris

			 (France)--Politics and government.</geogname>
         </controlaccess>
      </controlaccess>
      <descgrp type="admininfo">
         <head>INFORMATION FOR USERS</head>
         <prefercite>
            <head>Cite As:</head>
            <p>La Forte collection, #4711. Division of Rare and Manuscript

			 Collections, Cornell University Library.</p>
         </prefercite>
         <acqinfo>
            <head>PROVENANCE</head>
            <p>The La Forte Collection was purchased from the bookseller Lucien

			 Scheler of Paris in 1967 with the help of a donation by Arthur Dean.</p>
         </acqinfo>
      </descgrp>
      <relatedmaterial>
         <head>RELATED MATERIAL</head>
         <p>The La Forte Collection acquires added interest from its

			 relationship to the Lavoisier Collection and Lavoisier Manuscripts Collection

			 in the History of Science Collections. Lavoisier's connection to the salpetre

			 industry is described briefly by Denis I. Duveen and H.S. Klickstein in their 

		  <title>A Bibliography of Antoine Laurent Lavoisier</title>, London,

		  1954, pp. 219-231. Other related materials at Cornell are held in the French

		  Revolution Collection, Ben Grauer Collection, Maurepas Collection, Lafayette

		  Collection, and the general collection in the Division of Rare and Manuscript

		  Collection. </p>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <arrangement>
         <head>COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT</head>
         <p>The bookseller's description of the collection (available at the

		  Reference Desk), written in French and replete with representative extracts

		  from documents and correspondence, forms the core of the guide. The

		  bookseller's description treats the material as falling into three broad

		  series: general manuscripts and documents dating from the whole of La Forte's

		  career; correspondence from 1786 to 1793; and correspondence from

		  <emph render="italic">An</emph> II (1793/1794) to <emph render="italic">An</emph> V (1796/1797). The two correspondence series are

		  further divided into groups, usually according to the type of correspondent

		  (eg, correspondence from instructors, from the <emph render="italic">Comité de

		  Salut Public</emph>, etc.), and less frequently according to the particular

		  issue or project they address (eg, the construction of a powder mill).</p>
      </arrangement>
      <arrangement>
         <head>SERIES LIST</head>
         <list type="deflist">
            <defitem>
               <label>Series I. General Manuscripts and Documents</label>
               <item>Boxes 1, 3, 6, 7, 9, 10</item>
            </defitem>
            <defitem>
               <label>Series II. Correspondence from 1786 to 1793</label>
               <item>Box 1</item>
            </defitem>
            <defitem>
               <label>Series III. Correspondence from <emph render="italic">An</emph> II (1793/1794) to <emph render="italic">An</emph> V

				(1796/1797)</label>
               <item>Boxes 1, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8</item>
            </defitem>
            <defitem>
               <label>Series IV. Miscellaneous Documents</label>
               <item>Boxes 4, 6</item>
            </defitem>
         </list>
      </arrangement>
      <dsc type="in-depth">
         <head>CONTAINER LIST</head>
         <c01 level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Series I. General Manuscripts and Documents</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">1</container>
                  <container type="folder">3</container>
                  <unittitle>Documents Concernant l'Inspectuer Benoist La

				  Forte</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">1</container>
                  <container type="folder">7</container>
                  <unittitle>Instruction pour l'Inspection Générale</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">1</container>
                  <container type="folder">8</container>
                  <unittitle>Archives de M. de La Forte, Commissaire Puis Inspecteur

				  Général des Poudres</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">1</container>
                  <container type="folder">9</container>
                  <unittitle>Archives de M. de La Forte, Commissaire Puis Inspecteur

				  Général des Poudres</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">1</container>
                  <container type="folder">10</container>
                  <unittitle>Archives de M. de La Forte, Commissaire Puis Inspecteur

				  Général des Poudres</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">3</container>
                  <container type="folder">1</container>
                  <unittitle>Archives de M. de La Forte, Commissaire Puis Inspecteur

				  Général des Poudres</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">6</container>
                  <container type="folder">3</container>
                  <unittitle>Archives de M. de La Forte, Commissaire Puis Inspecteur

				  Général des Poudres</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">6</container>
                  <container type="folder">4</container>
                  <unittitle>Archives de M. de La Forte, Commissaire Puis Inspecteur

				  Général des Poudres</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">6</container>
                  <container type="folder">5</container>
                  <unittitle>Archives de M. de La Forte, Commissaire Puis Inspecteur

				  Général des Poudres</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">6</container>
                  <container type="folder">7</container>
                  <unittitle>Archives de M. de La Forte, Commissaire Puis Inspecteur

				  Général des Poudres</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">6</container>
                  <container type="folder">8</container>
                  <unittitle>Archives de M. de La Forte, Commissaire Puis Inspecteur

				  Général des Poudres</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">6</container>
                  <container type="folder">9</container>
                  <unittitle>Archives de M. de La Forte, Commissaire Puis Inspecteur

				  Général des Poudres</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">7</container>
                  <container type="folder">8</container>
                  <unittitle>Archives de M. de La Forte, Commissaire Puis Inspecteur

				  Général des Poudres</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">7</container>
                  <container type="folder">9</container>
                  <unittitle>Archives de M. de La Forte, Commissaire Puis Inspecteur

				  Général des Poudres</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">1</container>
                  <container type="folder">2</container>
                  <unittitle>Récépissés de la Régie des Poudres</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">3d</container>
                  <container type="folder">[4]</container>
                  <unittitle>Archives Comptables de M. de La Forte Commissaire, puis

				  Inspecteur Général des Poudres: Année 1787</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">3d</container>
                  <container type="folder">[3]</container>
                  <unittitle>Archives Comptables de M. de La Forte Commissaire, puis

				  Inspecteur Général des Poudres: Année 1788</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">3c</container>
                  <container type="folder">[1]</container>
                  <unittitle>Archives Comptables de M. de La Forte Commissaire, puis

				  Inspecteur Général des Poudres: Année 1789</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">3c</container>
                  <container type="folder">[2]</container>
                  <unittitle>Archives Comptables de M. de La Forte Commissaire, puis

				  Inspecteur Général des Poudres: Année 1790</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">3c</container>
                  <container type="folder">[5]</container>
                  <unittitle>Archives Comptables de M. de La Forte Commissaire, puis

				  Inspecteur Général des Poudres: Année 1791</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">3c</container>
                  <container type="folder">[7]</container>
                  <unittitle>Archives Comptables de M. de La Forte Commissaire, puis

				  Inspecteur Général des Poudres: Année 1792</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">3d</container>
                  <container type="folder">[6]</container>
                  <unittitle>Archives Comptables de M. de La Forte Commissaire, puis

				  Inspecteur Général des Poudres: Année 1793</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">9a</container>
                  <container type="folder">1 (oversize)</container>
                  <unittitle>Archives Comptables de M. de La Forte Commissaire, puis

				  Inspecteur Général des Poudres: An II</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">9b</container>
                  <container type="folder">2</container>
                  <unittitle>Archives Comptables de M. de La Forte Commissaire, puis

				  Inspecteur Général des Poudres: An III</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">10a</container>
                  <unittitle>Archives Comptables de M. de La Forte Commissaire, puis

				  Inspecteur Général des Poudres: An IV</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">10b (oversize)</container>
                  <unittitle>Archives Comptables de M. de La Forte Commissaire, puis

				  Inspecteur Général des Poudres: An V</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">1</container>
                  <container type="folder">4</container>
                  <unittitle>Le Comité de Salut Public et la Fabrication des Poudres

				  et Salpêtres Principalement  Avignon</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Series II. Correspondence from 1786 to 1793</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">1</container>
                  <container type="folder">1</container>
                  <unittitle>Correspondance avec la Ragie des Poudres</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Series III. Correspondence from <emph render="italic">An</emph> II (1793/1794) to <emph render="italic">An</emph> V

				(1796/1797)</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">1</container>
                  <container type="folder">5</container>
                  <unittitle>Correspondance avec le Comité de Salut

				  Public</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">4</container>
                  <container type="folder">6</container>
                  <unittitle>Correspondance avec l'Agence et les Regisseurs des

				  Salpêtres et Poudres</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">6</container>
                  <container type="folder">1</container>
                  <unittitle>Correspondance avec les Représentants du Peuple en

				  Mission</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">4</container>
                  <container type="folder">7-14</container>
                  <unittitle>Correspondance avec les Commissaires des Poudres et

				  Salpêtres</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">4</container>
                  <container type="folder">3</container>
                  <unittitle>Correspondance avec les Administrations des

				  Départements</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">7</container>
                  <container type="folder">4</container>
                  <unittitle>Correspondance avec les Commissaires du Directoire

				  Exécutif près les Communes</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">7</container>
                  <container type="folder">5</container>
                  <unittitle>Correspondance avec les Commissaires du Directoire

				  Exécutif</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">7</container>
                  <container type="folder">3</container>
                  <unittitle>Correspondance des Administrations des

				  Districts</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">7</container>
                  <container type="folder">1-2</container>
                  <unittitle>Correspondance avec les Agents Nationaux près les

				  Districts</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">3</container>
                  <container type="folder">2-5</container>
                  <unittitle>Correspondance avec les Communes</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">3</container>
                  <container type="folder">6</container>
                  <unittitle>Correspondance avec les Municipalités et les Corps

				  Constitués</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">4</container>
                  <container type="folder">5</container>
                  <unittitle>Correspondance de l'Inspecteur Général La Forte avec

				  la Municipalité d'Avignon Relativement  Diverses Fournitures</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">4</container>
                  <container type="folder">1-2</container>
                  <unittitle>Correspondance avec les Prbposés Instructeurs de

				  l'Agence des Poudres et Salpêtres</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">5</container>
                  <container type="folder">1-28</container>
                  <unittitle>Correspondance avec l'Agence des Salpêtres et Poudres

				  et les Agents Salpêtriers des Départements</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">6</container>
                  <container type="folder">6</container>
                  <unittitle>Correspondance avec les Agents Salpêtriers des

				  Départements</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">8</container>
                  <container type="folder">1</container>
                  <unittitle>Correspondance avec les Ouvriers et les Salpêtriers

				  Commissionnés</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">8</container>
                  <container type="folder">3-4</container>
                  <unittitle>Correspondance avec les Ouvriers et les Salpêtriers

				  Commissionnés</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">8</container>
                  <container type="folder">2</container>
                  <unittitle>Correspondance avec les Saliniers</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">7</container>
                  <container type="folder">7</container>
                  <unittitle>Correspondance avec les Intéressés aux Mines de

				  Saint-Bel et de Chessy</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">7</container>
                  <container type="folder">6</container>
                  <unittitle>Correspondance avec les Receveurs de

				  District</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">7</container>
                  <container type="folder">7</container>
                  <unittitle>Correspondance avec Divers An II- An V</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Series IV. Miscellaneous Documents</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">4</container>
                  <container type="folder">4</container>
                  <unittitle>Pièces Relatives  la Fourniture du Pain et des Rations

				  aux Ouvriers de la Manufacture des Poudres et Salpêtres d'Avignon</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <container type="box">6</container>
                  <container type="folder">2</container>
                  <unittitle>Pièces Diverses An II- An III</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
      <otherfindaid>
         <head>OTHER GUIDES TO THE COLLECTION</head>
         <p>The bookseller's description of the collection, which forms the core

			 of this guide, is available at the Reference Desk. Please contact 

			 <extref href="mailto:ref@cornell.edu">ref@cornell.edu</extref>
         </p>
      </otherfindaid>
   </archdesc>
</ead>