<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<!-- Transformed with v1v2002_4_cornell.xsl -->

<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../dtds/ead.dtd">
	 
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../styles/style.xsl" ?>
<ead>
   <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1" scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
      <eadid mainagencycode="nic" countrycode="us" publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections//TEXT(US::NIC::RMM01944::Samuel Frederick Nixon papers)//EN">RMM01944.xml</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Samuel Frederick Nixon papers, 1887-1958</titleproper>
            <titleproper type="sort">Nixon, Samuel Frederick papers, 1887-1958</titleproper>
            <author>Compiled by E. Hansen</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library</publisher>
            <date>March 2004</date>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note audience="internal">
               <p> 
				
                  <subject>rghis</subject>
			 
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>Finding aid encoded by Martin Heggestad <date>March 2004</date>
         </creation>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change encodinganalog="583">
            <date normal="2007-05-29">2007-05-29</date>
            <item>converted from EAD 1.0 to EAD 2002 </item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <frontmatter>
      <titlepage>
         <titleproper>Guide to the Samuel Frederick Nixon Papers,<lb/>
         </titleproper>
         <num>Collection Number: 1944</num>
         <publisher>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections <lb/>Cornell University Library</publisher>
         <list type="deflist">
            <defitem>
               <label>Contact Information:</label>
               <item>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections<lb/>
2B Carl A. Kroch Library<lb/>
Cornell University<lb/>
Ithaca, NY 14853<lb/>
(607) 255-3530<lb/>
Fax: (607) 255-9524<lb/>
<extref href="mailto:rareref@cornell.edu">rareref@cornell.edu</extref>
                  <lb/>
<extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu">http://rmc.library.cornell.edu</extref>
                  <lb/></item>
            </defitem>
            <defitem>
               <label>Compiled by:</label>
               <item>E. Hansen</item>
            </defitem>
            <defitem>
               <label>Date completed:</label>
               <item>August 1960</item>
            </defitem>
            <defitem>
               <label>EAD encoding:</label>
               <item>Martin Heggestad, March 2004</item>
            </defitem>
         </list>
         <date>© 2002 Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library</date>
      </titlepage>
   </frontmatter>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <head id="a1">DESCRIPTIVE SUMMARY</head>
         <unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="MARC 245">Samuel Frederick Nixon papers, 
		  <unitdate type="inclusive" encodinganalog="MARC 245">1887-1958, </unitdate>
		  
            <unitdate type="bulk" encodinganalog="MARC 245">1887-1905 (bulk)</unitdate>
		
         </unittitle>
         <unitid label="Collection Number:">1944</unitid>
         <origination label="Creator:"> 
		  
            <persname encodinganalog="100" normal="Nixon, Samuel Frederick, 1860-1905.">Samuel Frederick Nixon, 1860-1905.</persname>
		
         </origination>
         <physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="MARC 300">10 reels positive, 10 reels negative microfilm.</physdesc>
         <physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Correspondence, scrapbooks, cartoons, broadsides, memorial resolutions, biographical sketches, and obituaries.</physdesc>
         <repository label="Repository:"> Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library</repository>
         <abstract label="Abstract:">Includes correspondence from fellow political figures, constituents, special interest groups, and office-seekers concerning legislation under consideration in Albany; local and state politics, patronage, and other matters. Also, personal business correspondence; scrapbooks (4 volumes, 1895-1958) of clippings, cartoons, and broadsides, dealing chiefly with poitical events and issues during Nixon's public life; memorial resolutions, biographical sketches, and obituaries.</abstract>
         <langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="041" langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
         <head id="a2" altrender="biography">BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE </head>
         <p>Samuel Frederick Nixon was a trustee of the Village of Westfield, member of the Chautauqua County Board of Supervisors from the Town of Westfield, chairman of the county committee of the Republican Party, New York State Assemblyman, and speaker of the Assembly.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520">
         <head id="a3">COLLECTION DESCRIPTION</head>
         <p>Includes correspondence from fellow political figures, constituents, special interest groups, and office-seekers concerning legislation under consideration in Albany; local and state politics, patronage, and other matters. Also, personal business correspondence; scrapbooks (4 volumes, 1895-1958) of clippings, cartoons, and broadsides, dealing chiefly with poitical events and issues during Nixon's public life; memorial resolutions, biographical sketches, and obituaries.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <head id="a7">SUBJECTS</head>
         <controlaccess>
            <head>Names: </head>
            <persname encodinganalog="MARC 100">Nixon, Samuel Frederick, 1860-1905.</persname>
            <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Chautauqua County (N.Y.). Board of Supervisors.</corpname>
            <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">New York (State). Legislature.Assembly.</corpname>
            <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Republican Party (Chautauqua County, N.Y.)</corpname>
         </controlaccess>
         <controlaccess>
            <head>Subjects:</head>
            <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Patronage, Political.</subject>
            <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Politics, Practical.</subject>
            <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Politicians.</subject>
         </controlaccess>
         <controlaccess>
            <head>Places:</head>
            <geogname encodinganalog="MARC 651">Chautauqua County (N.Y.)--Politics and government.</geogname>
            <geogname encodinganalog="MARC 651">New York (State)--Politics and government.</geogname>
         </controlaccess>
         <controlaccess>
            <head>Form and Genre Terms:</head>
            <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="MARC 655">Broadsides.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="MARC 655">Scrapbooks.</genreform>
         </controlaccess>
      </controlaccess>
      <descgrp type="admininfo">
         <head id="a8">INFORMATION FOR USERS</head>
         <prefercite>
            <head>Cite As:</head>
            <p>Samuel Frederick Nixon papers, #1944. Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library.</p>
         </prefercite>
      </descgrp>
      <relatedmaterial>
         <head id="a5">NOTES</head>
         <p>Related collection: Joseph McGinnies. Papers, #1943.</p>
         <p>Related collection: Chautauqua County Republican Party Committee. Minute Book, #1945.</p>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <dsc type="combined">
         <head>CONTAINER LIST</head>
         <c01 level="file">
            <did>
               <container type="reel">1</container>
               <unittitle>Reel one covers the years 
				<unitdate>1898-1899</unitdate>
				and contains letters of congratulations to Nixon upon his election as Speaker of the New York Assembly, requests for positions on certain committees, letters attacking or supporting certain bills, and inquiries about state jobs and patronage.</unittitle>
            </did>
         </c01>
         <c01 level="file">
            <did>
               <container type="reel">2</container>
               <unittitle>Reel two covers the years 
				<unitdate>1900-1902</unitdate>
				and contains numerous letters attacking or supporting certain bills, e.g., the San Jose scale measure; letters from friends and pressure groups concerning politics and legislation; letters dealing with Nixon's business affairs in Chautauqua County; correspondence concerning the location of the proposed state tuberculosis hospital.</unittitle>
            </did>
         </c01>
         <c01 level="file">
            <did>
               <container type="reel">3</container>
               <unittitle>Reel three covers the years 
				<unitdate>1902-1903</unitdate>
				and contains letters relating to (a) formation of the Chautauqua County Trust Company and other business affairs (b) politics and legislation, e.g., the Stevens bill providing for a unified public school system in New York State, mortgage tax law, canal improvement, and restrictions on spear fishing in Lake Chautauqua.</unittitle>
            </did>
         </c01>
         <c01 level="file">
            <did>
               <container type="reel">4</container>
               <unittitle>The chronology is very confused on reel four. Correspondence begins with 
				<unitdate>1900</unitdate>
				and moves back to 
				<unitdate>1894</unitdate>
				. The latter part of the reel covers the years 1900- 
				<unitdate>1901</unitdate>
				. The correspondence embodies requests for patronage, attacks or endorsements of various measures before the State Assembly, and letters dealing with Chautauqua County politics.</unittitle>
            </did>
         </c01>
         <c01 level="file">
            <did>
               <container type="reel">5</container>
               <unittitle>Reel five is devoted entirely to the year 
				<unitdate>1901</unitdate>
				and concerns the following topics: personal business correspondence; dispute on the selection of a site for the proposed state tuberculosis hospital, letters protesting the selection of the Ray Brooke site; requests for patronage and state offices; attacks on the proposed Bell and Wagner medical bills; requests from citizens in the Conewango Swamp area that the state of New York assume the cost of draining the swamp; attacks on the proposed engineers bill #207 requiring competency tests for railway engineers; extensive correspondence concerning the canal improvement bill; and a petition from the Chautauqua County Pomona Grange supporting woman suffrage.</unittitle>
            </did>
         </c01>
         <c01 level="file">
            <did>
               <container type="reel">6</container>
               <unittitle>Reel six contains letters covering the years 
				<unitdate>1901-1903</unitdate>
				and concerns political affairs in Chautauqua County, patronage, the Bell medical bill, canal improvement, and the mortgage tax measure.</unittitle>
            </did>
         </c01>
         <c01 level="file">
            <did>
               <container type="reel">7</container>
               <unittitle>Reel seven contains four scrapbooks composed of newspaper clippings which deal with Nixon's political career. Volume I covers the period from Jan. 4, 1899 to Dec. 30, 1899; Volume II from Jan. 9, 1901 to July 8, 1902; Volume III from Jan. 7, 1902 to Jan. 30, 1903; Volume IV from Jan. 16, 1903 to Apr. 17, 1958.</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>a) Volume I contains a number of cartoons and broadsides, 1895-1905.</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>b) Volume II contains clippings dealing with the Dean bill, Odell machine, state police bill, canal bill, mortgage tax bill, the Ray Brooke site controversy, and the Nixon for United States Senator movement.</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>c) Volume III contains clippings dealing with the 1902 legislature, Chautauqua Centennial, the political future of State Senator Higgins of the Chautauqua area, the local and state elections of 1902.</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>d) Volume IV contains clippings dealing with the 1903 and 1904 legislatures and two obituary notices, George R. Nixon, Feb. 23, 1927, and Samuel Frederick Nixon, Junior, Apr. 13, 1958.</unittitle>
               </did>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 level="file">
            <did>
               <container type="reel">8</container>
               <unittitle>Reel eight contains personal letters to Nixon covering the years 
				<unitdate>1900</unitdate>
				and 
				<unitdate>1903-1904</unitdate>
				. The correspondence deals with patronage, personal business correspondence (Erie Rapid Transit Street Railway Company, Jamestown and Chautauqua Railroad Company, Lake Erie Railroad Company), pressure for the canal improvement act, Republican Party politics in Chautauqua County and New York State, and Nixon's activities as a member of the Chautauqua County Board of Supervisors.</unittitle>
            </did>
         </c01>
         <c01 level="file">
            <did>
               <container type="reel">9</container>
               <unittitle> The chronology on reel nine is very confused. The first half of the reel covers the years 
				<unitdate>1900, 1902 and 1904</unitdate>
				and contains personal letters to Nixon dealing with state and local politics. The second half covers the years 
				<unitdate>1894-1895</unitdate>
				and 
				<unitdate>1897-1898</unitdate>
				and concerns various issues facing the state legislature, e.g., appropriations and expenditures for state institutions and the New York Agricultural Experiment Station, demands for a sugar beet bounty and tariff, assembly bills and petitions, and educational appropriations.</unittitle>
            </did>
         </c01>
         <c01 level="file">
            <did>
               <container type="reel">10</container>
               <unittitle>Reel ten contains various memorials to Samuel Frederick Nixon, e.g., printed pamphlet <title>In Memoriam</title> containing a memorial proclamation by Governor Frank Higgins, memorial speeches by members of the state legislature, a copy of Nixon's last public speech, and Arthur Wade's resolution for a special memorial service for Nixon; newspaper clippings dealing with Nixon's illness in 
				<unitdate>1900</unitdate>
				and his death in 
				<unitdate>1905</unitdate>
				; printed pamphlet <title>Memorial to Samuel Frederick Nixon</title> containing messages of condolence, biographical sketch, tributes by the press, and pictures of funeral rites. </unittitle>
            </did>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>