<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1" scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
		<eadid mainagencycode="nic" countrycode="us" publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections//TEXT(US::NIC::RMM07779::Ed Wood, Jr. collection)//EN">RMM07779.xml</eadid>
		<filedesc>
			<titlestmt>
				<titleproper>Guide to the Ed Wood, Jr.
					collection,<date>1966-2006.</date></titleproper>
				<titleproper type="sort">Wood, Ed Jr. collection</titleproper>
				<author>Compiled by RMC Staff</author>
			</titlestmt>
			<publicationstmt>
				<publisher>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University
					Library</publisher>
				<date>October 2012</date>
			</publicationstmt>
			<notestmt>
				<note audience="internal">
					<p><subject>humsx</subject></p>
				</note>
			</notestmt>
		</filedesc>
		<profiledesc>
			<creation>Finding aid encoded by RMC Staff, <date>October 2012</date></creation>
		</profiledesc>
	</eadheader>
	<frontmatter>
		<titlepage>
			<titleproper>Guide to the Ed Wood, Jr. Collection,<lb/><date type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1966-2006.</date></titleproper>
			<num>Collection Number: 7779</num>
			<publisher>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections <lb/>Cornell University
				Library</publisher>
			<list type="deflist">
				<defitem>
					<label>Contact Information:</label>
					<item> Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections<lb/> 2B Carl A. Kroch
						Library<lb/> Cornell University<lb/> Ithaca, NY 14853<lb/> (607)
						255-3530<lb/> Fax: (607) 255-9524<lb/><extref href="mailto:rareref@cornell.edu">rareref@cornell.edu</extref><lb/><extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu">http://rmc.library.cornell.edu</extref><lb/></item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>Compiled by:</label>
					<item>RMC Staff</item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>Date completed:</label>
					<item>October 2012</item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>EAD encoding:</label>
					<item>Anne Jones, April 2012</item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>Date modified:</label>
					<item>Margaret Nichols, August 2017</item>
				</defitem>
			</list>
			<date>© 2012 Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University
				Library</date>
		</titlepage>
	</frontmatter>
	<archdesc level="collection">
		<did>
			<head id="a1">DESCRIPTIVE SUMMARY</head>
			<unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="MARC 245">Ed Wood, Jr. collection, <unitdate encodinganalog="MARC 245" type="inclusive">1966-2006.</unitdate>
			</unittitle>
			<unitid label="Collection Number:">7779</unitid>
			<origination label="Creator:"><persname encodinganalog="100" normal="Wood, Edward D. (Edward Davis), 1924-1978. ">Wood, Edward D.(Edward
					Davis)</persname></origination>
			<physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="MARC 300"><extent>2 cubic feet.</extent></physdesc>
			<physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Books, magazines, print outs, placards, poster, DVD.</physdesc>
			<repository label="Repository:">Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell
				University Library</repository>
			<abstract label="Abstract:">Pulp novels written anonymously and under various
				pseudonyms of the legendary psycho-sexual author and film-maker, Ed Wood, Jr.,
				collected by pulp scholar Robert Legault (1950 to 2008). In addition, magazines,
				reference materials, posters and other ephemera; and a DVD about Ed Wood.</abstract>
			<langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="041" langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial>
		</did>
		<bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
			<head id="a2" altrender="biography">BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE </head>
			<p>Edward Davis Wood, Jr. (October 10, 1924 to December 10, 1978), better known as Ed
				Wood, was an American screenwriter, director, producer, actor, author, and editor,
				who made a number of low-budget genre films and published pulp novels under various
				names. Ed Wood's fiction is as strange, idiosyncratic and out of step with his times
				and mores as his infamous movies. His novels inter-splice erotic segments with
				lengthy philosophical, sociological and psychological discourse. Rudolph Grey's
				biography "Nightmare of Ecstasy: The Life and Art of Edward D. Wood, Jr." (1992) and
				Tim Burton's biopic "Ed Wood," which earned two Academy Awards, brought attention to
				his life and work. He died in 1978 of an alcohol-induced heart attack and has since
				achieved cult status.</p>
		</bioghist>
		<scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520">
			<head id="a3">COLLECTION DESCRIPTION</head>
			<p>Pulp novels written anonymously and under various pseudonyms of the
				legendary psycho-sexual author and film-maker, Ed Wood, Jr., collected by pulp
				scholar Robert Legault (1950 to 2008). In addition, magazines, reference materials,
				posters and other ephemera.</p>
			<p>Also, an original one sheet poster for the 1953 film, "Glen or Glenda?" directed by
				Ed Wood, Jr. in his feature film debut. Originally titled "I Changed My Sex," the
				film has maintained a solid cult following over the decades despite its poor reviews
				due to Wood's decidedly distinctive style and z-budget production values. The aim of
				the film's producer, George Weiss, was to capitalize on the story Christina
				Jorgensen, who in 1952 became the first man widely known to undergo sex reassignment
				surgery. The film's first half guides the viewer down a crooked path that includes
				multiple narration techniques, BDSM (bondage/discipline/sadomasochist) pornography,
				and a buffalo stampede in order to convey a story about a man named Glen who wishes
				to become a transvestite, struggling to gain acceptance from his girlfriend. The
				second half, added largely at the demand of the distributor to include sex change in
				the content, is about a pseudohermaphrodite named Alan who fights his way through
				World War II in women's underwear, finally returning from the conflict to have the
				surgery he/she has always desired.</p>
			<p> Also, a DVD of an episode of "The Incredibly Strange Film Show," volume 3, on Ed Wood, featuring interviews with Wood's colleagues and clips from his films "Glen or Glenda?", "Bride of the Monster," "Plan 9 From Outer Space," "Revenge of the Dead," and "The Bride and the Beast." Also included in the DVD is his film "The Sinister Urge."</p>
		</scopecontent>
		<controlaccess>
			<head id="a7">SUBJECTS</head>
			<controlaccess>
				<head>Names: </head>
				<persname encodinganalog="MARC 100">Wood, Edward D., Jr. (Edward Davis), 1924-1978.</persname>
			</controlaccess>
		</controlaccess>
		<descgrp>
			<head id="a8">INFORMATION FOR USERS</head>
			<prefercite>
				<head>Cite As:</head>
				<p>Ed Wood, Jr. collection, #7779. Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections,
					Cornell University Library.</p>
			</prefercite>
		</descgrp>
		<odd type="notes">
			<head id="a6">NOTES</head>
			<p>Collecting Program: Human Sexuality Collection.</p>
		</odd>
		<dsc type="combined">
			<head>CONTAINER LIST</head>
			<c01 level="series">
				<did>
					<unittitle id="s1">Series I. Novels</unittitle>
				</did>

				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1963</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">Black Lace Drag</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	160	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Raven Books,	North Hollywood<lb/>[Wood’s first novel] </p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1965</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">Killer in Drag</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	192	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Imperial Books/Star News Co.,	Union City, NJ<lb/>[same as Black Lace Drag (Raven, 1963), Wood’s first novel.  Also printed as Black Lace Drag (Private Edition, 1967) and The Twilight Land (Europa, 1967) credited to Sheri Blue.]</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1965</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">The Homosexual Generation</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname><lb/>Pseudonym: <persname>	Ken Worthy</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	192	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	imperial Books/L.S. Publications Corp.,	New York<lb/>[purported socio-sexual study of the leanings of the current generation.  
							Generally derogatory in nature.  Page 105: "A fair sample of what is happening to the man-woman relationship can be seen in the movie, 
							‘The Knack – and How to Get it.’  Like, ‘Goodbye, Charley,’ and ‘Some Like It Hot,’ this is another thinly disguised homosexual movie in which a 
							young girl goes about begging one of three young men to rape her.  The men show no interest whatsoever, and the homosexual element is brought 
							out clearly when the leading character says of another male, ‘I want him to come here and live with us.  His name is Ricky.  He’s beautifully 
							big – six foot three – and he can teach both of us some tricks.’  All the male characters in the movie have hair curling around their collars; 
							all wear their hair brushed forward in a pompadour and all are very obviously interested only in males to the bewilderment of the girl who is 
							trying to get herself raped."  Page 174: "So there is a ‘cure’ for homosexuality – and it rests entirely with the parents!"] I personally think 
							this questionable whether or not its Wood </p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				
				
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1966</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">Mask of Evil</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname><lb/>Pseudonym: <persname>	Charlene White</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	157	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent><p>Publisher: 	First Niter Books, Inc.,	Buffalo<lb/>Cover art by Eric Stanton; also includes an interior advertisement 
						for Stanton's "Stantoons."<lb/>[Page 94: "The intruder was going deeper, penetrating further and further into her sensitive, exquisite tenderness.  
						She moaned and moved, trying to escape the sweet pain, yet now quite wanting not to do so.  Her movements only made the pain go deeper.  ‘Oh, no! No.’  
						She moaned.  ‘Stop.  Please stop.  Don’t stop!  It’s good.  It hurts, Ohh-h-h-h-h!’  The pressure on her became unbearably good.  Her senses were reeling.  
						Colors were whirling and swirling under her closed eyelids.  Then suddenly, sweetly, inexplicably, she was past the pain and was moving and twisting in 
						harmony with the youth.  Suddenly, she knew she had to scream.  Her lips parted without volition and a harsh, rough sound poured from her..At the same 
						time the young man’s breathing became jagged, cutting litany.  Infinity became finite and stood still."] read to give summary </p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1966</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">Orgy of the Dead</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr., intro by Forrest J. Ackerman</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	160	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Greenleaf Classics, Inc.,	San Diego<lb/>Photo Illustrated by R. Charleton Wilson (b&amp;w)<lb/>[novelization of the film by the same name, 
							scripted by Ed Wood, directed by A. C. Stephen (Stephen Apostolof).  Cover art done by adult paperback master Robert Bonfils.  The wolfman on the cover 
							is not actually in the book, but only in the film.  Illustrated with stills from the film.] add compiled info/summarize/excerpt </p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02><c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1966</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">Parisian Passions</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname><lb/>Pseudonym: <persname>	J. X. Williams (on cvr only, inside TP is Wood)</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	191	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Corinth Publications,	San Diego<lb/>[cover reads by J. X. Williams, a house name for Corinth, however the inside title page 
							states Wood’s real name.  Original title was reported as 69 Rue Pigalle.  The story follows Parisian Inspector Goulet tracking down the 
							killer of a number of strippers on the Rue Morgue.  He brings in Texas man Sherriff Buck Rhodes and female impersonator Lorraine Peters 
							for assistance.  Page 79: "Buck poured his glass full from the second bottle of wine.  It was apparent from the tensions in the room that 
							the unruly, sex-crazed mob wanted action and they wanted it now.  They had been kept waiting too long already.  They hadn’t come down to 
							the cellar just to sit around contemplating their own belly buttons.  Their whole idea was to contemplate someone else’s belly button."] 
							Eric Stanton cvr art?</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1966</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">Side-Show Siren</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	190	</physdesc>
					</did><scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Corinth Publications,	San Diego<lb/>[Rudolph Grey detailed: "When Karl the Abominable Snowman escapes from a carnival, 
							a series of gruesome murders ensues.  Change from the original title Naked Bones as more marketable for the paperback trade, 
							Side-Show Siren is possibly the first of Wood’s carnival novels.  It resembles films like The Ape (with Boris Karloff, Monogram, 
							1940) and Circus of Horrors (AIP, 1960).  The character of Jinx Dixon, a cowboy sharpshooter, is modeled after Wood’s close friend, 
							Kenne Duncan."  One-time Republic Pictures contract actor, Kenne "Horsecock" Duncan was, according to Grey, "known and billed as 
							‘the meanest man in the movies.’"] </p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
			
			
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1967</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">A Half World</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname><lb/>Pseudonym: <persname>	Michael Sharon</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	159	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Pad Library,	Agoura, CA</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1967</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">Black Lace Drag</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	160	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Private Edition Books,	Canoga Park<lb/>[1967 reprint of 1963 Raven Books Black Lace Drag, Wood’s first book.  
							Verso of title page claims "first printing 1967".]</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1967</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">Bloodiest Sex Crimes in History</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname><lb/>Pseudonym: <persname>	Spenser and West</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	160	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Pad Library/Nite Time,	Agoura, CA<lb/>[in the style of Spenser and West, "sexological" studies of vampirism, murder, necrophilia, prostitution,
							and contains a glossary of terminology.  Page 61: "This is not to suggest that ALL or even MOST morticians are Necrophiles.  It merely supposes that if 
							one is inclined toward the Necrophile practice – the choice of being a Mortician is logical."] read, excerpt, what is up with catalog numbers corresponding 
							to other pub. companies?</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1967</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">Confessions of a Hollywood Starlet</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname><lb/>Pseudonym: <persname>	Spenser and West</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	192	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Cougar Publications,	Los Angeles<lb/>[Not mentioned elsewhere in Wood literature, this book contains many Woodian hallmarks, 
							i.e. gratuitous ellipses and Hollywood sleaze, however the writing is slightly more sober than usual.  The story concerns casting couch shenanigans, 
							with character names such as Jake Palerack, Wolfgang von Klienshimdt, Fritz Dykeman, and Beverly Fuller.] </p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1967</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">Death of a Transvestite</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	192	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Pad Library/Nite Time,	Agoura, CA<lb/>[the follow-up to Black Lace Drag, concerns contract killer Glen/Glenda on death row who demands 
							to be allowed to die in drag.  Told in a Gothic epistolary style via clippings, confessions, etc.  Considered one of Wood’s finest works.] excerpt </p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1967</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">Devil Girls</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	192	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Pad Library,	Agoura, CA<lb/>[Rudolph Grey writes: "In the small town of Almanac, Texas, Sheriff Buck Rhodes tangles with drug smugglers 
							and teenage gangs, including the wild girl gang, The Chicks.  A series of sexual liaisons and violence culminate in their tragic end."  David Hayes 
							qualified, "Owing chiefly to the year it was printed, Devil Girls stands as the testament to Wood’s writing in the Golden Age.  Low on smut, but high 
							on intrigue and scandal, the novel moves along at a brisk pace and creates characters that are both believable and interesting (aside from Wood’s usual 
							stereotypical bad girls)."]</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1967</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">Drag Trade</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	159	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Triumph News Co., Inc.,	Van Nuys<lb/>[Page 38: "But come as it may, for the first time in his life he felt like a human being.  
							Before, with only the panties and the half slip he hadn’t been quite sure. He knew he liked the feeling of the clothes then, but once he had dressed 
							completely as a girl, he knew it was the life he must lead.  None of their hair would ever grow to any length, but wigs took care of that small problem.  
							And being young they taught him just how far his bust line should extend.  He love sweaters, the soft cashmeres and angoras...and he liked to see the 
							breasts sticking out in front of him...but for his size and age he was limited to the lines of a teenager."]</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1967</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">It Takes One to Know One</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	191	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Pad Library/Imperial,	Agoura, CA<lb/>[excerpt]</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1967</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">Security Risk</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	192	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Pad Library,	Agoura, CA<lb/>[Grey writes: "Espionage, Wood style, involving hard communists, sabotage at a movie set, and hard-loving, 
							hard smoking and hard drinking Col. Harvey Tate."  Hayes: "This is another classic case of Wood’s real-world experience (minus the freaky sex) 
							shoved smack dab into a smut novel."  The plot surrounds terrorists murdering employees at a government operated low-budget film company, 
							much like Autonetics Aviation, a company Wood had briefly made films for in the past.]</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1967</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">Sex Life of the Alcoholic</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname><lb/>Pseudonym: <persname>	Johnny J.</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	192	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Griffon Enterprises/Nite Time Books,	Beverly Hills<lb/>[case histories of boozy sexual encounters, dedication reads: 
							"To those anonymous booze-fighters whose stories are presented in these pages – and to the scores of others, likewise not to be named, 
							who have helped in the preparation of this book. – Johnny J."  Book topics include "Early Drinking and Introduction to Sex", "Alcohol as a Sexual Lubricant",
							"Breakdown of Sexual Inhibitions", "Rape, Incest and Homosexuality Through Release by Alcohol", and "Housewife Prostitution and Alcohol."]</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1967</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">Strange Sisters</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname><lb/>Pseudonym: <persname>	Sheri Blue</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	160	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Europa Books Limited/Pad Library,	Los Angeles<lb/>[this book is indicative of a bibliographical problem found elsewhere in both the 
							Ed Wood Collection and in the greater adult paperback business.  Due to the illegal nature of many publications, tax evasion, reusing old book components 
							for new publications, and ties to more savage legal infractions, companies were constantly starting, collapsing and renaming themselves in a fly-by-night 
							fashion.  Therefore we find ourselves with situations like Strange Sisters which has a Pad Library ID# on the cover, yet on the verso of the title page 
							we find the publication credit attributed to Europa Books Limited.  Obscured by a fog of criminality it is quite difficult to know where one company ended 
							and another began.  It is highly likely that the amalgam of imprints were owned by only a few people.  For instance, Michael Thevis of Pendulum was said 
							to have owned 90% of all adult bookstores during the 1970s.  Viceroy Books and Private Editions Books shared the same Canoga Park address.  
							See also Bloodiest Sex Crimes in History and It Takes One To Know One for more confusion.]  </p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1967</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">Suburbia Confidential</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname><lb/>Pseudonym: <persname>	Emil Moreau</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	159	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Triumph News Co., Inc.,	Van Nuys<lb/>[A collection of case histories as reported to Emil Moreau, "M. D."  Beyond the basic concept, 
							allegedly Wood and the book had nothing to do with the Apostolof film of 1966.] </p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1967</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">The Twilight Land</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname><lb/>Pseudonym: <persname>	Sheri Blue</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	160	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Europa Books Limited/Pad Library,	Los Angeles<lb/>[another 1967 reprint of Wood’s Black Lace Drag this time under alternate title and pen name.
							David C. Hayes claims a 1965 edition of The Twilight Land exists as well, though he may be mistaken.] </p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1967</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">Watts...After</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	191	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Pad Library,	Agoura, CA<lb/>[Follow-up to Watts...The Difference, more exploits with black nationalists and low-budget filmmakers] 
							excerpt/summary
						</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1967</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">Watts...The Difference</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	192	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Pad Library,	Agoura, CA<lb/>Cover art is signed but tough to read; looks like "Chad Collen"<lb/>[a Watts riot exploitation piece, 
							it’s rumored that Wood’s home was firebombed after the books release.  Other stories include death threats from the Black Panthers.  
							Alternate version is said to exist as Burn Baby Burn (1969) by Ray Jones] excerpt/summary</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				
				
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1968</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">Bye Bye Broadie</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	157	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Pendulum Publishers,	Los Angeles<lb/>Photo Illustrated (b&amp;w)<lb/>[another pictorial, this time with stills from a Image 4 motion picture 
							production.  Wood biographer Rudolph Grey summarized Broadie, "A peeping tom rapist spies on a group of young women making love in a boarding school.  
							He approaches them and joins in on thethe action.  The man-hating schoolmistress, Mrs. Grundy, discovers the orgy and beats the man to death with her cane.  
							The headmistress then coerces the girls to assist her in burying the body in a nearby pet cemetery.  After the burial, a hand appears out of the ground 
							and grabs one of the young girls.  The bloodied "corpse" smashes Mrs. Grundy with a shovel, sending her off into eternity.  After another young girl falls 
							victim to his revenge, the now blind young man staggers off toward the swamp water.  Accompanying photos are only marginally related to the story."  
							Page 105/6: "All any of them wanted to do was get the damned carcass in the ground and get the hell out of there.  Time was against them!  They had to 
							make the new movement of time aid in their own advantage."]</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1968</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">Carnival Piece</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname><lb/>Pseudonym: <persname>	Kathleen Everett</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	160	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Private Edition Books,	Canoga Park<lb/>[Kathleen Everett was in fact Wood’s wife’s maiden name.  Akin to Side-Show Siren the novel follows a 
							"murder-at-the-carnival" plot.  Grey writes: "Imbroglios concerning carnivals, a murdered dancing girl and her stunning young blonde replacement who 
							attracts the attentions of the local sheriff, the owner of the carnival and Mama Tate, a fat lesbian.  Characters include Wheezy the Skeleton, who prefers 
							wine to food; the Geek, another wino who bites the heads off snakes and chickens; Bertha the 450 pound fat woman; the tattoo man; the magician 
							("a ham bone lush"); the wolf man who "glues hair on his body everyday while he sniffs the glue and pops heroin in his veins"; and Matty, 
							the female impersonator who does the half-man, half-woman act."]</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1968</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">For Love Or Money</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname><lb/>Pseudonym: <persname>	Arthur Windsor</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	149	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	B. B. Sales Co.,	New York, NY<lb/>Photo Illustrated by Bill New (b&amp;w)<lb/>[For Love Or Money originally began as the novel 
							The Sexecutives (1968) by Donald L. Westermier (pseudonym of Edward D. Wood, Jr.).  Wood turned the novel into a script named For Love Or Money 
							that was in turn realized by sexploitation director Don A. Davis.  As was popular, the film was turned into a Foto-Reader which featured text opposite film 
							stills.  The For Love Or Money Foto-Reader is an abridged version of The Sexecutives, with much of Wood’s unique syntactical approaches excised, 
							thus rendering, by most accounts, a truly bland affair.]</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1968</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">Hell Chicks</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname><lb/>Pseudonym: <persname>	N. V. Jason</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	188	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Private Edition Books,	Canoga Park<lb/>Cover art signed "H"<lb/>[Rudolph Grey wrote: "Ghosted under ‘N. V. Jason’, Hell Chicks, 
							is one of Wood’s most crazed, anarchistic novels.  The complete disregard for normal rules of grammar suggest that it was written in one sitting.  
							Unleashed in distorted, alcoholic twists of consciousness, the novel takes girl gangs from his screenplays for The Violent Years and Fugitive Girls 
							to the ne plus ultra of sex and violence.  The Hell Chicks are twelve rough tough broads in black leather jackets.  Their credo: ‘Rules are LAWS and LAWS 
							were meant to be broken.’  Hopped up on grass and beer they roar across the countryside on their hogs, raping any man they can get their hands on.  
							Pussy, Pisser, Prancer, Sissy, Syph, Boobie, Cherry and Flame meet their inevitable end in a climactic bloody showdown with the law."  
							Page 82: "The boys of the Chain Gang hit from the north and the girls of the Hell Chicks screamed in from the south.  Twenty-four cycles with split mufflers
							roared their tunes of terror, into the hearts and soul of every passerby.  They gunned the exhaust...revved the motor...spit the back-fire flame and noise
							into anybody who dared brace them.  They all screamed like banshees and the words of vulgar sexual atonement intermingled with the screaching of tires as 
							they turned as if on a dime and giving nine cents change."  As reported by David Hayes, Hell Chicks marks Wood’s turn to hardcore pornography.] </p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1968</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">Purple Thighs</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	156	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent><p>Publisher: 	Private Edition Books,	Canoga Park<lb/>[Hippie sexploitation, cover says "Originally titled Lost Souls Delivered", Wood’s personal acronym for LSD.  Main characters Adam and Eve.] excerpt</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1968</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">Raped in the Grass</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	157	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Pendulum Publishers,	Los Angeles<lb/>Photo Illustrated (b&amp;w)<lb/>[This Wood novelization of a "film" by D-M Productions, Los Angeles, 
							was likely written from scratch and no film was ever produced.  Raped in the Grass is a pre-Hearst/SLA Helsinki syndrome psycho-sexual fantasy.  
							The book concerns two American girls who get captured by guerillas in a Central American country.  A large amount of sexual and violent torture is 
							unleashed by the guerillas on the girls who desperately want to leave.  Yet, by the end of the pictorial, the American girls realize they have found a 
							new home amidst the sexual degradation in Central America.  "A guerilla band of near-wild men and one sadistic lesbian capture two young girls on a trip...
							a trip that either one of them will ever forget."  Page 143: "Carlos, on the ground, as he came to, reached for his injured ear.  
							For the moment, he thought he was back raping the girl on the grass.  His ear hurt, his eyes opened.  He looked at the makeshift table – 
							to the ankles of his Leader, then he knew although his ass was in the grass, he was not with the broad. The Leader was.  He needed another drink...
							,He rolled over and could only lick at the remnants of his broken jug.  ‘More tequila – more tit!’"]   </p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1968</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">Sex Museum</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname><lb/>Pseudonym: <persname>	Jason Nichols</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	160	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Viceroy Books,	Canoga Park<lb/>[Sex Museum is a retelling of various sexual rites and occurrences throughout history.  
							[Page 81: "The father of our country, the U.S.A., may very well have tried to be just that, the FATHER of our country!  
							He certainly made one hell of an attempt at propagating the race of early Americans to a point where many a colonial mother locked their 
							alluring daughter behind doors when they saw the young militia colonel approaching.  George Washington, the first President of the new states of America 
							was a ‘cock-smith’ from the word ‘GO.’"]</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1968</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">Sex Shrouds and Caskets</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	187	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Viceroy Books,	Canoga Park<lb/>[Writings on the intermingling of sex and religion.  Page 113: 
							"Harry TURNED the girls ON as he had done all of his adult life.  But he TURNED THEM ON with a completely new, foolproof line.  
							‘The force of evil is within all of us!  It is for me to turn that evil out of your souls.’  Then he would open the BOOK at random 
							and read a short paragraph, then put in his own interpretation.  None could deny his words because as so many of his predecessors, 
							he was reading them from the BOOK, and that could not be wrong."]</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">1</container>
						<unitdate>1968</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">The Erotic Spy</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname><lb/>Pseudonym: <persname>	Abbott Smith</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	157	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent><p>Publisher: 	Pendulum Publishers,	Los Angeles<lb/>Photo Illustrated (b&amp;w)<lb/>[Pendulum Pictorials was a series akin to the 
						Olympic Foto-Reader, wherein text was accompanied by photo stills from a film.  As far as the Pendulum Pictorials go, it is highly doubtful that 
						any moving picture ever existed and rather the still photographs were taken with the purpose of illustrating the book.  The Erotic Spy featured the character 
						"The Gold Girl" who was also in the film Orgy of the Dead, played by Pat Barrington.  A note from the Editor: "Gold Girl is one of the most exciting characters 
						to have emerged from the world of fiction in recent years.  Completely amoral, infinitely and diabolically clever, willing to use her voluptuous body in 
						absolutely any way to achieve her ends, Gold Girl is, perhaps, fiction’s most formidable adversary since Superman...Because Gold Girl’s relations with everyone 
						she met – men and women alike – are heavily weighted with sexual overtones, the film was produced exclusively for adult audiences."]</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">2</container>
						<unitdate>1968</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">The Gay Underworld</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	192	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Viceroy Books,	Canoga Park<lb/>[Rudolph Grey writes: "Similar to Wood’s Drag Trade of 1967, with several episodes slightly rewritten.]</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">2</container>
						<unitdate>1968</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">The Love of the Dead</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname><lb/>Pseudonym: <persname>	V. N. Jensen</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	156	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Viceroy Books,	Canoga Park<lb/>[Page 66: "The [r]evulsion would last only a short time...
							Then there must be another dead partner...Soon there would never be the signs of revulsion again...
							       Only hope...and the exercising of his demands."] </p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">2</container>
						<unitdate>1968</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">The Perverts</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname><lb/>Pseudonym: <persname>	Jason Nichols</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	160	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Viceroy Books,	Canoga Park<lb/>[a proposed socio-cultural study of contemporary perversions and ‘deviations’, topics include Necrophilia, 
							Troilism, Prostitution, Fetishes, S&amp;M, Bestiality, Homosexuality, Transvestitism, Incest, Lesbianism.  Page 52: Man will seek out woman wherever he is 
							– the steaming jungles of the Amazon or the same steaming jungles of his own home town.  SEX WILL OUT!  And there will always be the whore to take care of 
							his needs.  She might be hidden or she might be out in the open.  The law will close up her PUSSY for a time, but once she is released the PUSSY will again 
							be open for business.  In thinking along the same thoughts the women of the world are also looking for their own whore – THE MALE WHORE!  There is a fellow 
							who will sell his body to women for a price.  The thoughts even there must go back along the lines of history to the oiled-down frames of the males who 
							were sent to the ruler’s chambers for the night."] excerpt trans section</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">2</container>
						<unitdate>1968</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">The Sexecutives</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname><lb/>Pseudonym: <persname>	David L. Westermier</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	160	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Private Edition Books,	Canoga Park<lb/>Cover art may be by Paul Rader, recycled from a lesbian pulp novel. [PROOF?]
							<lb/>[Surrounds a group of sex spies, "Instant Secretaries, Inc."  Was later turned into the Foto-Reader For Love Or Money.] excerpt heavily</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">2</container>
						<unitdate>1968</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">The Svengali of Sex</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname><lb/>Pseudonym: <persname>	Edgar Andrews</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	157	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Pendulum Publishers,	Los Angeles<lb/>Photo Illustrated (b&amp;w)<lb/>[Svengali concerns the exploits of a hypno-therapist, Larry, 
							who gives his hypnotized female patients the full-treatment.  Page 111: "Under hypnosis at least, she no longer thought of that.  Shirley stood 
							in front of the mirror, turning this way and that to look at herself.  The look on her face was one of critical satisfaction.  Now she turned to face Larry.
							"I think you’re right."  Larry got up and joined her at the mirror.  Casually he placed his hand around her waist.  ‘Now Shirley,’ he said, ‘can’t you see 
							for yourself that any normal man would certainly like you – almost instantly would want to make love to you?’  Shirley looked up at him but her eyes were 
							on his lips.  Softly she said, ‘Would you?’"  Page 137: "Larry kissed and sucked her breasts and used his hands on her love triangle and her hot, moist 
							crevice so that in a very few minutes she was moaning and crying in her ecstasy."  Photos from a B &amp; B Productions motion picture.]</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">2</container>
						<unitdate>1968</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">Young, Black and Gay</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	158	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Publishers Export Co., Inc./French Line Novel ,	San Diego<lb/>A PEC French Line novel<lb/>[Rudolph Grey writes: 
							"A homosexual transvestite adapts to prison life, taking the female sex role while absorbing convict philosophy.  
							He winds up the victim of a brutal beating in a filthy alley."]</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				
				
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">2</container>
						<unitdate>no year/c. 1969/70</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">A Study of the Lesbian the Homosexual the Bi-sexual</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname><lb/>Pseudonym: <persname>	Dr. T. K. Peters with S. T. Lee</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	192	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	SECS Press,	Los Angeles<lb/>Photo Illustrated (color/b&amp;w)<lb/>"Sex Education Clinical Series vol. XI"
							<lb/>[double check to see if this is Wood] </p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">2</container>
						<unitdate>1969</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">Let Me Die in Drag</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname><lb/>Pseudonym: <persname>	Woodrow Edwards</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	192	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Classic Publications,	Los Angeles<lb/>[reissue of Death of a Transvestite]</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">2</container>
						<unitdate>1969</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">Male Wives</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname><lb/>Pseudonym: <persname>	Norman Bates</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	191	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Barclay House,	North Hollywood<lb/>A Barclay House Psycho-Sex Study<lb/>[Bibliography includes Hollywood Babylon by Kenneth Anger, 
							The Seven Pillars of Wisdom by T. E. Lawrence, and more, as well as many adult books.]</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">2</container>
						<unitdate>1969</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">The Oralists</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname><lb/>Pseudonym: <persname>	Spenser and West</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	190	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Tiger Books/Powell Publications,	Reseda<lb/>[Spenser &amp; West were progressive "sexologists" who wrote based off of "interviews and case 
							histories", Introduction reads: "Oralism is the word that has been kept behind closed doors, hidden under hats and seldom spoken above a whisper.  
							It is scorned by thousands, yet secretly enjoyed by millions and is gaining an ever-increasing circle of aficionados.  Why? The hypocrisy intrigued us 
							and we ventured forth into the land of the oralist to find out.  Why is he different from other people?"] </p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				
				
				
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">2</container>
						<unitdate>1970</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">A Study of Stag Films</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname><lb/>Pseudonym: <persname>	S. T. Lee with Dr. T. K. Peters</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	192	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	SECS Press,	Los Angeles<lb/>Photo Illustrated (color/b&amp;w)<lb/>"Sex Education Clinical Series vol. XVI"
							<lb/>[contains glossary of film lingo in back, bibliography, possibly not Ed Wood, book discussions include set design, cinematography, gay films,
							S&amp;M films, and art films, "‘Flaming Creatures’ is another example of underground invasion of the stag market.  The film’s climactic cunnilingual 
							rape scene is expressed with calculated crudity and very primitive photography."  Also discusses Warhol amongst less pretentious pornography.  
							"Maybe a new sexuality is upon us.  Sort of a good-natured narcissism in which sex is a public demonstration whose feelings are best relished by the participant
							s later on...In other words, human confrontation (peace and love) has replaced human copulation.  Sex as passion seems almost non-existent."] 
							Gerhson Legman quote</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">2</container>
						<unitdate>1970</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">Gay Black</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	157	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent><p>Publisher: 	Regency Publishing Co.,	El Cajon<lb/>Reissue of Young, Black and Gay<lb/>[excerpt]</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">2</container>
						<unitdate>1970</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">Teen-Sex Swapping</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname><lb/>Pseudonym: <persname>	Norman Bates</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	c. 191	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Ben's Books Ltd.,	London<lb/>Photo Illustrated (b&amp;w)<lb/>[North Hollywood Barclay copyright, UK print]</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">2</container>
						<unitdate>1970</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">The Adult Version of Dracula</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname><lb/>Pseudonym: <persname>	Anon.</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	190	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Calga Publishers, Inc.,	Los Angeles<lb/>[part of Calga’s "Adult Versions of the World’s Standards", 
							among these advertised were The Escapades of Cleopatra and A Jack London Trilogy.  Told in an epistolary fashion via Jonathan Harker’s journal, 
							letters, clippings, etc. From Johnathan Harker’s journal May 5th (page 33): "My flesh shivered and my hands sank lower.  
							Across her tossing belly and down between her quivering thighs.  She arched the mound of her pussy against my hand, 
							pressing the diamond of delight into my palm."] </p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				
				
				
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">2</container>
						<unitdate>1971</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">A Study of Sexual Practices in Witchcraft and Black Magic: Book 1</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname><lb/>Pseudonym: <persname>	Frank Lennon with Dt. T. K. Peters</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	192	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	SECS Press,	Los Angeles<lb/>Photo Illustrated (color/b&amp;w)
							<lb/>"Sex Education Clinical Series vol. XVII"<lb/>["From time immemorial, sex and Satanism have been one and the same thing.  
							As you will see in later pages, worship of the devil involves sexual excesses on a scale so large, 
							that the so-called Hollywood sex orgies grow pale by comparison."]  off the walls photography and captions – must reproduce</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">2</container>
						<unitdate>1971</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">A Study of Sexual Practices in Witchcraft and Black Magic: Book 2</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname><lb/>Pseudonym: <persname>	Frank Lennon with Dt. T. K. Peters</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	192	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	SECS Press,	Los Angeles<lb/>Photo Illustrated (color/b&amp;w)<lb/>"Sex Education Clinical Series vol. XVIII"
							<lb/>["It is not the purpose of this book to condemn, condone or to accept the Black Arts, but to set forth some facts which have been hidden deep 
							in volumes on shelves of libraries, and hidden even deeper in court records."] off the walls photography and captions – must reproduce </p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">2</container>
						<unitdate>1971</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">A Study of The Sexual Man: Book Two</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname><lb/>Pseudonym: <persname>	Frank Leonard with Dr. T. K. Peters</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	191	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	SECS Press,	Los Angeles<lb/>Photo Illustrated (color/b&amp;w)<lb/>"Sex Education Clinical Series vol. XXXIII"
							<lb/>["Who is the sexual man? What special qualities does he possess that other men don't have? Can you become a sexual man?
							These are all questions that this book will answer."]</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">2</container>
						<unitdate>1971</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">A Study of The Sexual Woman: Book Two</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname><lb/>Pseudonym: <persname>	Mandy Merrill with Dr. T. K. Peters</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	191	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	SECS Press,	Los Angeles<lb/>Photo Illustrated (color/b&amp;w)
							<lb/>"Sex Education Clinical Series vol. XXXI"<lb/>"[Wood and Charles Anderson (Outlaws of the Old West), wrote and directed twelve 8mm films for SECS in 1975]
							possibly scan photo with captions
						</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">2</container>
						<unitdate>1971</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">A Study of the Sons and Daughters of Erotica</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname><lb/>Pseudonym: <persname>	compiled by Dick Trent with Dr. T. K. Peters</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	192	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	SECS Press,	Los Angeles<lb/>Photo Illustrated (color/b&amp;w)<lb/>"Sex Education Clinical Series vol. XXVIII"<lb/>[Akin to EDUSEX, 
							more pornography in the guise of education, ‘...as a pictorial and editorial representation of phases and mores in our contemporary society.’  
							Most likely SECS was Calga Publishers since they shared the same 5585 W. Pico address.  As suggested elsewhere also probably the same as Pendulum. 
							Bibliography includes: Criswell Predicts by Criswell, Black Myth by Trent and Peters (Ed Wood) (listed as Pendulum 1971 in bibliography, listed as 
							SECS 1971 in copy), Glen or Glenda (Wood movie), Satanic Bible by LaVey, and more.]</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">2</container>
						<unitdate>1971</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">A Study of the Swappers</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname><lb/>Pseudonym: <persname>	S. T. Lee with Dr. T. K. Peters</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	192	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	SECS Press,	Los Angeles<lb/>Photo Illustrated (color/b&amp;w)<lb/>"Sex Education Clinical Series vol. XXVII"</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">2</container>
						<unitdate>1971</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">Black Myth</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname><lb/>Pseudonym: <persname>	Dick Trent with Dr. T. K. Peters</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	192	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	SECS Press,	Los Angeles<lb/>Photo Illustrated (color/b&amp;w)<lb/>"Sex Education Clinical Series vol. XXII"
							<lb/>["A detailed analysis of the sexual and sociological misinformation surrounding black sexuality."  
							It was suggested by reported ex-Pendulum/Calga writer Leo Eaton, that Dr. T. K. Peters was in fact actually a real card-carrying doctor, 
							his website relays: "Pendulum had bought a serious, boring and excruciatingly long scientific study of sexuality from Dr. T. K. Peters. 
							It was an unpublished manuscript that the doctor had probably labored on for years without finding a buyer (he was a Kinsey-style researcher). 
							I hate to think what he was paid – probably peanuts – but he was very old (semi-senile was the word around the office) 
							and he’d let it go without realizing what use would be made of it. The manuscript gave Bernie [Bloom] a sort of ‘semi-legitimacy’ 
							for the books and magazine articles and we were all encouraged to make use of it whenever and wherever possible. Adding Dr. Peter’s name as co-writer 
							added a spurious legitimacy." (http://www.eatoncreative.com/memories/working-with-ed-wood-jr.php)   </p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">2</container>
						<unitdate>1971</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">The Cat's Urge</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname><lb/>Pseudonym: <persname>	Elliot Parker Ph.D.,</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	160	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Echelon Book Publishers, Inc.,	Los Angeles
							<lb/>[Contains salacious sexological case histories of female abandon - swapping, drunken sex, adulterous behavior, fetishes, and more.  
							Page 24: "The room began to smell like a whorehouse on dollar day.  Frantic, hot bodies give off a real musky smell when they’re in a close space.  
							And that apartment was like a closet.  Hell, I could have reached out and patted Benny on the butt."  Page 89: "While the majority of housewives 
							enter the forbidden world of animalism out of a profound despair, this is not an iron rule."  While much of Wood’s approaches to African-American 
							life are out and out racist, his views of Near Eastern sex practices seem to tend more towards a comical and prurient Orientalism, offensive and ignorant, 
							but tethered to an archetypal Rohmer-esque mythological world of sexist warriors, most certainly inspired by his fascination with the exotic and supernatural.  
							Yet, as opposed to Sax Rohmer, there is little awe and literary eloquence to counteract the reductions of the Other.  Rather the notion of a misogynist Arab, 
							painted as a savage and conquering force, is the primary abstraction of the Arab race with Wood.  This point of view is apparent during a discussion of Arab 
							sodomy on pages 136-7: "The Arab now straddled the American girl, and then his powerful maleness was at the entranceway.  ‘It is the way of the East, 
							my little love-slave.’  WIth [sic] that, he invaded.  There was some sphincter tightening.  Suddenly a gurgled shriek was heard as the American girl tried 
							to push him off [...] The sex-perverted Arab was now bearing down on her as if she were some animal, some beast.  She had always heard that these savage Arabs 
							were like that, but she never knew they were so brutal.  Now, a shock wave of pain tore through her narrow receptacle.  Suddenly, Ahman erupted in some erotic 
							sounding gibberish.  Then, he immersed himself "to the hilt" and there was a stiffening [...] Ahman’s stiffening was rigid.  Then the gushing proof of his peak 
							flooded Valerie’s soul until she was transformed into little more than a sexual slave [...] Wordlessly, he went to the bathroom and washed himself.  
							When he came out, bronzed and naked with his flaccid power a symbol of his superiority, he flashed a grin at her.  ‘This is how we use our women in the East.’"]
						</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">2</container>
						<unitdate>1972</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">Mary-Go-Round</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	191	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Little Library Press,	Atlanta<lb/>[similar to Carnival Piece but more explicit as LLP tended to be.]</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">2</container>
						<unitdate>1973</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">Diary of a Transvestite Hooker</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname><lb/>Pseudonym: <persname>	Randy, as told to Dick Trent</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	182	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Eros Publishing Co.,	Wilmington, Del. <lb/>Photo Illustrated (b&amp;w)
							<lb/>[an Eros Goldstripe production, a telling of escapades in the life of transvestite hooker, told in the pictorial style.  
							Page 173: "Summation – One might ask the question: ‘Why the life of a prostitute?’ of any number of prostitutes and there would be just as many, 
							individually different answers...but their answers might not be considered true answers by the sociologists, sexologists and psychiatrists, 
							because the girls themselves don’t have any true answers for themselves and why they first decided upon the profession.  
							But the answers they give have some measure of truth, because those answers are what they believe."  
							Page 177: "Thus it is with whores who would also like to glamorize their profession...and make a lot of money from their books in doing so...
							there is always a ready market for the lurid stories they reveal...imagined or otherwise...a madam, or working prostitute wrote it, therefore 
							everything she says must be true...she lived through it.  The public as well as the publisher will savor this type of material.  
							If they were to paint their profession and what they did as some sort of dirty episode in history, then they themselves must have been dirty.  
							Therefore...picture me pink..."] 
						</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">2</container>
						<unitdate>1973</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">Outlaws of the Old West</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Charles D. Anderson (ed.), Edward D. Wood, Jr. (contrib.)</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	253	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Mankind Publishing Company,	Los Angeles<lb/>Ilustrated (photo/drawing)
							<lb/>The Mankind Series of Great Adventures of History<lb/>["Selected Readings By Mankind Magazine", 
							contains the story "Pearl Hart and the Last Stage".  Non-pornographic work in the Western genre.  
							Tells the tale of Pearl Hart, a girl who dressed as a boy and became a famous stagecoach robber.  
							Page 232:  "She would have still been in the boys clothes she wore during the robbery, 
							bedraggled form those days in the sale and the elements of the weather, frightened to death of the crowd which she faced." 
							Page 234:  "Although Joe Boot slipped quickly into obscurity shortly after Sheriff Truman brought the outlaw pair into Florence, 
							the pistol and rifle-toting Pearl was just beginning to live, to be recognized, and to find her place in history.  
							And what she didn’t conjure up in her own mind was created by the newspaper accounts of her daring adventure into the badman’s territory.  
							Altogether, these made her break out in the cold sweats of fame." Page 235:  "She had a year of ecstatic glory with the cheers of 
							the public ringing in her ears.  And then night after night the audience became thinner and thinner.  The fickle public soon tires 
							of even its most important heroes."] 
						</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">2</container>
						<unitdate>1973</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">Tales for a Sexy Night Vol. 2</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Chuck Kelly (ed.)</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	160	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Gallery Press,	Los Angeles<lb/>Illustrated by Neil Weisbecker
							<lb/>[contains stories by Edw. D. Wood, Jr., "Final Curtain", "To Kill a Saturday Night" 
							(this one is a Beckett-esque masterpiece, should be excerpted), "Craps", and "Calamity Jane Loves Hosenose Kate Loves Cattle Anne".  
							Also includes a contribution from collaborator Charles D. Anderson.] </p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">2</container>
						<unitdate>1977</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">TV Lust</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname><lb/>Pseudonym: <persname>	Dick Trent</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	180	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Eros Publishing Co.,	Wilmington, Del. <lb/>Photo Illustrated (b&amp;w)<lb/>Transexual Library
							<lb/>[Written a year before his death, Hayes describes "The rigors of writing smut were definitely telling on Wood at this point.  
							The rehashed plot of the transvestite hitman certainly wasn’t original this time around, and the usual colorful characters are almost nonexistent.  
							The flair that made some of his other novels and films bearable, even through a thin plot and the strange grammar, was noticeably absent from TV Lust.  
							It seems as though Ed Wood had finally given up."  Page 40: "Chris slipped into the fur-like coat, and he was ready for his first walk on the street in girl’s clothes...
							he was elated nearly to the point of exploding...Chris mixed another pitcher of martinis and this time had poured a double before he went back to the big chair.  
							The pistol lay on the floor near the attaché case.  He liked the idea of the fur coat on the bed, it was going to be just as cold that night as it had been that October so long ago."]
						</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<container type="box">2</container>
						<unitdate>1995</unitdate>
						<unittitle><emph render="underline">Let Me Die in Drag</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname></unittitle>
						<physdesc>Pages: 	172	</physdesc>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Publisher: 	Gorse,	London<lb/>[modern reprint of Pad Library’s Let Me Die in Drag] 
						</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>


			</c01>

			<c01 level="series">
				<did>
					<unittitle id="s2">Series II. Magazines and Other Published Material</unittitle>
				</did>

				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="map-case">Z-17</container>
						<unitdate>1953</unitdate>
						<unittitle>"Glen or Glenda?", movie poster</unittitle>
					</did>
				</c02>
				
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="map-case">Z-17</container>
						<unitdate>1971</unitdate>
						<unittitle>"The Undergraduate", movie poster</unittitle>
					</did>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="box">3</container>
						<container type="folder">1</container>
						<unitdate>1968</unitdate>
						<unittitle><title>Fetish in Films</title> No. 1</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Includes an image taken from "For Love and Money"</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="box">3</container>
						<container type="folder">2</container>
						<unitdate>Feb. 1969</unitdate>
						<unittitle><title>Caper</title> Vol. 13 No. 8</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Includes the article "Guilding The Ghouls" discussing the "ghoulie flick"</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="box">3</container>
						<container type="folder">3</container>
						<unitdate>Aug./Sept. 1971</unitdate>
						<unittitle><title>Case Histories</title> Vol. 2 No. 2</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Includes "A Nation of Peepers" by Norman Bates (pseudonym)</p>
						<p>Includes "The Day the Mummy Returned" by Edward D. Wood, Jr.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="box">3</container>
						<container type="folder">4</container>
						<unitdate>Aug./Sept. 1971</unitdate>
						<unittitle><title>Pendulum</title> Vol. 3 No. 3</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Includes "Into My Grave" by Edward D. Wood, Jr.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="box">3</container>
						<container type="folder">5</container>
						<unitdate>Aug./Sept. 1971</unitdate>
						<unittitle><title>Lezo</title> Vol. 5 No. 3</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Includes "The Night the Banshee Cried" by Edward D. Wood, Jr.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="box">3</container>
						<container type="folder">6</container>
						<unitdate>Nov./Dec. 1971</unitdate>
						<unittitle><title>Belly Button</title> Vol. 2 No. 3</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Includes "The Wave Off" by Edward D. Wood, Jr.</p>
						<p>Includes "Sex and the Future" by Norman Bates (pseudonym)q</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="box">3</container>
						<container type="folder">7</container>
						<unitdate>Jan. 1972</unitdate>
						<unittitle><title>Horror Sex Tales</title> Vol. 1 No. 1</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Includes "Hellfire" by Edward D. Wood, Jr.</p>
						<p>Includes "Scream Your Bloody Head Off" by Edward D. Wood, Jr.</p>
						<p>Includes "The Rue Morgue Re-visited: by Dick Trent (pseudonym)</p>
						<p>Includes "Witches of Amau Ra" by Dick Trent (pseudonym)</p>
						<p>Includes "Bums Rush Terror" by Ann Gora (pseudonym)</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="box">3</container>
						<container type="folder">8</container>
						<unitdate>Mar./Apr. 1972</unitdate>
						<unittitle><title>Suck-Em-Up</title> Vol. 2 No. 1</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Includes " 'You Gotta' Have A Fetish' 'You Gotta' Have A Gimmick' " by Ann Gora (pseudonym)</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="box">3</container>
						<container type="folder">9</container>
						<unitdate>Apr./May 1972</unitdate>
						<unittitle><title>Savage Sex</title> Vol. 4 No. 2</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Includes "The Responsibility Game" by Dick Trent (pseudonym)</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="box">3</container>
						<container type="folder">10</container>
						<unitdate>July/Aug. 1972</unitdate>
						<unittitle><title>Body and Soul</title> Vol. 6 No. 2</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Includes "Scene of the Crime" by Edward D. Wood, Jr.</p>
						<p>Includes "What Would We Have Done Without Them?" by Edward D. Wood, Jr.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="box">3</container>
						<container type="folder">11</container>
						<unitdate>July/Aug. 1972</unitdate>
						<unittitle><title>Weird Sex Tales</title> Vol. 1 No. 1</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Includes "Ant Hell" by Alvin Tostig (pseudonym)</p>
						<p>Includes "News Read-Out" edited by Norman Bates (pseudonym)</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="box">3</container>
						<container type="folder">12</container>
						<unitdate>Aug./Sept. 1972</unitdate>
						<unittitle><title>Monster Sex Tales</title> Vol. 1 No. 1</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Includes "Castle of Dracula" by Chester Winfield (probable pseudonym)</p>
						<p>Includes "The Voyage of Dracula" by Roy Hemp (probable pseudonym)</p>
						<p>Includes "Lust of the Vampire" by Dudley McDonly (probable pseudonym)</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="box">3</container>
						<container type="folder">13</container>
						<unitdate>Sept./Oct. 1972</unitdate>
						<unittitle><title>Legendary Sex Tales</title> Vol. 1 No. 1</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Includes "Cleopatra's Sex Slave" by Dudley McDonly (probable pseudonym)</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="box">3</container>
						<container type="folder">14</container>
						<unitdate>Sept./Oct. 1972</unitdate>
						<unittitle><title>Orgy</title> Vol. 4 No. 2</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Includes "The Core of Vampire" by Ann Gora (pseudonym)</p>
						<p>Includes "Slap It To 'Em" by Dick Trent (pseudonym)</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="box">3</container>
						<container type="folder">15</container>
						<unitdate>Jan./Feb. 1973</unitdate>
						<unittitle><title>Orgy</title> Vol. 5 No. 1</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Includes "A Taste of Blood" by Edward D. Wood, Jr.</p>
						<p>Includes "Seek and Ye Shall Find" by Dick Trent (pseudonym)</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="box">3</container>
						<container type="folder">16</container>
						<unitdate>Jan./Feb. 1973</unitdate>
						<unittitle><title>Hellcats</title> Vol. 2 No. 1</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Includes "Trade Secrets" by Shirlee Lane (pseudonym)</p>
						<p>Includes "Lesbian Understanding" by Ann Gora (pseudonym)</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="box">3</container>
						<container type="folder">17</container>
						<unitdate>Jan./Feb. 1973</unitdate>
						<unittitle><title>Swap</title> Vol. 7 No. 1</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Includes "The Divorcee's Problem" by Ann Gora (pseudonym)</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="box">3</container>
						<container type="folder">18</container>
						<unitdate>June/July 1973</unitdate>
						<unittitle><title>Turn On</title> Vol. 2 No. 3</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Includes "The Creeping Sexation" edited by Edward D. Wood, Jr.</p>
						<p>Includes "Why a Prostitute's Life" by Dick Trent (pseudonym)</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="box">3</container>
						<container type="folder">19</container>
						<unitdate>May/June 1975</unitdate>
						<unittitle><title>Body and Soul</title> Vol. 8 No. 1</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Includes "What Would We Have Done Without Them?" by Edward D. Wood, Jr.</p>
						<p>Includes "Scene of the Crime" by Edward D. Wood, Jr.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="box">3</container>
						<container type="folder">20</container>
						<unitdate>1975?</unitdate>
						<unittitle><title>Body and Soul</title> Annual</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Includes "The Home Scene" by Edward D. Wood, Jr.</p>
						<p>Includes "Scene of the Crime" by Edward D. Wood, Jr.</p>
						<p>Includes "What Would We Have Done Without Them?" by Edward D. Wood, Jr.</p>
						<p>Includes "The Sport of Bored Lovers" by Norman Bates (pseudonym)</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="box">3</container>
						<container type="folder">21</container>
						<unitdate>Dec. 1976</unitdate>
						<unittitle><title>Ace</title> Vol. 21 No. 6</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Includes "Sheep in Wolf's Clothing" by Edward Wood</p>
						<p>Includes "How Erotica Turns Her On" by William P. Evans (pseudonym)</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="box">3</container>
						<container type="folder">22</container>
						<unitdate>June 1998</unitdate>
						<unittitle><title>Femme Fatales</title> Vol. 7 No. 1</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Includes "Orgy of the Dead Ed Wood's Post- "Plan 9" Legacy: Bonding Spirits and Strippers-in Color!" by Laura Schiff</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="box">3</container>
						<container type="folder">23</container>
						<unitdate>1999</unitdate>
						<unittitle><title>Outre</title> No. 16</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>Includes "From Ed Wood to Elvis! The Incredible Saga of Dolores Fuller" by Greg Douglas</p>
						<p>Includes "Hollywood Rat Race! How to Make a Cheap Picture and Fail" by Ed Wood, Jr.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				
			</c01>

			<c01 level="series">
				<did>
					<unittitle id="s3">Series III. Exhibition Material</unittitle>
				</did>

				<c02 level="subseries">
					<did>            
						<unittitle id="s3ss1">Print Outs</unittitle>
					</did>
					
					<c03>
						<did>
							<container type="box">4</container>
							<container type="folder">1</container>
							<unittitle>Ace Magazine</unittitle>
						</did>
					</c03>
					<c03>
						<did>
							<container type="box">4</container>
							<container type="folder">2</container>
							<unittitle>A Study of Censorship, Sex, and the Movies bk.2</unittitle>
						</did>
					</c03><c03>
						<did>
							<container type="box">4</container>
							<container type="folder">3</container>
							<unittitle>A Study of Sexual Practices and Witchcraft v.1 and v.2</unittitle>
						</did>
					</c03>
					<c03>
						<did>
							<container type="box">4</container>
							<container type="folder">4</container>
							<unittitle>A Study of Stag Films</unittitle>
						</did>
					</c03>
					<c03>
						<did>
							<container type="box">4</container>
							<container type="folder">5</container>
							<unittitle>Bellybutton Magazine</unittitle>
						</did>
					</c03>
					<c03>
						<did>
							<container type="box">4</container>
							<container type="folder">6</container>
							<unittitle>Body and Soul Magazine</unittitle>
						</did>
					</c03>
					<c03>
						<did>
							<container type="box">4</container>
							<container type="folder">7</container>
							<unittitle>Bye Bye Broadie</unittitle>
						</did>
					</c03>
					<c03>
						<did>
							<container type="box">4</container>
							<container type="folder">8</container>
							<unittitle>Glen or Glenda</unittitle>
						</did>
					</c03>
					<c03>
						<did>
							<container type="box">4</container>
							<container type="folder">9</container>
							<unittitle>Horror Sex Tales Magazine</unittitle>
						</did>
					</c03>
					<c03>
						<did>
							<container type="box">4</container>
							<container type="folder">10</container>
							<unittitle>Monster Sex Tales Magazine</unittitle>
						</did>
					</c03>
					<c03>
						<did>
							<container type="box">4</container>
							<container type="folder">11</container>
							<unittitle>Orgy of the Dead</unittitle>
						</did>
					</c03>
					<c03>
						<did>
							<container type="box">4</container>
							<container type="folder">12</container>
							<unittitle>Sleeze Paperbacks</unittitle>
						</did>
					</c03>
					<c03>
						<did>
							<container type="box">4</container>
							<container type="folder">13</container>
							<unittitle>Tales for a Sexy Night</unittitle>
						</did>
					</c03>
					<c03>
						<did>
							<container type="box">4</container>
							<container type="folder">14</container>
							<unittitle>The Book of the Sexual Woman, The Book of the Sexual Man</unittitle>
						</did>
					</c03>
					<c03>
						<did>
							<container type="box">4</container>
							<container type="folder">15</container>
							<unittitle>The Erotic Spy</unittitle>
						</did>
					</c03>
					<c03>
						<did>
							<container type="box">4</container>
							<container type="folder">16</container>
							<unittitle>The Sons and Daughters of Erotica</unittitle>
						</did>
					</c03>
					<c03>
						<did>
							<container type="box">4</container>
							<container type="folder">17</container>
							<unittitle>Various Magazine Printouts</unittitle>
						</did>
					</c03>
					<c03>
						<did>
							<container type="box">4</container>
							<container type="folder">18</container>
							<unittitle>Various Novel Printouts</unittitle>
						</did>
					</c03>
					<c03>
						<did>
							<container type="box">4</container>
							<container type="folder">19</container>
							<unittitle>Weird Sex Tales Magazine</unittitle>
						</did>
					</c03>
					
				</c02>
				<c02 level="subseries">
					<did>            
						<unittitle id="s3ss2">Drafts</unittitle>
					</did>
				
					<c03>
						<did>
							<container type="box">4</container>
							<container type="folder">20</container>
							<unittitle>Catalogue Drafts</unittitle>
						</did>
					</c03>
					<c03>
						<did>
							<container type="box">4</container>
							<container type="folder">21</container>
							<unittitle>Research Writing Drafts</unittitle>
						</did>
					</c03>
					<c03>
						<did>
							<container type="box">4</container>
							<container type="folder">22</container>
							<unittitle>Text Drafts</unittitle>
						</did>
					</c03>
				</c02>
				<c02>
					<did>
						<container type="box">4</container>
						<unittitle>Exhibit Placards</unittitle>
					</did>
				</c02>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="series">
				<did>
					<unittitle id="s4">Series IV. Films</unittitle>
				</did>
				<c02 level="item">
					<did>
						<unitid>DVD-2348</unitid>
						<unitdate>Date unknown</unitdate>
						<unittitle>"The Incredibly Strange Film Show, volume 3: Ed Wood"</unittitle>
					</did>
				</c02>
			</c01>
		</dsc>
		
		<separatedmaterial>
			<head>SEPARATED MATERIAL</head>
			<p>The following materials have been separated from the collection. Some have been cataloged individually:</p>
			<p><emph render="underline">A Study of Fetishes &amp; Fantasies</emph><lb/>By: <persname>Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname><lb/>Pseudonym: <persname>Norman Bates &amp; Dick Trent</persname>
				<lb/>Location: Human Sexuality HQ57.3 .W77 1973
				<lb/>Pages: 191 Published: 1971
				<lb/>[indicative of the fast and loose publishing culture: though the outer boards attribute the book to Wood &amp; Bates, 
				inside title page attributes "by Norman Bates &amp; Dick Trent".  Bibliography of this "educational" book cites a myriad of sources including Freud, 
				Krafft-Ebing, Stekel, and Theodore Sturgeon.]
			</p>
			<p><emph render="underline">A Study in the Motivation of Censorship, Sex &amp; The Movies: Book I</emph><lb/>By: <persname>	Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname>
				<lb/>Location: Human Sexuality PN1995.9.S45 S89 1973 bk.1
				<lb/>Pages: 190 Published: 1973
				<lb/>[the EDUSEX Press imprint under Gallery was similar to SECS in that in provided an educational guise for pornography that made it exempt from 
				obscenity prosecution, this "study" in particular allowed Wood to flex his knowledge of the film world.  Preface reads: "The President’s Commission 
				on Obscenity and Pornography has found that the law ‘is not the only or necessarily the most effective way’ to deal with pornography.  The report 
				recommends a massive and extensive sex education program to blunt the American’s taste for smut and to forge an informed public consensus on the 
				problem."]
			</p>
			<p><emph render="underline">A Study in the Motivation of Censorship, Sex &amp; The Movies: Book II</emph><lb/>By: <persname>Edward D. Wood, Jr.</persname>
				<lb/>Location: Human Sexuality PN1995.9.S45 S89 1973 bk.2
				<lb/>Pages: 191 Published: 1973
				<lb/>[sequel to Censorship, Sex, &amp; The Movies: Book 1]
			</p>
		</separatedmaterial>
		
	</archdesc>
</ead>
