<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../styles/style.xsl" ?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
<eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1"
scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
<eadid mainagencycode="nic" countrycode="us"
publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections//TEXT(US::NIC::RMM08492m::Guide to the Beracha ve Shalom at Joden Savanna - Suriname collection)//EN"
>RMM08492m.xml</eadid>
<filedesc>
<titlestmt>
<titleproper>Guide to the Beracha ve Shalom at Joden Savanna - Suriname collection.
<date/></titleproper>
<titleproper type="sort">Beracha ve Shalom at Joden Savanna - Suriname collection</titleproper>
<author>Compiled by RMC Staff</author>
</titlestmt>
<publicationstmt>
<publisher>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University
Library</publisher>
<date>February 2015</date>
</publicationstmt>
<notestmt>
<note audience="internal">
<p><subject>relig</subject></p>
</note>
</notestmt>
</filedesc>
<profiledesc>
<creation>Finding aid encoded by RMC Staff, <date>February 2015</date></creation>
</profiledesc>
</eadheader>
<frontmatter>
<titlepage>
<titleproper>Guide to the Beracha Ve Shalom At Joden Savanna - Suriname.<lb/><date
type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f"/></titleproper>
<num>Collection Number: 8492m</num>
<publisher>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections <lb/>Cornell University
Library</publisher>
<list type="deflist">
<defitem>
<label>Contact Information:</label>
<item> Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections<lb/> 2B Carl A. Kroch
Library<lb/> Cornell University<lb/> Ithaca, NY 14853<lb/> (607)
255-3530<lb/> Fax: (607) 255-9524<lb/><extref
href="mailto:rareref@cornell.edu"
>rareref@cornell.edu</extref><lb/><extref
href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu"
>http://rmc.library.cornell.edu</extref><lb/></item>
</defitem>
<defitem>
<label>Compiled by:</label>
<item>RMC Staff</item>
</defitem>
<defitem>
<label>Date completed:</label>
<item>February 2015</item>
</defitem>
<defitem>
<label>EAD encoding:</label>
<item>RMC Staff, February 2015</item>
</defitem>
<defitem>
<label>Date modified:</label>
<item>RMC Staff, February 2015</item>
</defitem>
</list>
<date>© 2014 Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University
Library</date>
</titlepage>
</frontmatter>
<archdesc level="collection">
<did>
<head id="a1">DESCRIPTIVE SUMMARY</head>
<unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="MARC 245">Beracha ve Shalom at Joden Savanna -
Suriname collection. </unittitle>
<unitid label="Collection Number:">8492m</unitid>

	<physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="MARC 300">1 folder</physdesc>
<physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Photographs, printed material, publications</physdesc>
<repository label="Repository:">Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell
University Library</repository>
	<abstract label="Abstract:">Photographs and printed material relating to the synagogue.</abstract>
<langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="041"
langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial>
</did>
	<scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520"> 
		<head id="a3">COLLECTION DESCRIPTION</head> 
		<p>Photographs and printed material relating to the synagogue, published in Paramaribo, Surinam.</p> 
	</scopecontent> 
<controlaccess>
<head id="a7">SUBJECTS</head>

<controlaccess>
<head>Subjects:</head>
<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Jews -- Surinam.</subject>
</controlaccess>
</controlaccess>
<descgrp>
<head id="a8">INFORMATION FOR USERS</head>
<prefercite>
<head>Cite As:</head>
	<p>Beracha ve Shalom at Joden Savanna - Suriname collection, #8492m, Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library.</p>
</prefercite>
</descgrp>

<dsc type="combined">
<head>CONTAINER LIST</head>
<c01 level="series">
<did>
<container type="folder">1</container>
	<unittitle>Documents</unittitle>
</did><c02 level="item">
						<did>	<unittitle>	Description of the “Restoration of Jewish Savannah”</unittitle></did></c02>
							<c02 level="item">
								<did>		<unittitle>Article from “De West Van Woensdag” (9 Maart 1966) titled “Restauratie van Joden Savanna, Hof van Justitie en Huis van Bewaring” (“Restoration of the Jewish Savanah…”)</unittitle></did></c02>
									<c02 level="item">
										<did>		<unittitle>Paper in Hebrew which appears to be about the synagogue</unittitle> </did></c02>
											<c02 level="item">
												<did>		<unittitle>“Plan to reconstruct the Synagogue Beracha ve Shalom at Joden Savanna – Suriname” booklet</unittitle></did><scopecontent><p>Contents:<lb/>
													<lb/>1. Illustration of the elevation by direction
													<lb/>2. Breakdown of each section of the synagogue, focus on the outside
													<lb/>3. Breakdown of the synagogue’s interior
													<lb/>4. Plan of the synagogue, cemetery marked
													<lb/>5. Location of the synagogue in relation to the Suriname River
													<lb/>6. Estimate of the Reconstruction of the synagogue “Beracha ve Shalon” at Joden Savanna
													<lb/>7. Photos – 1U copy 2 “remainder, North-elevation”; 1Y copy 2 “remainder, West-elevation”; 1Z copy 2 “detail of a tomb-stone”; four photos showing the details of a tombstone with Hebrew writing, two winged children, a skull and crossbones, and other imagery 
	
												</p></scopecontent></c02></c01>
	<c01 level="series">
		<did>
			<container type="folder">1</container>	
<unittitle>Photographs</unittitle>
</did>
<c02 level="item"><did><unitid label="Photo #: ">1A</unitid><unittitle>“Gezicht op de Joden Savanne“ – Naar een teekening uit den atlas behoorende bij het werk van M. D. Teenstra  „De Landbouw in de kolonie Suriname“, 1835 (– “View of the Jewish Savannah,“ taken from the work of M. D. Teenstra, “Agriculture in the colony of Suriname“); shows two houses on a hill, one figure seated on a log</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02 level="item"><did><unitid label="Photo #: ">1B</unitid><unittitle>“Paramaribo“, Augusta Currel; illustration of the capital of Suriname, flat boats with two figures each, houses on hills in the distance</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02 level="item"><did><unitid label="Photo #: ">1C</unitid><unittitle>“De Joden-Savanne“ (“The Jewish-Savannah“); “Synagogue“ written in the corner, illustrartion with two boats, small houses and figures on the shore</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02 level="item"><did><unitid label="Photo #: ">1D</unitid><unittitle>unlabeled; uneven field with stakes driven into the ground leading to a house in the distance, trees (including palm trees) breach the horizon</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02 level="item"><did><unitid label="Photo #: ">1E</unitid><unittitle>unlabeled;  three boats, each with figures, one with two sails, the others with oars; several hills with houses, some on stilts.</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02 level="item"><did><unitid label="Photo #: ">1F</unitid><unittitle>unlabeled; two figures gazing at another figure gesturing toward a child; an overhang of wood and some foliage is nestled among rocky slopes, trees behind.</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02 level="item"><did><unitid label="Photo #: ">1G</unitid><unittitle>“View of the Settlement called the Jews‘ Savannah“; two figures conversing in shadow, one seated, one reclining; behind are boats on a river and houses on a hill</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02 level="item"><did><unitid label="Photo #: ">1H</unitid><unittitle>Three figures, two reclining and one holding spears;, beside a tree; a house to their left; other houses and a review before</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02 level="item"><did><unitid label="Photo #: ">1I</unitid><unittitle>“Begraafplaats, Joden-Savanne-Suriname“ “( “Cemetary, Jewish-Savannah-Suriname“); a map of the cemetary marking graves; several graves have their iconography illustrated</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02 level="item"><did><unitid label="Photo #: ">1J</unitid><unittitle>“Post Gelderland en Joden Savannah“ (“Gelderland [Province] in the Jewish Savannah“); appears to be a more detailed version of 1B</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02 level="item"><did><unitid label="Photo #: ">1K</unitid><unittitle>“Joden Savannah“ – Gezigt op de Sunagoge en Kerkhof Van de Zude van het Militair Cordonpad Gezien (“Jewish-Savannah“-  Sight of the synogague and graveyard...); appears to be a more detailed version of 1D</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02 level="item"><did><unitid label="Photo #: ">1L</unitid><unittitle>from Voorbetere foto‘s, Boschman‘s foto studio, Waaldijkstraat 8, Tel. 3718, no title; holy Ark of the synagogue with covered Torah scrolls, candles, and a chandalier; synogague has a sand floor</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02 level="item"><did><unitid label="Photo #: ">1M</unitid><unittitle>from Voorbetere foto‘s, Boschman‘s foto studio, Waaldijkstraat 8, Tel. 3718, no title; same photo as 1L except with a man in the lower right (white shirt, black tie, yamaka)</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02 level="item"><did><unitid label="Photo #: ">1N</unitid><unittitle>from Voorbetere foto‘s, Boschman‘s foto studio, Waaldijkstraat 8, Tel. 3718, no title; wider view of the synagogue (benches, at least four chandaliers) , man (white shirt, yamaka) standing in the center</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02 level="item"><did><unitid label="Photo #: ">1O</unitid><unittitle>from Voorbetere foto‘s, Boschman‘s foto studio, Waaldijkstraat 8, Tel. 3718, no title; close-up of chandalier in the synagogue</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02 level="item"><did><unitid label="Photo #: ">1P</unitid><unittitle>from Voorbetere foto‘s, Boschman‘s foto studio, Waaldijkstraat 8, Tel. 3718, no title; close-up of standing candle-holder in the synogague</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02 level="item"><did><unitid label="Photo #: ">1Q</unitid><unittitle>from Voorbetere foto‘s, Boschman‘s foto studio, Waaldijkstraat 8, Tel. 3718, no title; similar to 1L but with Ark closed</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02 level="item"><did><unitid label="Photo #: ">1R</unitid><unittitle>from Voorbetere foto‘s, Boschman‘s foto studio, Waaldijkstraat 8, Tel. 3718, no title; close  up of chandalier in the synogague</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02 level="item"><did><unitid label="Photo #: ">1S</unitid><unittitle>P.J. Benoit: Voyage à Surinam, Bruxelles; No. 43: Village habité par des Juifs sur la rivière de Surinam (Lithographie van Lauters) (P.J. Benoit: Trip to Surinam, Brussels; No. 43: village inhabited by the Jewish people on the Surinam river); small houses on hills, figures on the path, river in the distance</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02 level="item"><did><unitid label="Photo #: ">1T</unitid><unittitle>PP3: J26.PN4; Suriname. (other writing cannot be made out completely); plants growing over smooth surface</unittitle></did></c02>
		<c02 level="item"><did><unitid label="Photo #: ">1U</unitid><unittitle>Remainder, North-elevation. Bureau Voor Architectuur en Stedebouw Van Oerle en Schrama, Paramaribo – Suriname (Office of Architecture and Urban Planning...Paramaribo – Suriname); ruined building, steps overgrown with grass</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02 level="item"><did><unitid label="Photo #: ">1V</unitid><unittitle>Bureau Voor Architectuur en Stedebouw Van Oerle en Schrama, Paramaribo – Suriname (Office of Architecture and Urban Planning...Paramaribo – Suriname); ruined building, wall with holes and overgrown with grass</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02 level="item"><did><unitid label="Photo #: ">1W</unitid><unittitle>Bureau Voor Architectuur en Stedebouw Van Oerle en Schrama, Paramaribo – Suriname (Office of Architecture and Urban Planning...Paramaribo – Suriname); ruined building, wall collapsed with grass growing through the bricks</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02 level="item"><did><unitid label="Photo #: ">1X</unitid><unittitle>Bureau Voor Architectuur en Stedebouw Van Oerle en Schrama, Paramaribo – Suriname (Office of Architecture and Urban Planning...Paramaribo – Suriname); ruined building, steps overgrown with grass</unittitle></did></c02>
		<c02 level="item"><did><unitid label="Photo #: ">1Y</unitid><unittitle>Remainder, West-elevation. Bureau Voor Architectuur en Stedebouw Van Oerle en Schrama, Paramaribo – Suriname (Office of Architecture and Urban Planning...Paramaribo – Suriname); ruined building, close up of steps overgrown with grass</unittitle></did></c02>
		<c02 level="item"><did><unitid label="Photo #: ">1Z</unitid><unittitle>Detail of a tomb-stone. Bureau Voor Architectuur en Stedebouw Van Oerle en Schrama, Paramaribo – Suriname (Office of Architecture and Urban Planning...Paramaribo – Suriname [stamp faded, but it appears to be the same as the other photos); carving of hand holding axe and cutting off tree, encircled with engraving of leaves</unittitle></did></c02>

</c01>
</dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
