<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../styles/style.xsl" ?>
			<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
	<eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1"
		scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
		<eadid mainagencycode="nic" countrycode="us"
			publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections//TEXT(US::NIC::RMM08418::Guide to the Paul Fishbeck menu collection)//EN"
			>RMM08418.xml</eadid>
		<filedesc>
			<titlestmt>
				<titleproper>Guide to the Paul Fishbeck menu
					collection,<date>1955-2015</date></titleproper>
				<titleproper type="sort">Fisbeck, Paul menu collection</titleproper>
				<author>Compiled by RMC Staff</author>
			</titlestmt>
			<publicationstmt>
				<publisher>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University
					Library</publisher>
				<date>September 2013</date>
			</publicationstmt>
			<notestmt>
				<note audience="internal">
					<p><subject>finart</subject></p>
				</note>
			</notestmt>
		</filedesc>
		<profiledesc>
			<creation>Finding aid encoded by RMC Staff, <date>September 2013</date></creation>
		</profiledesc>
	</eadheader>
	<frontmatter>
		<titlepage>
			<titleproper>Guide to the Paul Fishbeck Menu Collection,<lb/><date type="inclusive"
					encodinganalog="245$f">1955-2015</date></titleproper>
			<num>Collection Number: 8418 </num>
			<publisher>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections <lb/>Cornell University
				Library</publisher>
			<list type="deflist">
				<defitem>
					<label>Contact Information:</label>
					<item> Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections<lb/> 2B Carl A. Kroch
						Library<lb/> Cornell University<lb/> Ithaca, NY 14853<lb/> (607)
						255-3530<lb/> Fax: (607) 255-9524<lb/><extref
							href="mailto:rareref@cornell.edu"
							>rareref@cornell.edu</extref><lb/><extref
							href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu"
							>http://rmc.library.cornell.edu</extref><lb/></item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>Compiled by:</label>
					<item>RMC Staff</item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>Date completed:</label>
					<item>September 2013</item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>EAD encoding:</label>
					<item>RMC Staff, September 2013</item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>Date modified:</label>
					<item>Jude Corina, August 2017</item>
				</defitem>
			</list>
			<date>© 2013 Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University
				Library</date>
		</titlepage>
	</frontmatter>
	<archdesc level="collection">
		<did>
			<head id="a1">DESCRIPTIVE SUMMARY</head>
			<unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="MARC 245">Paul Fishbeck menu collection,
					<unitdate encodinganalog="MARC 245" type="inclusive">1955-2015</unitdate>
			</unittitle>
			<unitid label="Collection Number:">8418 </unitid>
			<origination label="Creator:"><persname encodinganalog="100" normal="Fishbeck, Paul,   "
					>Fishbeck, Paul, </persname></origination>
			<physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="MARC 300">.3 cubic feet.</physdesc>
			<physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Printed material</physdesc>
			<repository label="Repository:">Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell
				University Library</repository>
			<abstract label="Abstract:">Menus from restaurants with personal reminiscences from Mr.
				Fishbeck.</abstract>
			<langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="041"
					langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial>
		</did>
		<bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
			<head id="a2" altrender="biography">BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE </head>
			<p>Class of 1956, Hotel.</p>
		</bioghist>
		<scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520">
			<head id="a3">COLLECTION DESCRIPTION</head>
			<p>Menus from restaurants in New York, including Fraunces Tavern, Cafe des Artistes,
				Windows on the World, and Maxwell's Plum (postcards); California, including Aptos
				Beach Inn; Williamsburg (Va.) including Campbell's Tavern; Illinois: Massachusetts;
				Vermont; New Orleans - Brennan's; Bretton Woods, New Hamphire - the Mount Washington
				Hotel and Resort (guest directory) in ; Paris, including the Hotel Meurice and Le
				Drugstore; McClure's in Melbourne, Australia; and the Royal Hawaiian from a Matson
				ship. Includes personal reminiscences from Mr. Fishbeck.</p>
			<p>Menus from a cruise around the British Isles, Ireland, Norway on the SS Nautica taken
				by John and Helen Babcock.</p>
			<p>Additional menus from Louisiana, Australia, Portland (Oregon), and the Restaurant de
				la Pyramide in Vienne, France.</p>
			<p>Additional menus from New Zealand and Australia; also lunch menus from the Dawn
				Princess cruise ship.</p>
			<p>Additional menus from California, Australia, Switzerland, Chicago, and Hong Kong.</p>
		</scopecontent>
		<controlaccess>
			<head id="a7">SUBJECTS</head>
			<controlaccess>
				<head>Names: </head>
				<persname encodinganalog="MARC 100">Fishbeck, Paul, </persname>
			</controlaccess>
			<controlaccess>
				<head>Subjects:</head>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Gastronomy.</subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Dinners and dining.</subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Restaurants.</subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Menus -- United States -- History -- 20th
					century.</subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Menus -- France -- History -- 20th
					century.</subject>
			</controlaccess>
			<controlaccess>
				<head>Form and Genre Terms:</head>
				<genreform encodinganalog="MARC 655" source="aat">Menus.</genreform>
			</controlaccess>
		</controlaccess>
		<descgrp>
			<head id="a8">INFORMATION FOR USERS</head>
			<prefercite>
				<head>Cite As:</head>
				<p>Paul Fishbeck menu collection, #8418. Division of Rare and Manuscript
					Collections, Cornell University Library.</p>
			</prefercite>
		</descgrp>
		<dsc type="combined">
			<head>CONTAINER LIST</head>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">1</container>
					<unitdate>May 15, 1986</unitdate>
					<unittitle>The Wayside Inn, South Sudbury, Massachusetts</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: I am grateful when
						places date their stuff. The menu is one sheet about 12 inches by 6 inches
						and has all the old favorites and I guess was expensive for its day. Salmon
						was $13.25, filet mignon was $15.75. Something unusual? COOW WOOW –
						“America’s First Mixed Drink” made with rum - $2.75. Has anyone ever heard
						of it? They said they made their rolls from flour and meal stone ground at
						the Wayside Grist Mill, Mass. Meal tax – 5%. Barnie and I and some of our
						kids stayed overnight in an upstairs room which was quite quiet. That was
						probably because Henry Ford, after a visit, had the highway moved some half
						mile away from the Inn. A nice thing to do. Longfellow would have probably
						done the same if traffic in his day was a problem. </p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">1</container>

					<unittitle>St. Andrew’s Café at the Catering [sic] Institute of America on the
						Hudson River at Hyde Park, New York</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: I image a lot of
						you have been there over the years. Now the Hotel School does a lot of
						“joint” training/teaching with the Institute which makes sense. We ate in
						St. Andrews because we couldn’t get into the upmarket dining rooms or we
						didn’t have the money or only wore sneakers that day. Smoked tuna steak was
						$6.50 apple strudel $2.00 and Kona coffee $.75 so perhaps someone can put a
						date on that menu. I think we were on our way to see my cousin near
						Ogdensburg, New York, near the Canadian border. Stopped to see Chuck Laforge
						at Rhinebeck, but he was out of town. Ogdensburg is the home of Frederick
						Remington, the painter and sculptor of the wild west. If you go to the 21
						Club you will see a great deal of his work in the lobby.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">1</container>

					<unittitle>Royal Hawaiian Hotel, main dining room, Honolulu, Hawaii</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: The pink lady as it
						is affectionately known. The first time Barnie went to the U.S. was with her
						mother and they had a break from the ship, the SS MONTEREY in Honolulu.
						Chateauneuf-Du-Pape 1952 was $3.00. Only French wines on one page. Another
						with California wines – all $3.00. Prime Rib of Beef at $6.25 included hors
						d’oeuvres, soup, vegetables, salad (with 1000 island dressing I am pleased
						to see) dessert cheeses and demi tasse. The menu was not dated, but it was
						before Statehood as it said a Territorial tax of 3.5% would be included.
						Matson, the company I worked for at the time, sold their Hawaiian properties
						to Sheraton for peanuts as I think they needed the cash and to pay my
						salary. A note at the bottom of the menu says to inform the head waiter if
						you are expecting a phonecall. How times have changed and not for the better
						I would suggest.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">1</container>

					<unittitle>Royal Hawaiian, Honolulu, Hawaii</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: Where my future
						wife and mother-in-law dined while travelling on a Matson Ship. I am not
						sure if I mentioned Matson owned the major four properties on Waikiki before
						selling them to Sheraton. </p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">2</container>
					<unitdate>early 1980s</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Tango, Chicago, Illinois</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: Of interest is the
						note on the price of coffee going through the roof. Fifteen times the cost
						of tea.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">2</container>
					<unitdate>1977</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Campbell's Tavern, Williamsburg, Virginia</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: Very well done
						historically with reading material on the back. Every American should go
						there at least once as it represents the best of America.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">2</container>
					<unitdate>July 1, 1988</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Fraunces Tavern, New York, New York</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: How such a
						historical place could get into such trouble. Believe they are now closed
						and looking for someone with expertise and knowhow. The other tavern,
						Fraunces in New York City is also an icon of Democracy and if in financial
						difficulty should be bailed out by the government, any government for all to
						see at its best.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">2</container>
					<unitdate>1977</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Hotel Meurice, Paris, France</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: Stayed one night as
						we arrived in town early and our hotel across the road was full. Would have
						slept in the car if I had known at the time the Gestapo used it as
						headquarters during the war. A good article on the property in AD years ago.
						Hotel Meurice in Paris is just around the corner from the Intercontinental
						which is just around the corner from the Ritz. I believe Ernest Hemingway
						was the first to enter it after the end of World War II. A man with
						impeccable taste.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">2</container>
					<unitdate>mid 1980s</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Cafe des Artistes, New York, New York</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: Now closed due to
						cost burden of employees benefits. Operated by Smazathy , a good friend of
						the Hotel School. Was privileged to see his extensive library. Probably the
						best private collection of culinary material in the country and was told he
						knew the contents of every book. What a shame. Note the menu is rather
						ordinary for such a wonderful establishment. Shows what is really important
						- the food, decor and service.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">2</container>
					<unitdate>1980s</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Woodstock Inn, Woodstock, Vermont</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: One of the leading
						properties in the country. Simple, but adequate menu. Plenty of reading
						material to pass the time. Note Robert Trent Jones mentioned, went to
						Cornell.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">2</container>
					<unitdate>1950s</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Aptos Beach Inn, Aptos, California</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: Note to use of
						stickers to promote "Special Today" But why three? I"ll have the roast beef
						at $3.85.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">2</container>

					<unittitle>Windows on the World, New York, New York</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: I can't even
						comment.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">3</container>
					<unitdate>1975</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Matson menu</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: Note both the
						Captain and the Chef get a mention. Note the old company has a new owner,
						The Pacific Far East Line virtually doing the same run. And this menu dates
						from October on its way from Nuku'alofa to Wellington. A new menu was
						printed every day by the two printers aboard. Passengers sat at assigned
						tables each evening for the entre voyage. So if you embarked at San
						Francisco and returned to San Francisco you had six weeks (42 days) with the
						same passengers doing the same. And you had the same waitress for the entire
						trip. That is usually. On one trip I was on a particular one didn't turn up
						for the evening meal and some passengers asked where she was. The new one
						said the other one jumped overboard during the night!</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>

			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">3</container>

					<unittitle>Victoria Station, San Francisco, California</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: A very successful
						restaurant chain started and developed by three hotelies which went
						nationwide before running into problems. The theme was to do with railroads
						and three or four old freight cars were joined together to make a very
						attractive layout. The menu is I believe from the original property in San
						Francisco close to the Embarcadero. I went to another much larger operation
						in Universal Studios where the company had brought out from England what
						appeared to be an entire train station/waiting room.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">3</container>

					<unittitle>Trader Vic's, San Francisco, California</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: An old menu judging
						by the prices. A classmate Bumps Baldauf was the Manager before he opened
						his own establishment.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder"/>

					<unittitle/>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: </p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">3</container>
					<unitdate>1977</unitdate>
					<unittitle>New York Restaurant, Marseilles, France</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: Located on the head
						of the Old Port about fifty feet from the fishmongers with their fresh catch
						of seafood. The restaurant was primarily a seafood place and actually had
						one person going around the dining room helping customers open their
						oysters, crack their crabs, shell their lobster, etc. It was in 1977, we
						stayed just yards away at a hotel overlooking the port with a view to the
						unfolding dramas on the sidewalk. The first night a couple of men were seen
						to be arguing by the cafe in front of the hotel. One picked up a table
						umbrella and stabbed the other fatally. The police arrived in some sort of
						van, opened the rear doors and threw the dead man in rather roughly. Who
						needs television on holiday. My wife had bouillabaisse by the way later in
						the cafe.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">4</container>

					<unittitle>Tasman Empire Airways Limited, TEAL, menu postcard </unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: Operated in the
						Pacific from 1940 to 1965 when it became Air New Zealand. The early planes
						were flying boats made by the English Company Shorts who were the first
						company to make production aircraft. My wife's father used to fly on these
						planes from Wellington or Auckland to Sydney and land at Rose Bay. (my
						wife's maiden name!) The planes only carried some seventeen passengers but
						in luxury and style. </p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">4</container>
					<unitdate>1990</unitdate>
					<unittitle>MS Ryndam</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: A main dining room
						menu on board our voyage to Alaska and back to Vancouver in 1990. You can
						see the menu is Day 4 so they had a separate menu for each of the seven
						days. The back page gives a good summary of Holland American Line.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">4</container>
					<unitdate>July 8, 1957</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Huddart Parker Line, MV Wanganella</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: On board breakfast
						is served on Monday, the 8th of July 1957. Note Dolly Varden Cakes -
						somewhat of an institution. A pretty comprehensive menu on a short trip
						across the Tasman. This was my wife's first time on a ship, but not the
						last.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">4</container>
					<unitdate>ca. 1950s</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Caesar's</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: The cover page says
						"Home of the Original Caesar's Salad" If this is correct then this is a
						treasure. I have no idea where I got this menu nor the date. But it looks
						like it is from somewhere around the fifties or the sixties. Maybe someone
						can throw some light on both the origin and the date. The menu is certainly
						balanced and lively with a wide variety of wines, but none from the northern
						neighbor.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">4</container>
					<unitdate>1998</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Stag's Head and Bear Inn, Coventry, United Kingdom </unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: I combine these two
						since I got them more or less together on our sojourn to England. They are
						from around Coventy as one says. A friend and his wife took us to that area
						where we rented a car to go touring. He used to work in the area in
						automotive sales, but lamented now there were no major English car
						manufacturers owned by the English. The year was 1998. And the menus were
						certainly indicative of the forthcoming season. To digress - we stayed with
						our friends for a few nights in their quaint village called Ashby St.
						Ledgers which like most of England is filled with history. The Manor House
						was apparently the site of the hatching of the Gunpowder Plot in 1605 with
						Guy Fawkes in attendance. A long time ago the Manor House was a gift to a
						nobleman from William the Conqueror. The church in the village dates back to
						the middle ages and open to the public for inspection. A bit unnerving
						walking down the aisles knowing there were people buried under the stone
						flooring. Our friends lived there some ten years and the neighbors still
						called them Mr. and Mrs. Smith.   old port</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">5</container>

					<unittitle>Brennan's, New Orleans, Louisiana</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: Breakfast menu and
						Dinner menu - both very involved and expensive. Probably in the late
						eighties when we did a grand tour of the U. S. and spent some time staying
						with a fraternity brother who was born in New Orleans and is the only person
						I have even known who has always lived at the same address. He organized a
						"swamp" tour and it felt like we were in the middle of the Amazon until a
						plane flew over and someone said we were just pass the airport. He took us
						up the Mississippi River and showed us a bridge spanning the river. He said
						to look closely and note there were not any approaches to the bridge. A
						local politician promised a bridge if elected, but said nothing about the
						approaches. We stopped at Oak Alley on the way and the place is famous for
						being in plenty of ads due to its magnificent tree lined avenue from the
						front gate to the house. A commercial was actually being filmed the day we
						were there so we helped ourselves to ice cold drinks set out for the filming
						crew. It was very hot!</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">5</container>

					<unittitle>The Mount Washington Hotel and Resort Guest Directory, Bretton Woods,
						New Hampshire</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: Not a menu as such,
						but indicates the high level of everything they attempt. Built in 1902 it is
						the largest timber building in New England. I think I got that right. It was
						the site of the Bretton Woods Conference in the 1940's where the free world
						leaders and or finance ministers worked out the monetary system to be
						adopted after WWII. As the location was so remote I suppose it was selected
						for security reasons. We read or were told that during the days before cars
						became popular several passenger trains arrived each and every day bringing
						trainloads of tourists summer and winter. We stayed across the main highway
						in one of the properties and had a rail line run behind. Waiting for dinner
						we took a short walk along the tracks which were still in place and then
						rolled down the embankment to the highway. At the exact spot we found a
						plaque almost hidden by bushes which indicated a railroad named something,
						something, and Ogdensburg. I mentioned another line which had Ogdensburg in
						its name, being the hometown of my Dad. The other marvel in the area is the
						Cog Railway which runs to the top of Mt. Washington, the highest peak east
						of the Mississippi I recall. The highest winds in the U. S. were recorded
						there in the thirties. The other notable fact is the railway was the first
						to adopt the technology of using cogs on such mountains. We beat the Swiss
						by one year!</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">5</container>
					<unitdate>1977</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Le Drugstore, Paris, France</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: A fun place in busy
						area of Paris. The English translations seem to be hidden away for only some
						items, but it doesn't matter in gay Paree.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">5</container>

					<unittitle>Clyde's, Washington, D.C</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: No menu, but an
						early postcard of the first, I think, operation in Georgetown. The company
						now has say ten or more operations covering D. C. and outer areas. The last
						time we were there we encountered a bomb scare with a package left on the
						street. The police told everyone to vacate the restaurant via the rear
						entrance as the fun was over. I asked the waiter if we still had to pay.
						Unfortunately he said yes. We became a little nervous in the drama as we
						were dining with two fraternity brothers and their wives. One was the first
						U. S. Ambassador to Albania, a country which had just come out of the cover
						of communism and a very poor country.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">5</container>
					<unitdate>Mid 1970s</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Maxwell's Plum, New York, New York</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: The owner had been
						in the movie industry mainly in design and it could be seen in his designs.
						I think he also ran the Tavern on the Green in Central Park. Sorry did not
						obtain a menu.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">5</container>
					<unitdate>ca. 1975</unitdate>
					<unittitle>McClures, Melbourne, Australia</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: A family style
						restaurant on a busy thoroughfare near downtown Melbourne. From memory, the
						price changes on the menu were handmade and pretty ordinary, but a new
						government raised wages overnight by some thirty per cent! I talked to the
						owners years later and he said they lost half a million dollars in their
						first year of business because they had no idea of how to run a restaurant
						They made a fortune selling a large wholesale business and decided to open a
						restaurant. They didn't seek any help so suffered the consequences. </p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">6</container>
					<unitdate>ca. 2000s</unitdate>
					<unittitle>SS Nautica</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: Menus from a recent
						trip taken by my friends, John and Helen Babcock who live in the next town
						on the map - Flinders. They have sailed on the SS Nautica around the British
						Isles, Ireland and a touch of Norway. The smaller menus are from different
						days noted at the top so you can see where they went. The two larger menus
						are from the specialized dining areas with meals at no extra cost. I think
						it is important to mention this as most shipping companies charge something
						for the specialized dining areas claiming the menu is better, the meals are
						prepared in a separate galley, etc. etc. Some of these claims are true, some
						are not. Note on the main dining menu Jacques Pepin has Signature dishes.
						Most companies have induced a leading chef, be it an American or a Frenchman
						to do some consulting and add his name to the culinary delights. Usually a
						male by the way. Their services may include a voyage or two each year to
						reinforce their activity. A good idea especially if the voyage is a culinary
						one. The ship is one of the Oceania Cruise Line which bought the Nautica
						from the Renaissance Cruise Line when it went bust. They had eight almost
						identical ships taking about 684 passengers. It is easy to identify their
						origin as such. We went on one several years ago named the SS Pacific
						Princess and found the size very pleasant. New ships are being launched now
						which carry around 5000 passengers, Yes, that was five thousand. A veritable
						city in itself. I recall the Pacific Princess had a main dining room with
						two sittings for dinner, a bistro/cafeteria for the three meals, a small
						food area by the pool and maybe one specialty restaurant. <lb/><lb/>The new
						mega ships have almost twenty restaurants/ food area/ places to eat perhaps
						at an extra cost. So on a seven day voyage you rarely have to eat in the
						same place twice. On traditional ships there are two sittings for dinner,
						whereas the more adventurous are offering dinner between say 5 pm and 10 pm
						which suits more people as they are not tied down to a specific time. I
						recall on the Pacific Princess one could eat say ten hours per day, whereas
						newer and larger ships one can virtually eat around the clock. That is if
						you want to gain fifty pounds in a week! And if the meal areas are closed
						there is always room service. I know of people who go on cruises for the
						experience and never get off the ship in port. And nowadays many lines do
						not require people to dress for so called formal nights. If they do, a
						reefer jacket or a dark suit will do in most cases. Whereas when I went to
						sea every night was formal and I mean formal except the first night
						(unpacking) and the last night (packing). On my first trip or two I had to
						spend an hour each morning in the baggage room in case passengers wanted to
						change some item. And the cases were not suitcases, but trunks. And very
						heavy. <lb/><lb/>Note the prices for wines on the main menus. A Napa Valley
						red for $93 doesn't sound like any bargain which it should be due to being
						outside most zones for excise taxes. I guess it cuts down on drunken
						passengers. Also a health warning to cover themselves in case of a problem.
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">7</container>
					<unitdate>Various</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Various</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: Lafitte’s Landing –
						circa 1989. On the Mississippi some 50 miles north of N. O. One of my
						fraternity brothers is the only person I know who has always lived in the
						same house except for his university ears. When we were staying with him he
						suggested this place. A nice short drive, good food and a bit of sightseeing
						on the way. We stopped at Oak Alley where an automobile commercial was being
						filmed. We helped ourselves to the refreshing beverages on the porch.
						Further on, Tim pointed out a fairly new bridge and asked me what I saw
						which was slightly different. My eyes must have been on vacation too as I
						couldn’t see anything unusual. Tim said the local candidate for some office
						promised to get a bridge for the locals across the mighty Mississippi. Tim
						said have another look and note there are no approaches! The candidate said
						he would get the bridge, but didn’t say it would have any approaches!
						Louisiana has always had a fascinating political background going back to
						Huey P. Long in the early part of last century. Now the restaurant – the
						chef and owner was selected by President Reagan to go with him to Iceland
						when he had a meeting with the Russian President!<lb/>The Australian and
						American Association dinner at the Hilton Hotel sometime in the 80’s. I got
						to carve the turkey at our table. The detail on American Culinary Heritage
						is very detailed and thoroughly interesting.<lb/>The Fijian – breakfast
						menu. Bottom cup of coffee – 25 cents gives one an idea of the date. I was
						shown the second kitchen currently at that time not in use. Just as well as
						all the pots hanging up were rusted. <lb/>The Kon-Tiki, Sheraton Portland,
						1959. A hotelie, ex fraternity brother Ross Bell ‘57 was the Sales Manager
						when we were living in Portland. Ross was the head of the Army ROTC Corps at
						Cornell and thought he would make the Army his career. After being posted to
						Alaska he soon changed his mind. Tropical themes were very popular back in
						those days. Maybe the musical South Pacific added to their appeal. Note a
						daiquiri was 85 cents and a stinger $1. Ross went on to manage the Sheraton
						Universal and then the Sheraton at the LAX.<lb/>And to top things off one of
						the best at the time. Restaurant de la Pyramide in Vienne, France between
						Lyon and Marsailles. The day we stopped there for lunch was the day they
						were closed, but the next best thing was to get a copy of the menu. Madame
						Point ran the restaurant after her husband died. Hand written adds a bit of
						class and a set price was probably way ahead of its time. 150 frances then
						about $30. Expensive, not when it is one of the great restaurants in the
						world. The book on Mess. Point is in the Hotel School Library and certainly
						worth reading. Paul Bocuse was just one of the apprentices who gained from
						working there. About 1977.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">8</container>
					<unitdate>2013</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Kotaraya</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: Need an hour to
						read the menu.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">8</container>
					<unittitle>Phamish</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: Very trendy</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">8</container>
					<unittitle>Milanos</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: A Melbourne
						institution. on the beach front. They must be confident about their
						reputation to charge $140 for a lunch.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">8</container>
					<unitdate>2013</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Greta Point Cafe</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: A nautical theme.
						Note the back of the calling card. The tenth coffee is free. A good
						marketing idea so customers keep the card rather than throw it away.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">8</container>
					<unitdate>2013</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Terroir</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: An expensive winery
						restaurant with small portions with large prices. The Dineaid card is a good
						idea; it only added $2 to the bill.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">8</container>
					<unittitle>Princess Cruises Dawn Princess lunch menus</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: Coded as the voyage
						is repeated several times during the summer. Note there is always the
						hamburger available. Also a profile of the two main players on the ship.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">8</container>
					<unittitle>Maxwell’s Plum in New York City, postcards</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: Must be thirty to
						forty years old.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>

			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">8</container>

					<unittitle>Clyde’s in Washington D.C. area</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: I first went to
						Clyde’s over thirty years with my cousin’s son for breakfast. It was the
						only one then. Now is a well established chain of high quality food and run
						I believe by a hotelie. The last time we went to the “original’ in
						Georgetown with a couple of fraternity brothers there was a bomb scare on
						the street and we were evacuated. The fact one of them was the first US
						Ambassador to Albania wasn’t a consideration I guess?</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">9</container>

					<unittitle>Bouchon in Napa Valley.</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: One of Thomas
						Keller’s properties and just down the road from his landmark restaurant.
						Obviously not everyone can afford to eat at the later so he saw an opening
						for “reasonable” prices in Bouchon. Our only complaint was the fact the
						tables were on top of each other and getting up was a real challenge. The
						menu covered all the bases one would expect from such a professional. We
						went there say three or four years ago with an old friend.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">9</container>
					<unitdate>2013</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Whispering Vines Cafe</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: A local property.
						Reasonable prices in a pleasant spot in a winery on the Mornington
						Peninsula. Most of the restaurants down here are way overpriced and attract
						the visitors and not the locals. Good idea on the wine - have half glass of
						each. For children - call them little people rather than children.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">9</container>

					<unittitle>Hotel du Lac Coppet </unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: Although not a menu
						the brochure gives an indication of the style of food and the ambiance of
						the property. We stayed here by chance and when we checked out of our
						four-hundred-year-old room I noticed a brochure on the desk for the taking.
						It was our introduction to the Relais and Chateaux chain of great properties
						around the world. Stayed in the late seventies from memory. </p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">9</container>

					<unittitle>Wayside Inn brochures</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: Described
						previously.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">9</container>

					<unittitle>Cape Cod Room in Chicago</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: In its day,
						probably the best restaurant in Chicago. No menu, but freshness was their
						secret. From memory, all seafood flown in daily from either coast. </p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">9</container>

					<unittitle>Hoefly’s in Long Beach, California</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: Around the late
						fifties or early sixties. Everything on the men to please everyone. Coffee –
						15 cents! Cocktails not priced - Why? Signed by the owner for friends of
						ours we met on the ship.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">9</container>
					<unitdate>ca. 1962</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Grison’s Chicken House in San Francisco</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: Probably early
						sixties when we lived there. Pretty ordinary to change some prices with a
						pen, but maybe they were being clever, as the prices went down, not up!
						Recommended by various guides, including Duncan Hines, who was the guru when
						I was young.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">9</container>
					<unitdate>1977</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Bahnhof Buffet</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: amazing operation.
						There were some eight or more places to eat in the “basement” of the Berne
						railway station. There was what was really a small hotel underground for the
						staff only – some thirty to forty rooms. The owner, Fritz Haller gave us a
						tour. French and German would have covered most of the customers, and prices
						need some calculating.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">9</container>
					<unitdate>ca. 1962</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Bentleigh’s</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: Maybe Oakland,
						California. The menu is supposed to show elegance.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">9</container>
					<unitdate>1977</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Baron’s Table, Holiday Inn in Hong Kong</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: Very
						well-thought-out menu in German. Print very small. Prices in Hong Kong
						dollars from memory. About ten to one?</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">10</container>
					<unitdate>2014</unitdate>
					<unittitle>The Chocolate Fish, Wellington, New Zealand</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: Four of us had four
						sandwiches, one each, and one bottle of wine –$100!! But it was a fun place.
						There was a small dining room, but as the sun was shining everyone ate
						outside. They had a huge lawn where most people sat on the grass! This might
						not work in North America, but New Zealanders are pretty tough. Right on the
						harbor, so a perfect position in good weather.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">10</container>
					<unitdate>2012</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Moorooduc Estate, Mornington Peninsula, Melbourne,
						Australia</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: This was a club
						dinner. I used to belong but thought ten years was enough. Priced around
						$50-60. The great thing about functions if that you know exactly what to
						plan and especially if it is a fixed contract. Note there was no choice of
						the main course which is somewhat unusual.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">10</container>
					<unitdate>2013</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Ciao Bella</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: The menu explains
						itself. With the full menu on the blackboard.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>

			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">10</container>
					<unitdate>1977</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Holiday Inn, Hong Kong</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: We stayed in the
						Holiday Inn (American), dined in the Main restaurant (German) in an Asian
						city. I think the price in US dollars, was say $10. Very expensive menu
						cover, but could be used for other events. </p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">10</container>
					<unitdate>1977</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Hofbrauhaus, Munnich, Germany</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: At that time
						probably the most famous restaurant in Munich. I think it sat about one
						thousand customers. The changed in the menu handwritten show they are
						confident in their operation and the menu covers a multitude of dishes. So
						why change menus for the sake of fussy customers.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">10</container>
					<unittitle>Dining Experience, SS Dawn Princess</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: Dining experience –
						although not a menu it highlights the breakdown of the kitchen staff
						required to prepare about ten thousand meals each and every day at sea. Who
						else can afford a full time ice carver! Both of the pictured gentlemen on
						the cover attended either a hotel or catering school. Most have done so in
						Italy and both have been with Princess for a long period of time saying
						something about the company! Each voyage they put on a cooking demonstration
						which is part education and part entertainment.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">10</container>
					<unittitle>Wildwood Inn, Paradise California</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: It is noted the
						year was 1963 but not certain. I was manager of a nearby hotel and probably
						went there around that time. Note the steaks were not cheap for that time,
						but other items relatively cheaper. Lots of info on the menu confusing those
						who only wanted to order a meal. “Minimum service charge for small children”
						How many would you like?</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">11</container>
					<unitdate>2014</unitdate>
					<unittitle>SS Dawn Princess Menus</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: A full set of menus
						from our recent trip to New Zealand and return to Melbourne. The easy way to
						travel. The voyage, to use maritime language, was for thirteen nights. The
						ship makes about six or seven exact same voyages each summer. So the menus
						are exactly the same each time. This system has numerous advantages as you
						can imagine. The main galley prepares some nine to ten thousand meals each
						day. In the information sheets I sent some time ago the ship told the number
						of staff involved in the preparation of meals. With computers the number of
						each item served can be recorded exactly making ordering much more precise
						than in the old days. Percentages of each item ordered can be used for
						further purchases using the entire summer voyages as a guideline. Nowadays a
						ship turns around in about ten hours so everything has to be delivered and
						stored to a strict schedule. Thus many of the staff have to work harder
						while in port than at sea. I recall the ships I served on had two or three
						days in San Francisco to take on goods for the next voyage. The new
						provisions for our latest voyage would have been loaded in Melbourne where
						everything would have been available and goods would be of a high standard
						determined by shore visits to the various providers. The only item I saw
						being taken aboard on the cruise was fuel in Auckland, New Zealand.
						<lb/><lb/>The menus – The clue for each night is at the bottom of the page
						with Italian Night, English Night, etc. etc. It seemed to be the Head
						Waiter’s job to see the waiters used the correct ones for the particular
						night. The menus are well balanced with three appetizers, four soups and
						salads, and six or so main courses. No one went hungry. The mains included a
						pasta, a vegetarian, a fish or seafood, and one or two red meat and or a
						poultry dish. Some dishes used to be flambéed at the table as did desserts,
						but with current concerns this has been done away with. And if there is
						nothing to one’s liking for the night, then one can always choose one, or
						two or three of the items on the left hand side of the menu. After the three
						courses, one is presented with a dessert menu which again offers many
						choices and old regulars. We often just asked for ice cream, which of
						course, changed daily and was entirely made on the ship, I never noticed
						many passengers ordering any of drinks on the left hand side of the dessert
						menu. There was a comprehensive wine list in addition to the above
						mentioned.. In order to please light drinkers, one could have just one glass
						and the waiter would mark the bottle and one could have more the next night.
						<lb/><lb/>Everyone on the staff tried their best to please and if one didn’t
						want, say Brussels sprouts, then one could ask for something else. I don’t
						think menus have changed much over the years except perhaps healthier,
						smaller portions, but not too small, and notices to warn of eating
						undercooked items and reference to allergies and diet requests.
						<lb/><lb/>The dining room had separate breakfast and lunch menus of a much
						simpler style, but still with daily specials. In case one couldn’t wait for
						the dining room to open there was always the buffet which had everything
						anyone could want and was open about eighteen hours each day. In addition
						there was a restaurant which served only pizzas and also a steakhouse open
						for evening meals at a slight extra charge. If getting from one’s stateroom
						to the dining room proved too difficult there was always room service,
						twenty-four hours a day. <lb/><lb/>The main dining rooms had two sittings
						for dinner – the first about 5:45 and the second about 7:45. Now there is a
						trend to have open seating from say 5 PM to 10 PM which allows to dine when
						the please more or less. We first came across this on a Norwegian Line Ship
						and it worked well. If one went to the dining room and your preference was
						not available, you were given a beeper and when a table was available they
						gave you a buzz. Usually only five or ten minutes. No problem since you
						weren’t going anywhere.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">12</container>
					<unitdate>2014</unitdate>
					<unittitle>U.K. Menus</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: Friends of ours
						recently went touring in the U. K. and they asked what they could bring
						back. I said menus of course, and told them where they would end up. They
						brought several from quaint pubs and inns. …hamburger in every shape and
						form seems to take over the market over there. And most places seem to be
						very concerned the customer doesn’t sue for any breach of nutrition. Our
						friends had Chinese takeaway one night and were asked if they wanted chips
						and gravy (commercial) with the food. All very exciting.<lb/><lb/>Menus
						include: Emirates Airlines, Best Pizza and Kebab House, The Boat Inn, The
						Buccleuch Hotel and Restaurant, The Famous Star Hotel, Dumfriesshire, The
						Fox and Pheasant Inn, Cumbria, Marston’s Inns and Taverns, Nith Hotel,
						Dumfries, Old Success Inn, The Roebuck Pub and Dining Room, The Sycamore
						Tree, Longtown, Trees Café, Wheeler’s of St. James, Dunfries, Scotland. </p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">13</container>
					<unitdate>2014</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Victoria Australia Menus</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: When I started this
						journey I thought I was sending pieces of paper or cardboard with words
						written or drawn on them. I didn’t know how I even obtained many of the
						menus let alone when or where. And I only had some idea of the dates. Only
						since I have been obtaining them more recently have I realized it is about
						people rather than paper. When I ask for a copy of the restaurant’s menu I
						get some very interesting replies – too busy, okay if the boss isn’t
						looking, why do I want it, etc. When I have the chance to tell someone where
						it is going the response can be completely different. For example -
						<lb/><lb/>Late last year Barnie and I went to a small town for a few nights.
						There was an Accor resort in the town of Creswick, just out of Ballarat, one
						of our provincial cities. Good mining country and find the area fascinating.
						Ballarat even had a stock exchange during the gold rush days. One night we
						ate at the American Hotel, and had quite a reasonable meal for a country
						pub. After the meal I asked the manager if I could have a copy of his menu
						and told him where it would end up. He got quite excited and said to hold on
						a minute. He gathered all his menus. He was a hometown boy and had never
						heard of Cornell. Told him about the Ivy League and had heard of Harvard! He
						asked if we would like to see the rest of the property. <lb/><lb/>There were
						guest bedrooms, a function room, and more. He even pointed out the
						outbuilding where the gold was held before being shipped to Melbourne. The
						rooms were covered with prints of Norman Lindsay, a hometown boy. Originals
						would be worth a fortune as he was very successful. The two original
						American owners were involved with Cobb and Co. a stagecoach company which
						covered the east coast of Australia and a cinema company. The town of
						Creswick had seen better times since the gold rush days, but now a very
						successful woolen mill with a retail outlet and a great patisserie on the
						main street. The passenger rail has been brought back top life for a couple
						of times each week. <lb/><lb/>We just spent four days in what is called the
						High Country some one and fifty miles north east of Melbourne. We ate in
						four different restaurants and found them all satisfactory and a lot of fun.
						Menus as follows- <lb/><lb/>The Bright Brewery. A good concept. You order
						and pay at the counter. You get your own silver from a bucket. The food is
						delivered to your table. Outside tables when the weather permits.
						<lb/><lb/>Alpine Hotel. A bustling property. Same concept as the Brewery. A
						bit of everything on the menu. Even Moet at $110.00. Established 1864.
						<lb/><lb/>Tahbilk Restaurant in the Tahbilk Winery. This is a favorite of
						ours, only about sixty miles north of Melbourne on the Goulbourn River. It
						is the oldest winery in Victoria and some of the oldest vines of a
						particular variety in the world! We have been going to this winery for about
						forty-five years now and pick up a couple of cases each time. The menu is
						several sheets, but I grabbed the main one. </p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">14</container>
					<unitdate>2014</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Doyles</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: The setting would
						be hard to beat. We went there on a weekend and it was packed. Around since
						1885 which is ancient for Australia. The daily menu is stappled to the
						history so there is no wastage. I believe the cooking oil is changed every
						day rather than strained and reused. A time and motion study exercise. The
						prices are not cheap, but freshness comes with a cost. A great operation
						going strong. A surcharge to be the labor costs on weekends. </p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">14</container>
					<unitdate>2015</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Itali.co</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: A very good true
						Italian restaurant down the cost from our abode. And not too expensive for
						the quality. I usually sit so I can watch the people in the open kitchen and
						one can tell everything is made to order. A surcharge applies on public
						holidays because of our crazy wage structure. The owner brings out young
						staff from Italy and provided accommodation so they can get a feel for our
						culture. And they all seem happy. the restaurant is in one half of an old
						hotel which is good for for both parties. </p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">14</container>
					<unitdate/>
					<unittitle>Portsea Hotel</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: A very old hotel at
						the end of the road on the Peninsula. Sweeping views of the Bay, outdoor
						dining and atmosphere. One orders at the counter, but the food is delivered
						to the table. I couldn’t grab the full menu. Been going there for almost
						fifty years. Some very good meals, some ordinary depending what is the day
						of the week. Always can be a problem with different staff on different days.
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">14</container>
					<unitdate>2015</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Le Bouchon</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: A true French
						Restaurant in the closest town. Reasonable for the quality served. Small and
						rather noisy, but not pretending to be anything more than a French bistro.
						The town. or better village, now has two pizza come Italian, one Chinese,
						one pub, one Asian, and a bakery serving meals. Quite a choice.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">14</container>
					<unitdate/>
					<unittitle>Lord Chumley’s</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: Finally. one owned
						by a fraternity brother, Don Clark’54 who was always in the hospitality
						business. Think it was in the 70’s on a visit to DisneyWorld. Note other
						locations mentioned. Have to be pretty confident customers like this one.
						Menu slides into a very flash jacket embossed in gold. Don was talking about
						Key Man insurance the day I met him. Fairly new concept I recall.
						Interesting wine list.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">15</container>
					<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="2015">2015</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Cunard, Queen Elizabeth</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: An old friend of
						ours, the widow of a previous Director of ASIO, one of our intelligence
						agencies, went on a voyage last summer and kindly brought back several
						different menus from the ship. The best two are the first and last night’s
						menus cleverly included in a booklet about the history of the company. You
						will note at the top is a Royal Spa Selection and I had no idea what the
						figures next to the item meant until I wised up and looked down below to see
						they were calories/fat/fibre! Someone said no one goes on a voyage to worry
						about the diet, but there will be a percentage who do nowadays. First time I
						have seen such figures. The Cunard ships are class ships and what level of
						cabin one has determines which dining room one dines in. Our friend was one
						step down from the top. If you look at the menus carefully you will see they
						lean toward being American. Main courses are entrees and many items will be
						familiar to Americans. As an excursion in our senior year took the class on
						the Queen Mary we toured the galley, but failed to provide us with any
						menus! The Queen Mary is now a floating hotel in Long Beach, California.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">15</container>
					<unitdate>Undated</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Nickodell</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: A very busy menu
						when restaurants tried to cover all the bases. I have no idea if I ever went
						there or someone gave it to me, but looked like the sixties, but there is a
						77 at bottom of first page. Enough salads alone to sink a ship. Mentioning
						air conditioning and “free Parking” are interesting. Three cheers for
						Hollywood!.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">15</container>
					<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="2015">2015</unitdate>
					<unittitle>The Menzies Hotel, Sydney, Australia</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: Room Service menu
						with 1963 on the cover – the year the hotel opened. We didn’t dine in any
						official restaurant due to my condition so this had to do. Note kid’s menu
						being very reasonable and wine the same, except Tattinger Champagne.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">15</container>
					<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="2015">2015</unitdate>
					<unittitle>The Vibe, Melbourne, Australia</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: Another room
						service menu for comparison. Minimum order required and a $4 charge for
						delivery. What about picking it up yourself? Steak not cheap or wines. Only
						one Victoria wine and Knappstein from outer space! Not a flash hotel but
						only across the street from the train station where we caught the train to
						Sydney.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">15</container>
					<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="2015">2015</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Cafe Menu Trainlink</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p><emph render="underline">Notes from the collector</emph>: Speaking of trains,
						this is the menu for on board consumption. There are no sit down dining rooms
						on the east coast trains that I know of, but at least one can get a decent
						sandwich,main meal,glass of wine or a beer. And headache and pain relief
						materials.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">15</container>
					<unitdate>Undated</unitdate>
					<unittitle>King "Neptune's Table"</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="item">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">15</container>
					<unitdate>Undated</unitdate>
					<unittitle>Kook-o-theek, Holland</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
		</dsc>
	</archdesc>
</ead>
