<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<!-- Transformed with v1v2002_4_cornell.xsl -->

<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../dtds/ead.dtd">
	 
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../styles/style.xsl" ?>
<ead>
   <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1" scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
      <eadid mainagencycode="nic" countrycode="us" publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections//TEXT(US::NIC::RMM06003::First Baptist Church of Geneva records)//EN">RMM06003.xml</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the First Baptist Church of Geneva records,1825-1890.</titleproper>
            <titleproper type="sort">First Baptist Church of Geneva records,1825-1890</titleproper>
            <author>Compiled by M.C.L.</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library</publisher>
            <date>June 2004</date>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note audience="internal">
               <p> 
				
                  <subject>rghis</subject>
				
                  <subject>relig</subject>
                  <subject>church</subject>
			 
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>Finding aid encoded by Andrea Hektor, <date>June 2004</date>
         </creation>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change encodinganalog="583">
            <date normal="2007-05-29">2007-05-29</date>
            <item>converted from EAD 1.0 to EAD 2002 </item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <frontmatter>
      <titlepage>
         <titleproper>Guide to the First Baptist Church Of Geneva Records,<lb/>1825-1890.</titleproper>
         <num>Collection Number: 6003</num>
         <publisher>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections <lb/>Cornell University Library</publisher>
         <list type="deflist">
            <defitem>
               <label>Contact Information:</label>
               <item>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections<lb/>
2B Carl A. Kroch Library<lb/>
Cornell University<lb/>
Ithaca, NY 14853<lb/>
(607) 255-3530<lb/>
Fax: (607) 255-9524<lb/>
<extref href="mailto:rareref@cornell.edu">rareref@cornell.edu</extref>
                  <lb/>
<extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu">http://rmc.library.cornell.edu</extref>
                  <lb/></item>
            </defitem>
            <defitem>
               <label>Compiled by:</label>
               <item>M.C.L.</item>
            </defitem>
            <defitem>
               <label>Date completed:</label>
               <item>Mar. 1979</item>
            </defitem>
            <defitem>
               <label>EAD encoding:</label>
               <item>Andrea Hektor, June 2004</item>
            </defitem>
            <defitem> 
               <label>Date modified:</label> 
               <item>Marcie Farwell, February 2015</item> 
            </defitem> 
         </list>
         <date>© 2004 Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library</date>
      </titlepage>
   </frontmatter>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <head id="a1">DESCRIPTIVE SUMMARY</head>
         <unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="MARC 245">First Baptist Church of Geneva records, 
		  <unitdate type="inclusive" encodinganalog="MARC 245">1825-1890.</unitdate>
		
         </unittitle>
         <unitid label="Collection Number:">6003</unitid>
         <origination label="Creator:"> 
		  
            <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110">First Baptist Church of Geneva, (Geneva, N.Y.)</corpname>
		
         </origination>
         <physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="MARC 300">1 reel microfilm.</physdesc>
         <physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Microfilm.</physdesc>
         <repository label="Repository:">Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library</repository>
         <abstract label="Abstract:">Includes records of the Baptist Society (1826-1830); records of the Board of Trustees of the first Baptist Society; constitution of the Social Aid Society (1855-1864); minutes of the Ontario Baptist Ministerial Conference (1852-1877); and the records of the Baptist Church (1826-1890).</abstract>
         <langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="041" langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
         <head id="a2" altrender="organization">ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY </head>
         <p>The First Baptist Society of Geneva was formed in August 1825 and the records of the Society begin on the 29th of that month. The church was incorporated in 1839 when a church building was purchased from the Presbyterians. The church was a member of the Ontario Baptist Association and the Ontario Baptist Ministerial Conference. In addition, the church established its own missionary society auxiliary to the Baptist Association and maintained a Bible tract society and a temperance organization. A social aid society was formed in November 1855. There was considerable revival activity in the church, most notably in the winter of 1838-1839 and from November 1842 to March 1843.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520">
         <head id="a3">COLLECTION DESCRIPTION</head>
         <p>The records of the Geneva Baptist Church document a wide range of topics, including church discipline, a continuing controversy about seating the church's black members, church finances, and maintaining piety. At various times, the church was referred to as either a church or a society. The dates covered are: Item 1 - Aug. 29, 1829-Jan. 29, 1842; Item 2 - Nov. 12, 1855-May 29, 1864; Item 3 - June 2, 1852-Aug. 14, 1877; Item 4 - Jan. 7, 1826-Apr. 1, 1838; Item 5 -undated; and Item 6 - Dec. 25, l84l-Dec. 11, 1890. Included in the collection are the records of the church's Social Aid Society, mainly minutes and the minutes of the Ontario Baptist Ministerial Conference.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <head id="a7">SUBJECTS</head>
         <controlaccess>
            <head>Names: </head>
            <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110">First Baptist Church of Geneva, (Geneva, N.Y.)</corpname>
            <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">First Baptist Church of Geneva.Social Aid Society.</corpname>
            <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Ontario Baptist Ministerial Conference.</corpname>
         </controlaccess>
         <controlaccess>
            <head>Subjects:</head>
            <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Baptists--Societies, etc.</subject>
            <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Baptists--New York (State)--Geneva.</subject>
         </controlaccess>
         <controlaccess>
            <head>Places:</head>
            <geogname encodinganalog="MARC 651">Ontario County (N.Y.)--Religious life and customs.</geogname>
            <geogname encodinganalog="MARC 651">Geneva (N.Y.)--Religious life and customs.</geogname>
         </controlaccess>
         <controlaccess>
            <head>Form and Genre Terms:</head>
            <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="MARC 655">Minutes.</genreform>
            <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="MARC 655">Constitutions.</genreform>
         </controlaccess>
      </controlaccess>
      <descgrp type="admininfo">
         <head id="a8">INFORMATION FOR USERS</head>
         <prefercite>
            <head>Cite As:</head>
            <p>First Baptist Church of Geneva records, #6003. Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library.</p>
         </prefercite>
      </descgrp>
      <dsc type="combined">
         <head>CONTAINER LIST</head>
         <c01 level="item">
            <did>
               <unitid>Item 1</unitid>
               <unittitle>Records for the Geneva Baptist Society by William Kimber, Clerk Geneva August 29, 1825, Chronological, unpaginated, 
				<unitdate>(1825-1842)</unitdate>
			 
               </unittitle>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
               <p>These minutes begin with an entry at the organization of the church on August 29, 1825, detailing the various official appointments of the church (moderators, trustees and Sunday school class leaders) and deal with the church's finances. The minutes are followed by three pages of lists of children, school lessons and notes on the church building. Following this is a page entitled "The records of the board of Trustees of the first Baptist Society in Geneva," which cover only four pages, the last page being a series of figures (March 29, 1827-Oct. 16, 1830). They cover various appointments to the Board and notes on church finances.</p>
            </scopecontent>
         </c01>
         <c01 level="item">
            <did>
               <unitid>Item 2</unitid>
               <unittitle>Records of the Social Aid Society. Chronological, unpaginated, 
				<unitdate>(1855-1864)</unitdate>
			 
               </unittitle>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
               <p>The records of the Social Aid Society covering both the organization and functions of the group, include drafts of the Society's constitution, accounts of Society funds and lists of members. A list entitled "Visitors," has contributions to the society noted next to each name. Receipts are pasted into four pages of the volume. There are 36 pages of minutes (November 12, 1855-May 29, 1864; no entries 1859-1863). Minutes include the election of officers, planned activities, changes in membership, governmental resolutions, and records of collections and expenditures. Also noted are meeting activities including readings, singing and prayer.</p>
            </scopecontent>
         </c01>
         <c01 level="item">
            <did>
               <unitid>Item 3</unitid>
               <unittitle>Minutes of the Ont(ario) Bap(tist) Ministerial Conference From June 2, 1852 To --, Chronological with meetings numbered ( 
				<unitdate>June 2, 1852-August 14, 1877</unitdate>
				, meetings 56-147), unpaginated</unittitle>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
               <p>Ministerial Conference meetings were divided into morning, afternoon and evening sessions of two consecutive days for each meeting. #6003 continued Included in the minutes are notes on prayers and sermons as veil as mention of essays delivered at meetings e.g. "Universalism - a system of Infidelity having no affinity with the Gospel." Critiques of the sermons and essays were also delivered. The minutes record the selection of moderators and arrangements for succeeding meetings. Also included is a list entitled "Members of Ontario Baptist Ministerial Conference l86o-6l," containing the names of 21 ministers and their respective churches. Also included is a list entitled "Brethren meeting with Ont. Bap. Con." with names, residences, age and year ordained; and a list of eight towns with unidentified figures.</p>
            </scopecontent>
         </c01>
         <c01 level="item">
            <did>
               <unitid>Item 4</unitid>
               <unittitle>The Records of the Baptist Church in Geneva Constituted February 8, 1826, Chronological, 24l pp. 
				<unitdate>(January 7, 1826-April 1, 1838)</unitdate>
			 
               </unittitle>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
               <p>This book contains both covenant and regular meeting minutes, opening with an index of important events and a key to various letter symbols denoting baptisms, additions by letter, restoration, dismission, exclusion and deaths. The records include appointments to various church offices, organizational resolutions and some brief notes on church finances. Of particular note in the minutes are entries interspersed between 1831-1838 concerning black members, including entries referring to a partition constructed between blacks and whites, a resolution to give the gallery over to black use, concluding on June 3$ 1837 when the church's black members receive permission to form their own church. Another entry of note (Sept. 2, 1826) notes the formation of an auxiliary to the Ontario Baptist Association to spread the Gospel "and promote Indian reform."</p>
            </scopecontent>
         </c01>
         <c01 level="item">
            <did>
               <unitid>Item 5</unitid>
               <unittitle>Four loose sheets, 
				<unitdate>n.d.</unitdate>
			 
               </unittitle>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
               <p>These sheets note the exclusion of three male church members who had "in their possession the Book or papers Containing the Articles and Covinant" and refused to return them. The articles and covenant are then restated and a list of members included.</p>
            </scopecontent>
         </c01>
         <c01 level="item">
            <did>
               <unitid>Item 6</unitid>
               <unittitle>Meeting Minutes Chronological, 413 pp., ( 
				<unitdate>December 25, l84l-Dec. 11, 1890</unitdate>
				) </unittitle>
            </did>
            <scopecontent>
               <p>These minutes include the appointments of church officials (moderators, conference delegates, trustees and Sunday school class leaders), dealing additionally with some church finances and church discipline. There is significant revival activity, particularly during November 1842-March 1843.</p>
               <p>Entries on the activities of the congregation focus heavily on concerns for unity within the church. A noteworthy entry (March 4, 1848) contains the report of a "Vigialance Committee" stating that many in the church were "Unworthy members making use of their standing in the church to accomplish unholy objects" and called for strict discipline." The committee concluded its extensive report by saying "in our humble opinion this church cannot reasonable expect the blessing of God."</p>
            </scopecontent>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>