<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US">RMM09170</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Hendricks-Hodge Archaeological Expedition papers.<num>9170</num></titleproper><author>Compiled by Evan Fay Earle and Brenda Shears</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections</publisher><p><date>March 2006</date></p><address><addressline>2B Carl A. Kroch Library</addressline><addressline>Cornell University</addressline><addressline>Ithaca, NY 14853</addressline><addressline>rareref@cornell.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://rare.library.cornell.edu/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://rare.library.cornell.edu/" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p><subject>nam</subject></p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-10-05 18:26:48 -0400</date>.</creation></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>12/07/2018</date><item>This resource was modified by the ArchivesSpace Preprocessor developed by the Harvard Library (https://github.com/harvard-library/archivesspace-preprocessor)</item></change><change><date>2007-05-29</date><item>converted from EAD 1.0 to EAD 2002</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Hendricks-Hodge Archaeological Expedition papers.</unittitle>
    <unitid>9170</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 cubic feet.</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">1 cubic feet.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1917/1923" type="inclusive">1917-1923.</unitdate>
    <physdesc id="aspace_4a564a2e2bf6b599388b92b5cc2f8c6a">Correspondence, Diaries, Manuscripts, Photographs</physdesc>
    <abstract id="aspace_03430cd03a534a3b295e086e8c9473e4">Field notes, some loose, some in notebooks, and original manuscript texts regarding Hawikuh portion of the expedition. Three notebooks of Edwin Francis Coffin Notes on the Hawikuh site include lists of the burials and objects from the burial sites, maps and diagrams, language translations, presumably for helping to communicate with Zuni workers, architectural notes, forms of burial, types of bones, plant remains, Manuscripts and notes on pottery, the Plaza Trench, Square Kiva, and the cities of Cibola. Correspondence and photocopies to and from Thea Heye, Harry Shusta, Louis Chavez, and the Indian Temperance Union. Several photographs of the dig site and artifacts with captions and notes for publication. Also included are photocopies and a printed catalog of Cambridge University's Ketchipaun documentation of the expedition, from 1986. Copies of Cambridge holdings include the field notes, burial data, specimen list, diary, and transcripts of the record of excavation. There is one original notebook from Ketchipaun included. A folder of transcripts and microfilm information is also included.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_fcc6b8cd9da2e7ce5468f7954f92f003">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="041" langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial>
    <unitid type="bibid">5734414</unitid>
  </did>
  <odd id="aspace_0871da40f3e56cabe86af319e52b3079">
    <head>General</head>
    <list type="deflist">
      <defitem>
        <label>Contact Information:</label>
        <item>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections 2B Carl A. Kroch Library Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3530 Fax: (607) 255-9524 <extref href="mailto:rareref@cornell.edu">rareref@cornell.edu</extref> <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu">http://rmc.library.cornell.edu</extref></item>
      </defitem>
      <defitem>
        <label>Compiled by:</label>
        <item>Evan Fay Earle and Brenda Shears</item>
      </defitem>
      <defitem>
        <label>Date completed:</label>
        <item>March 2006</item>
      </defitem>
      <defitem>
        <label>EAD encoding:</label>
        <item>Evan Fay Earle March 2006</item>
      </defitem>
      <defitem>
        <label>Date modified:</label>
        <item>RMC Staff, July 2012</item>
      </defitem>
    </list>
  </odd>
  <bioghist id="aspace_3704407cfd75ddb0a4834c5cbce69960">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>The Hendricks-Hodge Archaeological Expedition was funded by the Museum of the American Indian, Heye Foundation. It was one of the most extensive such projects ever conducted in the Southwest. Zuni Indians participated in the excavation of their ancestral villages of Hawikku and, Kechiba:wa, sometimes seen as Hawikuh and Kechipauan. Sophisticated archaeological techniques led to the excavation of thousands of artifacts.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_170f70af94f85a67d5ff099e999657ce">
    <head>COLLECTION DESCRIPTION</head>
<p>Field notes, some loose, some in notebooks, and original manuscript texts regarding Hawikuh portion of the expedition. Three notebooks of Edwin Francis Coffin Notes on the Hawikuh site include lists of the burials and objects from the burial sites, maps and diagrams, language translations, presumably for helping to communicate with Zuni workers, architectural notes, forms of burial, types of bones, plant remains, Manuscripts and notes on pottery, the Plaza Trench, Square Kiva, and the cities of Cibola. Correspondence and photocopies to and from Thea Heye, Harry Shusta, Louis Chavez, and the Indian Temperance Union. Several photographs of the dig site and artifacts with captions and notes for publication. Also included are photocopies and a printed catalog of Cambridge University's Ketchipaun documentation of the expedition, from 1986. Copies of Cambridge holdings include the field notes, burial data, specimen list, diary, and transcripts of the record of excavation. There is one original notebook from Ketchipaun included. A folder of transcripts and microfilm information is also included.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_9a63e280d02bc2bcbdbbc0f82661bf58">
    <head>RELATED MATERIALS</head>
<p>Microfilm available. Also all the folders in this collection have been digitized, the notebooks are not digitized, but are on microfilm.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <arrangement id="aspace_b19ce61e04444787915d82ce8e7be49d">
    <head>SERIES LIST</head>
<p><emph render="bold"> <ref actuate="onrequest" show="replace" target="s1">Series I. Boxed Notebooks</ref> </emph> </p><p>  <emph render="bold"> <ref actuate="onrequest" show="replace" target="s2">Series II. E. F. Coffin Notebooks</ref> </emph> </p><p>  <emph render="bold"> <ref actuate="onrequest" show="replace" target="s3">Series III. Foldered Material</ref> </emph></p>  </arrangement>
  <odd id="aspace_31796fb7146b72fab9cfa059178f8077">
    <head>General</head>
<p><emph render="bold">Hodge, Hawikku, And The Museum Of The American Indian</emph></p>  </odd>
  <odd id="aspace_5225653fd0efda77d504a46ecbfcf20b">
    <head>General</head>
<p>The Museum of the American Indian played a key role in the excavation of the ancestral Zuni cities of Hawikku (Hawikuh) and Kechiba:wa (Kechipawan, Kechipaun and Kechipauan). Anthropologist Frederick Webb Hodge first visited the Zuni region in 1886 as field secretary to Frank W. Cushing, director of the Hemenway Southwestern Archaeological Expedition. In all probability, that was his first awareness of the Zuni town that was first disrupted by the Spanish explorers in 1540. Hawikku captured Hodge's imagination, and he managed to return there some 30 years later to archaeologically investigate its history.</p>  </odd>
  <odd id="aspace_9e8111395f8ac543518c9e4ba92c900f">
    <head>General</head>
<p>In 1917, George G. Heye, director of the Museum of the American Indian, with major financial support from a founding trustee, Harmon W. Hendricks, enthusiastically endorsed and sponsored the excavation of Hawikku under the leadership of F. W. Hodge. From 1917-1923 the Hendricks-Hodge Expedition carried out the most extensive archaeological investigation of a single site in the United States up to that time. A site report, however, was never written. The microfilming of the original field notes from the Expedition represents a major source for research on this site.</p>  </odd>
  <odd id="aspace_2c69917921fa7f57f7cf5009f29dd5aa">
    <head>General</head>
<p>Frederick Hodge produced an important summary of historical information related to Hawikku in 1937. Watson Smith, at Hodge's request, and in collaboration with Richard B. Woodbury, Nathalie F.S. Woodbury, and Ross G. Montgomery produced a major descriptive work on the archaeology of the site which was published by the Museum of the American Indian in 1966. Since then, the collections have remained essentially unstudied and unpublished. In 1986 The Museum received a grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities to organize and computerize the documentation related to the Hendricks-Hodge Expedition. Brenda Shears New York, New York</p>  </odd>
  <odd id="aspace_1ce7e4ea6f0bac9471c2b1bb6ed2d2f8">
    <head>General</head>
<p><emph render="bold">The Hendricks-Hodge Archaeological Expedition</emph></p>  </odd>
  <odd id="aspace_60ea56da87b3d4a3698f5726c9dc9651">
    <head>General</head>
<p>On June 7, 1540, the expedition of Francisco Vasquez de Coronado stormed at the Zuni village of Hawikku in search of the fabled Cities of Cibola. This confrontation was the first meeting between the Spaniards and the Pueblo Indians. Because of Hawikku's key historical role, the Hendricks-Hodge Expedition conducted archaeological excavations at the site from 1917-1923. Noted anthropologist Frederick Webb Hodge, ethnologist-in-charge at the Bureau of American Ethnology, came to the Museum of the American Indian especially to direct the expedition. George G. Heye, director of the Museum of the American Indian, fully endorsed the project, and Harmon W. Hendricks, one of the Museum's founding trustees, made it financially possible.</p>  </odd>
  <odd id="aspace_c1228c25dc8df94a5d72f4f73f1c0371">
    <head>General</head>
<p>The Hendricks-Hodge Expedition was one of the most extensive archaeological projects ever conducted in the Southwest. With major funding from Hendricks, Hodge began the field work in 1917 while still with the Bureau of American Ethnology. This season was jointly sponsored by the Museum of the American Indian and the Smithsonian Institution. Hodge joined the staff of the Museum in 1918 and subsequent fieldwork during the summers of 1918-1921 was sponsored by this institution. The last field season, during the summer of 1923, was jointly sponsored by the Museum of the American Indian and Louis C.G. Clarke, then director of the University Museum of Anthropology and Archaeology, Cambridge University. Major excavations were carried out at two sites of early historic villages near the modern Pueblo of Zuni, New Mexico: Hawikku (also #Hawikuh") and Kechiba:wa (also #Kechipawan, #Kechipaun," or #Kechipauan").</p>  </odd>
  <odd id="aspace_5fad36c9b4f5bedc2fd0eb486a040dd1">
    <head>General</head>
<p>During the work at Hawikku, Hodge supervised a staff which included Jesse L. Nusbaum, Edwin F. Coffin, Samuel K. Lothrop, George Hubbard Pepper, Alanson Buck Skinner, Donald A. Cadzow, and Louis C. G. Clarke. In addition, at least 39 Zuni men participated in this excavation of their ancestral villages. (See Smith, Woodbury, and Woodbury 1966 for a complete listing of the field staff.) Hodge's archaeological techniques were sophisticated for the times and encompassed stratigraphic excavation; the systematic recording of rooms, features, artifacts in field notebooks; in situ photographs; and ethnographic analogy. These techniques resulted in the recovery and documentation of thousands of artifacts of diverse types including ceramics, wood, bone, textiles, shell, lithics, and architectural elements from about 370 rooms, 1000 burials, and the large mission church and its associated friary.</p>  </odd>
  <odd id="aspace_eb121858d20d2e548fbb66c06f466143">
    <head>General</head>
<p>Hodge published several articles and one book related to the site on specialized topics such as bonework, turquoise, and the history of Hawikku. The only descriptive publication of the excavations, The Excavation of Hawikuh by Frederick Webb Hodge, Report of the Hendricks-hodge Expedition, 1917-1923 was written by Watson Smith, Richard B. Woodbury, and Nathalie F.S. Woodbury and published in 1966. This publication contains a wealth of information about the site of Hawikku and the Expedition. The field notes were used extensively to produce this report, and it is an important reference volume for anyone working with the original field notes. In particular it contains a map of the site including the relative location of room blocks and burials.</p>  </odd>
  <odd id="aspace_30ac7118d87a64a0b24164bba61ea84f">
    <head>General</head>
<p><emph render="bold">The Field Notes</emph></p>  </odd>
  <odd id="aspace_0ab04fc43b8194bd369ef197a3be0c58">
    <head>General</head>
<p>The Library is the repository for 15 volumes of field notes from the Hendricks-Hodge Expedition. All have been microfilmed. Nine relate specifically to Hawikku and are primarily handwritten by Hodge. The others include one from the 1919 work at Kechiba:wa, one by Nusbaum on the Church and Monastery, and four small books containing room plans by Coffin. The notebooks contain descriptions of the excavations, referenced by room numbers, field numbers, and burial numbers, and are the key to understanding and interpreting this important Expedition. The numbering system used during the six field seasons is not consistent or obvious. See page 177 in Smith, Woodbury and Woodbury 1966 for an explanation of the field numbers.</p>  </odd>
  <odd id="aspace_2e1b920634362d4d7d0aaf0db15aefd6">
    <head>General</head>
<p>These 15 notebooks represent the original field notes made during the excavations at Hawikku and Kechiba:wa. However, four additional notebooks of the 1923 work at Kechiba:wa recorded by Lothrop which contain field notes, room plans, burial descriptions and drawings, and a packing list were deposited with the University Museum of Ethnography and Archaeology, Cambridge, England, the co-sponsor of the 1923 field season. Through the courtesy of the University Museum photocopies of those records have been placed in the Library along with a listing of the catalog information on the Kechiba:wa artifacts that are stored in Cambridge.</p>  </odd>
  <odd id="aspace_8f2d9c84c2ec0ea843a123c0d637924c">
    <head>General</head>
<p><emph render="bold">Other documentation</emph></p>  </odd>
  <odd id="aspace_7af309f8c43483b9a40d4d3892d3363d">
    <head>General</head>
<p>A computerized listing of the catalog information for over 5000 artifacts and 1000 photographs from the Hendricks-Hodge Expedition is deposited at the Library, as is a computer printout of the approximately 1000 burial data forms prepared by the Richard and Nathalie Woodbury from the original field notes. In addition the Museum of the American Indian Archives contain about 1000 pages of typescript of the room notes that were produced by Hodge, the original burial maps that have been microfilmed with the field notes, and various drawings, photographs, correspondence related to the Expedition. Negatives and prints made during the Expedition are in the collection of the Museum's Photographic Archives.</p>  </odd>
  <odd id="aspace_a40ac567168bb488f39092a3b2cbf35b">
    <head>General</head>
<p>The research files of Watson Smith on architecture, the individual rooms, and their features (e.g. fireplaces, benches, chimneys) are deposited in the Museum of the American Indian Archives, and those of the Woodburys on the pottery and burials are at the Arizona State Museum Library Archives, University of Arizona, Tucson. Many of Hodge's personal papers that contain some references to the Expedition have been deposited in the Southwest Museum Library, Los Angeles.</p>  </odd>
  <odd id="aspace_cf63cd75bbd1784998e3299fff214f66">
    <head>General</head>
<p>The thousands of artifacts that were recovered by the Hendricks-Hodge Expedition were originally accessioned and cataloged by the Museum of the American Indian while the excavations were in progress. Provenience information on artifact catalog cards, however, is limited to a site identification (such as Hawikku), and for only about a third of the pieces, a field catalog number. Associated objects were not cataloged as a group, and therefore are separated throughout the approximately 5000 catalog entries. The field notes are the only source for contextual information about the artifacts and archaeological features in the words of the original excavators.</p>  </odd>
  <odd id="aspace_a72d8e957a26f2e96cac0a31a0da4ea1">
    <head>General</head>
<p><emph render="bold">References</emph></p>  </odd>
  <odd id="aspace_39ada20d6fabf11c3c350cbee0007c2d">
    <head>General</head>
<p>Ferguson, T. J. and E. Richard Hart. A Zuni Atlas. Norman: University of Oklahoma Press, 1985.</p>  </odd>
  <odd id="aspace_720f69c9cb4c93af689e510e89718b48">
    <head>General</head>
<p>Hodge, Frederick Webb. History of Hawikuh, New Mexico: One of the So-called Cities of Cibola. (Frederick Webb Hodge Anniversary Publication Fund, vol. 1) Los Angeles: The Southwest Museum, 1937.</p>  </odd>
  <odd id="aspace_13a4018c57b614b69c31c9f61703b85a">
    <head>General</head>
<p>Kintigh, Keith W. Settlement, Subsistence and Society in Late Zuni Prehistory. (Anthropological Papers of the University of Arizona, no. 44), Tucson: University of Arizona Press, 1985.</p>  </odd>
  <odd id="aspace_0f3d78ea89fe3d50879e3b34673423e8">
    <head>General</head>
<p>Smith, Watson, Richard B. Woodbury and Nathalie S. Woodbury. The Excavation of Hawikuh by Frederick Webb Hodge: Report of the Hendricks-Hodge Expedition, 1917-1923. (Contributions from the Museum of the American Indian, no. 20), New York, 1966.</p>  </odd>
  <prefercite id="aspace_b5c2a17442337f58ae52b4859fbaa921">
    <head>Cite As:</head>
<p>Hendricks-Hodge Archaeological Expedition papers. #9170. Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library.</p>  </prefercite>
  <unitid type="bibid">5734414</unitid>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_eea76837e954104e2d2c2f4feea1ccd2" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series I. Boxed Notebooks</unittitle></did><c02 id="aspace_d456b11d0bd6ce0f44541ec082f82536" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hawikuh 1</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1917/1917">1917</unitdate><container id="aspace_2bcb86b21884bf610b0bea852af721a1" label="Mixed Materials [31924112438787]" type="box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_089603745a09dfce1131f05a2eee2680"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Catalogue of Collection. Contains field nos. 1-277 and burials 1-201. 139p.</p></scopecontent><scopecontent id="aspace_c3e7bbfa3b3ee33d4783d6e7f46190c5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 1</emph></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_635edf7696d70c8d965c6111b426e60d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hawikuh 2</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1917/1918" type="inclusive">1917-1918</unitdate><container id="aspace_b84fb9ac0822a1a07892790f149f4442" label="Mixed Materials [31924112438787]" type="box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_52eee5bb43478e1c3b11bb891b5b39f4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains burials 201-237 and field nos. 273-329. 28p., plus unnumbered pages (rooms 2-15 and houses on summit).</p></scopecontent><scopecontent id="aspace_548daeb5353f846acbaceb4ad45d4c7a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 1</emph></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_937ca82bb2e03892465cf8a5fea77f85" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hawikuh 3</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1918/1918">1918</unitdate><container id="aspace_512e51cedb60dd67699761d31c49f9fb" label="Mixed Materials [31924112438787]" type="box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_04f408df0d8de231f61945291d0b99a2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains field nos. 501-1000. 206p. [N.B. Numbering system changes here, giving sequential numbers for burials and their contents. See Smith, Woodbury, and Woodbury 1966, p.177 for explanation.]</p></scopecontent><scopecontent id="aspace_9e55cf4e9aa59bc6e88f1681cd30fc14"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 1</emph></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ae1ae741b77e952c290d54bd9647d3f9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hawikuh 4</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1919/1919">1919</unitdate><container id="aspace_00b5731f89abf0b4ec4a2ded78890b54" label="Mixed Materials [31924112438787]" type="box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3a66a27ed744054619bb3c76569bf366"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains rooms 103-166 and burials 1001-1256. 271p.</p></scopecontent><scopecontent id="aspace_1d0b9aa08c9697f56dc686a7fa126f4c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 1</emph></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_8294d6ef13f7ad013077c356a185fabf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hawikuh 5</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1920/1920">1920</unitdate><container id="aspace_a2f43951507eb4c8603b0038a7ea6e5b" label="Mixed Materials [31924112438787]" type="box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_18c054027151632461e12145c3d9a389"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains rooms 166-247. 187p.</p></scopecontent><scopecontent id="aspace_e7168d6f009b5e4bcbbe1a1c34303567"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 1</emph></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_3b5eca71dc7d880fd444cf60a29a6c04" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hawikuh 6</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1920/1920">1920</unitdate><container id="aspace_2a4695277b8603d6e0fe220a1d993b12" label="Mixed Materials [31924112438787]" type="box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ffded643391e20dc33f4a47d0fce2c4c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains rooms 248-272, house group F; ancient ruins west of Hawikuh, ruin I, skeletons 1-6; and site I, west of Hawikuh, the kiva. Also site II, skeleton 1; and continuation of notes from vol. 5. 78p.</p></scopecontent><scopecontent id="aspace_5201c45b59c63c5d78a265de3935c7fa"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 1</emph></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_a5916fdbe3152e5550c3406ce990e291" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hawikuh 7</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1921/1921">1921</unitdate><container id="aspace_eb3f4bb2e1121a6024d9221c6ab5320b" label="Mixed Materials [31924112438787]" type="box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e7e66a50eca6f6016020a30b4f79bf6e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains rooms 269-350. 266p.</p></scopecontent><scopecontent id="aspace_d569248724b6dd6325dcd9d9a929d3f2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 1</emph></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_84deba5a1ea63a17d6296c1f0f8df5bd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hawikuh 8</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1921/1921">1921</unitdate><unitdate normal="1923/1923">1923</unitdate><container id="aspace_68a96f42f9d07a81012fdde83578c17e" label="Mixed Materials [31924112438787]" type="box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1f68a8fc05a9ce7fd9078a022cce766d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains rooms 358-420; burials 1305-1307; the kiva under the plaza, section through plaza, levels 1-13; and burials 1290, 1295, 1296. 288p.</p></scopecontent><scopecontent id="aspace_051c47c03fac2801c02c04bcdd145106"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 1</emph></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_efe5656c9b58a3c545f8a65373c881ec" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hawikuh 9</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1923/1923">1923</unitdate><container id="aspace_8e18a894ab586f68cf3f796475f68133" label="Mixed Materials [31924112438787]" type="box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4ff774c26faae723203efd491ef9e9be"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Continues entries from vol. 8; contains rooms 421-444; burials in southern cemetery, 1277-1331. 164p.</p></scopecontent><scopecontent id="aspace_78ffc2a846d99974b366520600418549"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 1</emph></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_b74ba632c6004c0ea819d58fd24b7855" level="file"><did><unittitle>Nusbaum Church and Monastery</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1919/1919">1919</unitdate><container id="aspace_7afb64e8319ed4fed1c28acadc7a2d5e" label="Mixed Materials [31924112438787]" type="box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8cd545df72bf24cdda92905b2943eb44"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains descriptions and sketches of room 1-38. Also has Kechipauan burials 1-43. 192p.</p></scopecontent><scopecontent id="aspace_358584f7553f53c148faace46339246b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><emph render="italic">Also available second from the end on Reel 2</emph></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_0f9cc352a20ca49dcdf8e3ea7fb038ec" level="file"><did><unittitle>Kechipauan</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1919/1919">1919</unitdate><container id="aspace_d843485f7bcadb7d12997558fc1d786f" label="Mixed Materials [31924112438787]" type="box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1ad8bf77932077cd81a53ceebf77c7dc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains burials 44-91. Pages unnumbered.</p></scopecontent><scopecontent id="aspace_099382b3116c32eb42008879cec8b5b9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><emph render="italic">Also available at the end of Reel 2</emph></p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_3c628c2c4df84a624bc4cd541d091147" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series II. E. F. Coffin Notebooks</unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0fbd59eb6e30b58d8c4bdd3cebb37052"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Ordered below as they appear on the microfilm.</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_0f393b194e62b9a13068aa6fcadafabd" level="file"><did><unittitle>E. F. C. notebook #4</unittitle><container id="aspace_73dc117ffb3eaab3de4187500bc9d6e8" label="Mixed Materials [31924112438787]" type="box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b72df70c2a7e354ae605f7aa530d4906"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains sketches of the layout of rooms uncovered. Rooms 169-238. 97p.</p></scopecontent><scopecontent id="aspace_ed433e5ab65f02b1bcfd91ea09c89265"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 2</emph></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_5c3fdbaa03e8eeac57a0049fd2137859" level="file"><did><unittitle>E. F. C. notebook #1</unittitle><container id="aspace_ee19f9f6d43ddc59951c50929f9a4e70" label="Mixed Materials [31924112438787]" type="box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4043d01f514ced43f0a25083f9bdd165"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Rooms 220-380. 192p.</p></scopecontent><scopecontent id="aspace_c348e0d486248a5cabcbe3f2d09d51db"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 2</emph></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_7d5e088e797d85fa05d402f442e7bdd5" level="file"><did><unittitle>E. F. C. notebook #2</unittitle><container id="aspace_ba84c6d11c0e43fb66e207b4ae314422" label="Mixed Materials [31924112438787]" type="box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9ff9d0134bb64f7be6574a153725fef3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Rooms excavated in 1921; numbers vary, but includes room numbers through 415. Includes plans for kiva in plaza. 188p.</p></scopecontent><scopecontent id="aspace_9b1936fc0ed6cd746a07c469bc337535"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 2</emph></p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_efcc946fb9c04a83ad66f09432ac1f4b" level="file"><did><unittitle>E. F. C. notebook #3</unittitle><container id="aspace_32aa41b6ab6efab9f933d016d2d3e692" label="Mixed Materials [31924112438787]" type="box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e6d9d3f8f54a3acc7390067dcd246d40"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Rooms excavated in 1923, including rooms 416-445. 48p. Also includes 3 pages of "Notes for Hodge."</p></scopecontent><scopecontent id="aspace_27cf59585aa1b2398debe04c1e7692b8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><emph render="italic">Also available on Reel 2</emph></p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_1a662be17e3609d9b1914d4070cfc7b0" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series III. Foldered Material</unittitle></did><c02 id="aspace_69ff16b661201c56c1fceb7564a5afae" level="file"><did><unittitle>Microfilming information</unittitle><container id="aspace_9b136d5605de03980a89dc2d86cd448d" label="Mixed Materials [31924112438787]" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_09c48e3b1c1453de4a7d4b11c9b2ad68" parent="aspace_9b136d5605de03980a89dc2d86cd448d" type="folder">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_e774d2b9ce9ac578b202e559278b5d73" level="file"><did><unittitle>Printout of Cambridge University catalog</unittitle><container id="aspace_43c848c5d30d35c3a000620d8db8b4ad" label="Mixed Materials [31924112438787]" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_4ef5a43793138de2540a5e5cc0270342" parent="aspace_43c848c5d30d35c3a000620d8db8b4ad" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_707b4d728eb57d34e303074af3d6ca73"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Items held by Cambridge regarding the expedition.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_bf865a5193d2732d895c51a16debad2a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cambridge University - Correspondence between museums - Photocopies</unittitle><container id="aspace_f2b707033e685457e85446aa0c505e06" label="Mixed Materials [31924112438787]" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_a361d5fdb3e85f0aafc3409f6426d000" parent="aspace_f2b707033e685457e85446aa0c505e06" type="folder">3</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_e7aca35e9b376b14dae2a69243751263" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ketchipuan - Skeletal remains - Photocopies from Cambridge University</unittitle><container id="aspace_f7128d9f661d2bcf78c1d7de93a046aa" label="Mixed Materials [31924112438787]" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_65626e23660dbc2173aed4141aa9239f" parent="aspace_f7128d9f661d2bcf78c1d7de93a046aa" type="folder">4</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_1dca6758f3f8dcbf0c147a57bb541394" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ketchipuan - Diaries - Photocopies from Cambridge University</unittitle><container id="aspace_6bd5f95d34b5903798a27c8fad89c9d1" label="Mixed Materials [31924112438787]" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_1209f537228f96726ed6355e1f54d25e" parent="aspace_6bd5f95d34b5903798a27c8fad89c9d1" type="folder">5</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_668944188324ac2df933f3122a9360c9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ketchipuan - Specimen shipped - Photocopies from Cambridge University</unittitle><container id="aspace_e21572f00089d5ee8c05cf81da818711" label="Mixed Materials [31924112438787]" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_85208d717c97444025c0f41af76b32a9" parent="aspace_e21572f00089d5ee8c05cf81da818711" type="folder">6</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ab68a029b8be6ad67860293416cad30e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ketchipuan - Burial data - Photocopies from Cambridge University</unittitle><container id="aspace_d3ae805f7452024d69ce97aa807fd547" label="Mixed Materials [31924112438787]" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_5838a4ae85a42b30c2ed65e43847d50c" parent="aspace_d3ae805f7452024d69ce97aa807fd547" type="folder">7</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_1af70819f519afb64057740af1ef00b7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ketchipuan - Field notebooks - Photocopies from Cambridge University</unittitle><container id="aspace_d74173db03649ca557e9a52a6e986274" label="Mixed Materials [31924112438787]" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_22d37b92bf6c9438909cc33640b280ea" parent="aspace_d74173db03649ca557e9a52a6e986274" type="folder">8, 9</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_d3850fe44bcdc2657cfd27d9d0d3ad15" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ketchipuan - General notes and diary - Photocopies from Cambridge University</unittitle><container id="aspace_d088adb1ee3b312733cd60647af5ddde" label="Mixed Materials [31924112438787]" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_094b8daed7939a9262fd654f63adea2e" parent="aspace_d088adb1ee3b312733cd60647af5ddde" type="folder">10</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_20a88fcd953105d83c2602b68e65436f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Architectural Notes</unittitle><container id="aspace_16dbcec00f363f4db88bd37c17f57b96" label="Mixed Materials [31924112438787]" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_112fa9f5c3d6dda3b4034ed3e30cdc92" parent="aspace_16dbcec00f363f4db88bd37c17f57b96" type="folder">11</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_66075fb1d6b4d684f0f89dcf6b75314a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cities of Cibola during 16th and 17th centuries</unittitle><container id="aspace_a7413f47caab4f141c9665b909ad1c1c" label="Mixed Materials [31924112438787]" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_5bcdf190744aa654beb64a4c338978c0" parent="aspace_a7413f47caab4f141c9665b909ad1c1c" type="folder">12</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_fda16ce48272f1eee86a174c9a58cb04" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photos of Excavations at Zuni with captions for publication</unittitle><container id="aspace_b57ad2a589c0565fb5368f6fb4be073d" label="Mixed Materials [31924112438787]" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_331880dc7a8f637ad2cc7fae25493d57" parent="aspace_b57ad2a589c0565fb5368f6fb4be073d" type="folder">13</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_7f42c396de2dd7170a416a24bdd107a8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Miscellaneous letters from Indian people</unittitle><container id="aspace_62d5503689d3ee0fb6e158da29019b7e" label="Mixed Materials [31924112438787]" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_938ed15c753a312df33f633b7b07a982" parent="aspace_62d5503689d3ee0fb6e158da29019b7e" type="folder">14</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_64294a250e5a970d82c34fef5f9b2241" level="file"><did><unittitle>Varga visits Zuni and other notes</unittitle><container id="aspace_1fec3980857456570845800913aa7989" label="Mixed Materials [31924112438787]" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_14027f8f1de62c3115ba86861bfb2927" parent="aspace_1fec3980857456570845800913aa7989" type="folder">15</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_40dc72aecba671b30c3180cd3359413b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Square Kiva</unittitle><container id="aspace_ce636518cd64064e4684fa071e37f1c2" label="Mixed Materials [31924112438787]" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_4006735b1d72b7b563b4ff531d992c9c" parent="aspace_ce636518cd64064e4684fa071e37f1c2" type="folder">16</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_2ba58d36c04fe219421d6414a66fd4a4" level="file"><did><unittitle>The plaza trench and its disclosures</unittitle><container id="aspace_80d9dcfb7c03b22710ede40f11f719d8" label="Mixed Materials [31924112438787]" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_754d6c458b7342e5bf8d31a71e78adda" parent="aspace_80d9dcfb7c03b22710ede40f11f719d8" type="folder">17</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_eedf600c7049ab36e7256717fbbca310" level="file"><did><unittitle>The plaza trench manuscript and tables</unittitle><container id="aspace_dbaef3a51e0061af18958a9fbd82c8f0" label="Mixed Materials [31924112438787]" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_055bde013b60fdb49b7a7ced433d2480" parent="aspace_dbaef3a51e0061af18958a9fbd82c8f0" type="folder">18</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_4b3d7136acc0342fc03bb1531853da98" level="file"><did><unittitle>Burials within the church</unittitle><container id="aspace_e89e3182f9589e14985b0ddf7b6d17b1" label="Mixed Materials [31924112438787]" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_7fddcc3ed00b1d166f3336c567470a2f" parent="aspace_e89e3182f9589e14985b0ddf7b6d17b1" type="folder">19</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_e928248b32ffd2695bddbd04c1c282b9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Plant remains</unittitle><container id="aspace_0333e1581b8fdf08d38783dcb662a988" label="Mixed Materials [31924112438787]" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_d52fcdfbdba4af6dec2b14bc10485a9d" parent="aspace_0333e1581b8fdf08d38783dcb662a988" type="folder">20</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_f8340f0012082fb3d9dc1a0a9dc4aba7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hawikuh waste</unittitle><container id="aspace_3ff74612ee1a4a664530478c9747756a" label="Mixed Materials [31924112438787]" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_d1e000382fe2f4df39f2bc3fbf7855fd" parent="aspace_3ff74612ee1a4a664530478c9747756a" type="folder">21</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_d36535ff21c7c938379af44ee93d63a6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Miscellaneous notes and photos from Hawikuh</unittitle><container id="aspace_913a859c414c6923e2cd9779b0ba3452" label="Mixed Materials [31924112438787]" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_026e4b967b3f5c97146d9de4ab842069" parent="aspace_913a859c414c6923e2cd9779b0ba3452" type="folder">22</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_cf6d0e11cf02fd22f93f29c48db8cfd4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bones from Hawikua</unittitle><container id="aspace_be2fa1d8fc3e433cc3590afaa22d2328" label="Mixed Materials [31924112438787]" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_243c9525b6fc1c91fc149022341b4158" parent="aspace_be2fa1d8fc3e433cc3590afaa22d2328" type="folder">23</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_07a164d65985cc5602439dd31eba9cdf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ceremonial deposits in the Hawikuh cemetery</unittitle><container id="aspace_12ea0b56b9a8d0bb80c7c0ee76fa0da6" label="Mixed Materials [31924112438787]" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_6bacfc923dece7362d0421fbfc39ea45" parent="aspace_12ea0b56b9a8d0bb80c7c0ee76fa0da6" type="folder">24</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_d4ba0d600f1c26ec9540ed47e721c6d5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Forms of burial and miscellaneous notes</unittitle><container id="aspace_ea8b85d79c21d36a12f43b5649e851ba" label="Mixed Materials [31924112438787]" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_606fe299477d6278e76a7bf0b9016710" parent="aspace_ea8b85d79c21d36a12f43b5649e851ba" type="folder">25</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_5df178e570818cb3760dd14e8a1a7620" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sequence of pottery at Hawikuh</unittitle><container id="aspace_afe2e136c88aefa9eb3afd3c9f582b65" label="Mixed Materials [31924112438787]" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_3ad1ae5479c7ad1967850f6552896d1c" parent="aspace_afe2e136c88aefa9eb3afd3c9f582b65" type="folder">26</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_60af0c87f505c203918a0e9c1c0954fb" level="file"><did><unittitle>List of 216 burials with associated objects</unittitle><container id="aspace_328730b476b76585781c0cc76926b870" label="Mixed Materials [31924112438787]" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_0aaad814a05d6ecd84142645ee7bb54b" parent="aspace_328730b476b76585781c0cc76926b870" type="folder">27</container></did></c02></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
