<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead audience="internal" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US">RMM08811</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Carl Irving Wheat correspondence<num>8811</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections</publisher><address><addressline>2B Carl A. Kroch Library</addressline><addressline>Cornell University</addressline><addressline>Ithaca, NY 14853</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 607-255-3530</addressline><addressline>Fax Number: 607-255-9524</addressline><addressline>rareref@cornell.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://rare.library.cornell.edu/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://rare.library.cornell.edu/" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2023-07-03 00:15:33 UTC</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is written in: <language langcode="und" scriptcode="Zyyy">Undetermined, Code for undetermined script script</language>.</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Carl Irving Wheat correspondence</unittitle>
    <origination audience="internal" label="Creator">
      <persname authfilenumber="n 85050468" source="lcsh">Wheat, Carl I. (Carl Irving), 1892-1966</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>8811</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.4 cubic feet.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1945" type="inclusive">1938-1945</unitdate>
    <abstract audience="internal" id="aspace_ac01e54ddcd5bb55ea607a3c0ccbdad2">Materials assembled by Carl Wheat concerning the publication of Hu Shih's "China, Too, is Fighting to Defend a Way of Life" by the Grabhorn Press.</abstract>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_1445366d971b81ac2593003b72d76d7d" label="Mixed Materials [31924113901718]" type="box">1 </container>
    <unitid type="bibid">15580292</unitid>
  </did>
  <scopecontent audience="internal" id="aspace_a4db76fe1f2a95d904939a8aa8ffcf65">
    <head>Content Description</head>
<p>Collection contains correspondence with Hu Shih regarding his address titled "China, too, is Fighting to Defend a Way of Life" and its publication by the Grabhorn Press, correspondence with Chinese Embassy officials including Madame Chiang Kai-shek (Mayling Soong Chiang), correspondence with Washington figures including President Franklin D. Roosevelt, correspondence between Wheat and publishers, manuscript material including Hu Shih's original 37 page speech, pamphlets inscribed by Hu Shih, and other ephemera.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <bioghist audience="internal" id="aspace_b069336da4ffda2537d534cf68d86c63">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Carl Irving Wheat was born in Holliston, Massachusetts on December 5, 1892. Wheat graduated from Pomona College in 1915 and Harvard Law School in 1920. He joined the legal staff of the Railroad Commission of California in 1922 and started private practice in 1929 in Los Angeles. Wheat was involved with the Historical Society of Southern California and became the chairman of its publication committee, frequently contributing his own publications. His most significant work was <title>Mapping the Transmississippi West, 1540-1861</title> in five volumes.  In 1950, Wheat was elected to the American Antiquarian Society. In 1959, he was named a fellow of the California Historical Society and was awarded the Henry R. Wagner Memorial Medal.</p>  </bioghist>
  <bioghist audience="internal" id="aspace_b8cff29cc810fcbbc0bda889ad8c7148">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Huh Shih was born in Shanghai, China on December 17, 1891. He was a Chinese diplomat, essayist, literary scholar, philosopher, and politician. In August 1910, Hu Shih was sent to study agriculture at Cornell University. In 1912, he changed his major to philosophy and literature. After receiving his undergraduate degree, he went on to study philosophy at Teachers College, Columbia University. He returned to China to lecture at Peking University. Hu is widely recognized today as a key contributor to Chinese liberalism. He was influential in the May Fourth Movement, one of the leaders of China's New Cultural Movement, was a president of Peking University, and in 1939 was nominated for a Nobel Prize in literature. He served as ambassador of Republic of China to the United States between 1938 and 1942.</p>  </bioghist>
  <separatedmaterial audience="internal" id="aspace_162d64d571b7c891595830aff7429fa0">
    <head>Separated Materials</head>
<p>"China, too, is Fighting to Defend a Way of Life" - deluxe edition, one of 100 copies reserved for Hu's personal use, presentation copy inscribed by Hu Shih to Carl Wheat. Housed in red Morocco-backed slipcase and red cloth chemise.</p><p>"China, too, is Fighting to Defend a Way of Life" - standard edition, in boards with jacket, with Wheat's compliments card.</p>  </separatedmaterial>
  <prefercite audience="internal" id="aspace_70891b14cd5d55234b2db86ebc0ed3af">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Carl Irving Wheat correspondence, #8811.  Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library.</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">World War II</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">China -- Foreign relations -- United States.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">China -- Politics and government -- 20th century.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">China -- History -- 20th century.</geogname>
    <persname source="lcsh">Hu, Shi, 1891-1962</persname>
    <persname source="ingest">Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945</persname>
    <persname audience="internal" authfilenumber="n 50059493" source="lcsh">Chiang, May-ling Soong, 1897-2003</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <unitid type="bibid">15580292</unitid>
  <dsc><c01 audience="internal" id="aspace_90b008d6e19e06a02f3303a40ca18d70" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series I. Hu Shih manuscript materials</unittitle></did><c02 audience="internal" id="aspace_90e389ba7610e27fed9931c43645a947" level="item"><did><unittitle>Calligraphic manuscript of the book's Chinese title brushed by Hu</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" certainty="approximate" datechar="creation" era="ce">Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_7ea81cb5b6ee8f9945a8f7f2ce4497a2" label="Mixed Materials [31924113901718]" type="box">1 </container><container id="aspace_8d4dcbfda0a3e28889b0106ef3c0b331" parent="aspace_7ea81cb5b6ee8f9945a8f7f2ce4497a2" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent audience="internal" id="aspace_793b85b1ac18be35cd59bfd22efcb70b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Calligraphic manuscript of the book's Chinese title brushed by Hu.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 audience="internal" id="aspace_cbef671296f25e3d46cb08bbd090827c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Original manuscript</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" certainty="approximate" datechar="creation" era="ce">Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_bf1edf0b9b625ccdc92405c960dd3018" label="Mixed Materials [31924113901718]" type="box">1 </container><container id="aspace_4773311046a093a77f2af370f0f19d13" parent="aspace_bf1edf0b9b625ccdc92405c960dd3018" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent audience="internal" id="aspace_8e190e7b5c3fb5bebf7c385c273fd69e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Original 37-leaf manuscript of Hu's speech. Includes handwritten and typed pages, with his annotations and revisions.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 audience="internal" id="aspace_d185fd4fc119035c10088c32a9c91db9" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series II. Pamphlets inscribed by Hu Shih to Wheat</unittitle></did><c02 audience="internal" id="aspace_34cd435632bc9a604fbae566e063ccb2" level="item"><did><unittitle>"The Conflict of Ideologies"</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate" datechar="creation" normal="1941-11/1942-09-04" type="inclusive">1941, 1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_14903fbba83e84e6353df3a6187669d2" label="Mixed Materials [31924113901718]" type="box">1 </container><container id="aspace_9a3d6c2ab9a757235b06f0a16138a214" parent="aspace_14903fbba83e84e6353df3a6187669d2" type="folder">2</container></did></c02><c02 audience="internal" id="aspace_29ba889eb0ff429933cbc1fc18431d71" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Japan's War in China"</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate" datechar="creation" normal="1938/1942-09-04" type="inclusive">1938, 1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_18960b597669232d010194ebd94e391b" label="Mixed Materials [31924113901718]" type="box">1 </container><container id="aspace_0eb60513c4a62f73362fc4676a19ada8" parent="aspace_18960b597669232d010194ebd94e391b" type="folder">2</container></did></c02><c02 audience="internal" id="aspace_c40394bbf093a148220c6e9c7f19b080" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Woman's Place in Chinese History"</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate" datechar="creation" normal="1939/1942-09-04" type="inclusive">1939, 1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_cad575c4f2d653a4c172e74dd950e222" label="Mixed Materials [31924113901718]" type="box">1 </container><container id="aspace_8fe4a32d1f3f214232ce7ba89028e80b" parent="aspace_cad575c4f2d653a4c172e74dd950e222" type="folder">2</container></did></c02></c01><c01 audience="internal" id="aspace_82c8b89aafec4da871fa8b38b795df70" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series III. Correspondence</unittitle></did><c02 audience="internal" id="aspace_d11ecc14d5519b5897edac986c0428ac" level="file"><did><unittitle>Between Wheat and Hu, Madame Chiang Kai-Shek, and Chinese embassy officials</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate" datechar="creation" normal="1942-03-24/1945-12" type="inclusive">1942-03-24-1945-12</unitdate><container id="aspace_04a7cbadea883f6d01772efa4e59ff59" label="Mixed Materials [31924113901718]" type="box">1 </container><container id="aspace_326e5d6d10c4630ba831b8d2fc59da85" parent="aspace_04a7cbadea883f6d01772efa4e59ff59" type="folder">3</container></did><index audience="internal" id="aspace_45464865155115d5f085b0be8aba9997"><p>24 March 1942, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Dr. Kan Lee.</p>
<p>18 June 1942, TLS, from Dr. Kan Lee to Wheat; grouped with 29 June 1942, TLS, from Dr. Kan Lee to Wheat, with enclosed photostat copy of Hu's calligraphic instruction of the book's title; and 2 manuscript leaves of Wheat's drafts for the colophon. </p>
<p>26 June 1942, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Dr. Kan Lee; grouped with manuscript instructions from Wheat to his secretary). </p>
<p>2 September 1942, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Dr. Kan Lee. </p>
<p>2 September 1942, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Hu. </p>
<p>6 September 1942, manuscript draft letter from Wheat to Hu. </p>
<p>13 October 1942, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Edith Phillips. </p>
<p>15 October 1942, TLS, from Edith Phillips to Wheat.</p>
<p>16 November 1942, TLS, from Edith Phillips to Wheat; grouped with clipping of Edward Tinker's review of the publication in the New York Times Book Review, 1 November 1942. </p>
<p>23 November 1942, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Hu; grouped with single-leaf typed poem, CC, by Wheat and 92 x 90 mm photograph of Edwin Grabhorn. </p>
<p>5 December 1942, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Hu. </p>
<p>10 December 1942, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Madame Chiang Kai-Shek.</p>
<p>12 January 1943, TLS, from Edith Phillips to Wheat.</p>
<p>29 March 1943, ALS, from Hu to Wheat, with enclosed clipping from a California newspaper. </p>
<p>14 April 1943, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Hu. </p>
<p>December 1945, handwritten Christmas greetings from Hu to Wheat. </p></index></c02><c02 audience="internal" id="aspace_d2c7dfd0e7fbe39dad517a0126887c1c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Between Wheat and Grabhorn Press</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate" datechar="creation" normal="1942-11-21/1942-12-08" type="inclusive">1942-11-21-1942-12-08</unitdate><container id="aspace_811f281563738fcfded80be98d4d3ed9" label="Mixed Materials [31924113901718]" type="box">1 </container><container id="aspace_7edcedd9a3584b3a8c17ce30aa72bad9" parent="aspace_811f281563738fcfded80be98d4d3ed9" type="folder">4</container></did><index audience="internal" id="aspace_8568861e72ad32e2cf8c89f02ed53185"><p>21 November 1942, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Edwin Grabhorn. </p>
<p>24 November 1942, TD, retained CC, draft telegram from Wheat to Arthur Kent. </p>
<p>25 November 1942, Western Union telegram, from Arthur Kent to Wheat. </p>
<p>8 December 1942, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Edwin Grabhorn.</p></index></c02><c02 audience="internal" id="aspace_4e8957c986a4073f5d878dd1e0ad8134" level="file"><did><unittitle>Between Wheat and Hu and influential Washington figures</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate" datechar="creation" normal="1942-09-19/1943-02-12" type="inclusive">1942-09-19-1943-02-12</unitdate><container id="aspace_e4d3e9aceb51cfcd994955b3b7c95971" label="Mixed Materials [31924113901718]" type="box">1 </container><container id="aspace_2f544853fb1a3f6502344fbb1952b40f" parent="aspace_e4d3e9aceb51cfcd994955b3b7c95971" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent audience="internal" id="aspace_53c5f6cff74158d59985a5da759848f1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes correspondence from FDR and members of his administration.</p></scopecontent><index audience="internal" id="aspace_0a4131232f79df4f8c14dfa6d2adb585"><p>19 September 1942, ALS, from John T. Whiting (Office of the Undersecretary, War Department) to Wheat. </p>
<p>24 September 1942, TLS, from Under Secretary of State Sumner Welles to Hu. Includes photostat copy of the same. </p>
<p>25 September 1942, TLS, from Secretary of State Cordell Hull to Hu. Includes photostat copy of the same. </p>
<p>28 September 1942, TLS, from Stanley K. Hornbeck (Advisor on Political Relations, Department of State) to Wheat; 6-leaf typed CC of Hornbeck's introductory remarks on the occasion of Hu Shih addressing the Cosmos Club, 4 May 1942; 29 September 1942, TL, retained CC, from Wheat's secretary to Hornbeck; 13 October 1942, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Hornbeck (and 1 duplicate). </p>
<p>15 October 1942, TLS, from President Franklin D. Roosevelt to Hu, with original envelope; Photostat copy and 7 facsimiles of same. </p>
<p>29 October 1942, TLS, from Coleman Rosenberger (US Senate) to Wheat; 31 October 1942, TL, retained CC, from Wheat's secretary to Rosenberger; 2 January 1943, TLS, from Rosenberger to Wheat. </p>
<p>5 January 1943, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to President Franklin D. Roosevelt; 11 January 1943, TLS, from Grace G. Tully (Private Secretary to Roosevelt) to Wheat. </p>
<p>5 January 1943, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Frankfurter; 6 January 1943, TLS, from Justice Felix Frankfurter (SCOTUS) to Wheat. </p>
<p>5 January 1943, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Chief Justice Harlan F. Stone (SCOTUS); 7 January 1943, TLS, from Stone to Wheat; 8 January 1943, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Stone </p>
<p>5 January 1943, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Vice President Henry A. Wallace; 12 January 1943, TLS, from Mary Huss (Personal Secretary to Wallace) to Wheat. </p>
<p>7 January 1943, TLS, from Basil Manly (Vice Chairman, Federal Power Commission), to Wheat.</p>
<p>7 January 1943, TLS, from Secretary of State Cordell Hull to Wheat.</p>
<p>12 January 1943, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Nelson A. Rockefeller (Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs, Office for Emergency Management, Executive Office of the President); 14 January 1943, TLS, from Rockefeller to Wheat. </p>
<p>15 January 1943, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Under Secretary of State Sumner Welles; 18 January 1943, TLS, from Welles to Wheat. </p>
<p>15 January 1943, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Willys R. Peck (Chief of the Chinese Section, Division of Cultural Relations, Department of State); 12 February 1943, TLS, from Peck to Wheat. </p>
<p>20 January 1943, TL, from Associate Justice Justin Miller (US Court of Appeals) to Wheat.</p>
<p>25 January 1943, TLS, from Colonel Frank W. Wozencraft (Office of the Joint Chiefs) to Wheat.</p>
<p>26 January 1943, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Earnest M. Kai (Secretary of Hawaii); Undated ALS (postcard), from Kai to Wheat. </p>
<p>26 January 1943, TLS, from Maxwell M. Hamilton (Chief, Division of Far Eastern Affairs, Department of State) to Wheat; 27 January 1943, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Hamilton; 28 January 1943, TLS, from Hamilton to Wheat.  </p></index></c02><c02 audience="internal" id="aspace_f6840b6b8ce6efdbba7479e0e534e91b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Between Wheat and Edward Larocque Tinker</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate" datechar="creation" normal="1942-09-15/1942-11-25" type="inclusive">1942-09-15-1942-11-25</unitdate><container id="aspace_f6a6f0b40b4a32540258277e8db869da" label="Mixed Materials [31924113901718]" type="box">1 </container><container id="aspace_31268c3c37168183cc16647d7396573f" parent="aspace_f6a6f0b40b4a32540258277e8db869da" type="folder">6</container></did><index audience="internal" id="aspace_65430c60054feff6c589ccfb00852ecc"><p>Undated, ALS, from Tinker to Wheat; 2-leaf manuscript of Wheat's draft reply. </p>
<p>15 September 1942, ALS, from Tinker to Wheat. </p>
<p>2 November 1942, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Tinker. </p>
<p>15 November 1942, TLS, from Tinker to Wheat. </p>
<p>25 November 1942, ALS, from Tinker to Wheat. </p></index></c02><c02 audience="internal" id="aspace_8e71d78a66b25995eb603618569776da" level="file"><did><unittitle>Between Wheat, the Grabhorn Press, and others concerning the distribution of copies</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942-09-08/1943-06-30" type="inclusive">1942-09-08-1943-06-30</unitdate><container id="aspace_8a45945f2afa1d4e80f8b6f6da0407d6" label="Mixed Materials [31924113901718]" type="box">1 </container><container id="aspace_bffbf3ce6008c0433dd26efc11081f52" parent="aspace_8a45945f2afa1d4e80f8b6f6da0407d6" type="folder">7-9</container></did><index audience="internal" id="aspace_1dc266c0fe69cba68b70205a9701475a"><head>Folder 7</head><p>Undated, hand-completed acknowledgement card from G.F. Bowerman (Chairman of the Cosmos Club) to Wheat. </p>
<p>Undated, TLS, from Thomas W. Norris to Wheat.</p>
<p>Undated, signed acknowledgement card from State Librarian of New York to Wheat.</p>
<p>Undated, signed acknowledgement card from Harold Bingham, Indiana State Library. </p>
<p>Undated, hand-completed acknowledgement card from Library Associates of Occidental College to Wheat. </p>
<p>8 September 1942, hand-completed acknowledgement card from Henry H. Curran (University Club Library) to Wheat. </p>
<p>11 September 1942, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Charles K. Adams, with duplicate of same; 11 September 1942, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Dr. Teodoro Becu, with duplicate of same; 11 September 1942, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Lee Stopple, with duplicate of same; 13 September 1942, TLS, from Teodoro Bedu to Wheat. </p>
<p>12 September 1942, hand-completed acknowledgement card from Librarian of Congress to Wheat. </p>
<p>17 September 1942, TLS, from Thomas W. Streeter to Wheat. </p>
<p>18 September 1942, TLS, from secretary of Theodore Gray to Wheat. </p>
<p>21 September 1942, TLS, from Edward W. Allen to Wheat. </p>
<p>21 September 1942, TLS, from Evelyn Steel Mills (Librarian, Mills College) to Wheat. </p>
<p>21 September 1942, autographed acknowledgement card from corresponding secretary of California Historical Society to Wheat; 22 September 1942, TLS, from corresponding secretary of California Historical Society to Wheat. </p>
<p>21 September 1942, TLS, from secretary of the Bohemian Club to Wheat. </p>
<p>21 September 1942, TLS, from A.F. Adams to Wheat. </p>
<p>22 September 1942, TLS, from Frederick C. Cordes to Wheat. </p>
<p>22 September 1942, TLS, from Don Emery to Wheat. </p>
<p>22 September 1942, TLS, from "Bill" (Earl O. Shreve) to Wheat. </p>
<p>23 September 1942, ALS, from Phillip J. Wickster to Wheat. </p>
<p>23 September 1942, ALS, from Garfield David Merner to Wheat. </p>
<p>23 September 1942, TLS, from Frank Phillips to Wheat. </p>
<p>23 September 1942, TLS from State Librarian of California to Wheat. </p>
<p>23 September 1942, TLS, from President and Director of Libraries, Stanford University, to Wheat. </p>
<p>23 September 1942, ALS, from Valenti Angelo to Wheat. </p>
<p>24 September 1942, TLS, from Ernest Dawson (Dawson's Bookshop) to Wheat. </p>
<p>24 September 1942, TLS, from Charles Morton Jr. (Assistant Editor, the Atlantic Monthly) to Wheat. </p>
<p>24 September 1942, TLS, from Assistant Librarian, Pomona College, to Wheat. </p>
<p>24 September 1942, ALS, from Charles K. Edmonds (President, Pomona College) to Wheat. </p>
<p>29 September 1942, TLS, from secretary of Jean Monnet to Wheat. </p>
<p>6 October 1942, TLS, from secretary of H.P. Mahoney to Wheat. </p>
<p>7 October 1942, TLS, from Alfred Kohlberg to Wheat. </p>
<p>8 October 1942, TLS, from Colonel Karl R. Bendesten (Director of Wartime Civil Control Administration, San Francisco) to Wheat. </p>
<p>13 October 1942, TLS, from Hunter Gary to Wheat. </p>
<p>14 October 1942, TLS, from Ernest Sweetland to Wheat. </p>
<p>15 October 1942, from representative of United States Potash Company to Wheat. </p>
<p>16 October 1942, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Nicholas Roosevelt (New York Herald Tribune), with duplicate of same; 30 October 1942, TLS, from Roosevelt to Wheat. </p>
<p>1 November 1942, handwritten postcard from Mrs. W. Murray Crane to Grabhorn Press. </p>
<p>1 November 1942, TLS, from Dr. H.M. Marvin to Grabhorn Press. </p>
<p>1 November 1942, TLS, from Dr. John B. Solley to Grabhorn Press; 15 December 1942, TLS, from Solley to Wheat; 18 December 1942, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Solley. </p>
<p>1 November 1942, ALS, from Lieutenant Charles M. Fleischner to Grabhorn Press; 10 December 1942, TLS, from Fleischner to Wheat; 11 December 1942, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Fleischner. </p>
<p>1 November 1942, TLS, from Anthony Arch Kline to Grabhorn Press, with Wheat's handwritten draft reply below the signature; 23 November 1942, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Kline; 26 November 1942, TLS, from Kline to Wheat; 5 December 1942, TL, from Wheat to Kline; 8 December 1942, TLS, from Kline to Wheat; 12 December 1942, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Kline; 15 December 1942, TLS, from Kline to Wheat. </p>
<p>3 November 1942, AL, unsigned, to Grabhorn press. </p>
<p>3 November 1942, TLS, from James T. Babb (Assistant Librarian, Yale) to Wheat; 11 December 1942, signed acknowledgement letter from Babb; 11 December 1942, TLS, from Babb to Wheat. </p>
<p>3 November 1942, TLS, from William F. Maag to Wheat; 7 November 1942, TL, retained CC, from secretary of Wheat to Maag; 23 November 1942, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Maag; 25 November 1942, TLS, from Maag to Wheat; 5 December 1942, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Maag.  </p>
<p>4 November 1942, ALS, from Elizabeth Haurein to Grabhorn Press. </p>
<p>4 November 1942, TLS, from Frank A. Libbon to Wheat; 7 November 1942, TL, retained CC, from secretary of Wheat to Libbon; 22 December 1942, TLS, from Libbon to Wheat. </p>
<p>4 November 1942, handwritten postcard, from Anne C. Studnicka (Librarian, Slocum-Truax High School Library) to Grabhorn press; 23 November 1942, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Studnicka. </p>
<p>4 November 1942, TLS, from Detroit Flower Growers, Inc. to Wheat; TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Detroit Flower Growers, Inc. </p></index><index audience="internal" id="aspace_17adf7a955bc5514da422e58100c5d99"><head>Folder 8</head><p>5 November 1942, TLS, from Nathan Boone Williams to Hu; typed note from Edwin Grabhorn about Williams. </p>
<p>5 November 1942, ALS, from Agnes M. Pearce to Grabhorn Press. </p>
<p>5 November 1942, TLS, from Willis Kerr (Librarian, Claremont Colleges) to Wheat; 27 February 1943, signed acknowledgement letter from Kerr to Wheat. </p>
<p>5 November 1942, TLS, from Kenneth R. Shaffer (Order Librarian, Indiana State Library) to Grabhorn Press. </p>
<p>5 November 1942, TLS, from James Drake (bookseller) to Grabhorn Press; 23 November 1942, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Drake; 3 December 1942, TLS, from Drake to Wheat; 7 December 1942, ALS, from Ethelwyn Doolittle to Wheat. </p>
<p>5 November 1942, handwritten postcard from Phillip Dfesling to Grabhorn Press. </p>
<p>6 November 1942, handwritten postcard from Charles K. Adams to Wheat. </p>
<p>6 November 1942, TLS, from L. Jeston Hampton (Central State College) to Grabhorn Press. </p>
<p>6 November 1942, TLS, from L. Douglas (Zamorano Club) to Wheat. </p>
<p>9 November 1942, TLS, from Leonard Balz (St. Louis Public Library) to Grabhorn Press; 12 December 1942, handwritten note by Wheat; 24 December 1942, TLS, from Balz to Wheat. </p>
<p>9 November 1942, TLS, from William W. Clary to Wheat. </p>
<p>10 November 1941, handwritten postcard from Grace Clifford James to Grabhorn Press. </p>
<p>10 November 1942, TLS, from Harry Weinberger to Grabhorn Press; 17 December 1942, TLS, from Weinberger to Wheat. </p>
<p>10 November 1942, TLS, from Homer D. Crotty to Wheat. </p>
<p>10 November 1942, TLS, from H.G. Montillon to Grabhorn Press; 21 December 1942, TLs from Montillon to Wheat. </p>
<p>10 November 1942, TLS, from F.W. Hodge (Southwest Museum) to Wheat. </p>
<p>11 November 1942, handwritten postcard from H.H. Chang to Grabhorn Press. </p>
<p>11 November 1942, TLS, from Leslie Edgar Bliss (Librarian, the Huntington) to Wheat. </p>
<p>11 November 1942, TLS, from Dana Jones to Wheat. </p>
<p>11 November 1942, TLS, from Morgan Gunst (Master of the Press, Roxburghe Club) to Wheat; 15 January 1942, TLS, retained CC, from Wheat to Gunst. </p>
<p>12 November 1942, TLS, from Ethel Lansing (New York State Library) to Wheat. </p>
<p>12 November 1942, ALS, from William W. Smith to Grabhorn Press. </p>
<p>12 November 1942, TLS, from Phillip Duschnes to Wheat. </p>
<p>13 November 1942, TLS, from J.G. Leidig to Grabhorn Press. </p>
<p>15 November 1942, TLS, from W.W. Robinson to Wheat. </p>
<p>15 November 1942, ALS, from J. Gregg Layne to Wheat. </p>
<p>16 November 1942, signed purchase order from Library, Colonial Williamsburg, to Grabhorn press. </p>
<p>17 November 1942, signed typed postcard from F. Rosenblum (Gotham Book Mart) to Wheat; 23 November 1942, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Rosenblum; 30 November 1942, TLS, from Rosenblum to Wheat. </p>
<p>18 November 1942, TLS, from "Cobbie" (Call Bulletin San Francisco) to Wheat. </p>
<p>19 November 1942, ALS, from Mildred R. Bancroft to John S. Clapp. </p>
<p>19 November 1942, typed card from Mrs. W. Murray Crane to Wheat. </p>
<p>21 November 1942, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Henry R. Wagner; 30 November 1942, TLS, from Wagner to Wheat. </p>
<p>21 November 1942, TLS, from Blanche Prichard McCrum (Librarian, Wellesley College) to Wheat. </p>
<p>22 November 1942, TLS, from Gladys Thomas to Grabhorn Press.</p>
<p>23 November 1942, ALS, from Wallace B. Phillip to Wheat. </p>
<p>24 November 1942, TLS, from Charles Sessler (bookseller) to Wheat. </p>
<p>26 November 1942, ALS, from Helen Makepeace Lillie to Wheat, written on 23 November 1942, TLS, from Wheat to Concord Book Shop; 9 December 1942, ALS, from Lillie to Wheat. </p>
<p>26 November 1942, TLS, from Brentano's, New York, to Wheat. </p>
<p>26 November 1942, ALS, from Donald Charnock to Wheat. </p>
<p>2 December 1942, TLS, from M.S. Slocum to Wheat. </p>
<p>8 December 1942, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Mrs. Alfred L. Castle. </p>
<p>9 December 1942, ALS, from H.L. Doolittle to Wheat. </p>
<p>15 December 1942, ALS, from A.J. Cohen to Wheat. </p>
<p>16 December 1942, ALS, from Elizabeth Hawkins to Wheat; picture postcard from Hawkins to Wheat. </p>
<p>21 December 1942, TLS, from Gustavus A. Pfeiffer to Wheat. </p>
<p>30 December 1942, handwritten postcard from Grace Clifford to Grabhorn Press. </p>
<p>31 December 1942, typed postcard from Edith Wetmore to Grabhorn Press; 3 February 1943, TLS, from Wetmore to Wheat. </p></index><index audience="internal" id="aspace_c044353428991d0436d0da753a74cda6"><head>Folder 9</head><p>2 January 1943, ALS, from Agnes Pearce to Wheat. </p>
<p>3 January 1943, TLS, from Gladys Thomas to Wheat. </p>
<p>8 January 1943, TLS, from Florence Powdermaker to Grabhorn Press. </p>
<p>15 January 1943, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Mortimer Graves (Secretary, American Council of Learned Societies); 15 January 1943, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Dr. Waldo G. Leland (Director, American Council of Learned Societies); 20 January 1942, TLS, from Graves to Wheat; 23 January 1943, TLS, from Leland to Wheat. </p>
<p>16 January 1943, TLS, from Harriett Sheppard to Wheat. </p>
<p>17 January 1943, autographed card from Sergeant Phillip Sfeiling to Wheat. </p>
<p>18 January 1943, TLS, from James L. McConaughy (President, United China Relief) to Wheat. </p>
<p>18 January 1943, ALS, from Ruth Grannis (Librarian, Grolier Club) to Wheat; hand-completed acknowledgement card from Grannis to Wheat; 25 January 1943, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Grannis; 22 March 1942, TLS, from Grannis to secretary of Wheat. </p>
<p>20 January 1943, signed acknowledgement card from Keyes Metcalf (Librarian, Harvard College) to Wheat. </p>
<p>23 January 1943, ALS, from Stella M. Hinch to Wheat. </p>
<p>26 January 1943, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Ward Ritchie. </p>
<p>26 January 1943, TLS, from Elizabeth McCloy (Librarian, Occidental College) to Wheat. </p>
<p>27 January 1943, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Dr. Arthur Hummel (Chief, Division of Orientalia, Library of Congress); 1 February 1943, TLS, from Hummel to Wheat; 18 February 1943, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Hummel. </p>
<p>27 January 1943, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Dr. Edmund Day (President, Cornell University); 5 February 1943, TLS, from Day to Wheat. </p>
<p>27 January 1943, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Admiral Harry E. Yarnell; 30 January 1943, ALS, from Yarnell to Wheat. </p>
<p>27 January 1943, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Dr. Raymond Fosdick (Rockefeller Foundation); 19 February 1943, TLS, from Fosdick to Wheat. </p>
<p>27 January 1943, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Dr. David Stevens (Director, Rockefeller Foundation); 3 February 1943, ALS, to Stevens to Wheat. </p>
<p>27 January 1943, signed acknowledgement card from Franklin F. Hopps (Director, New York Public Library) to Wheat. </p>
<p>30 January 1943, ALS, from Theodore M. Lilienthal to Oscar Lewis; 19 February 1943, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to lewis. </p>
<p>1 February 1943, TLS, from Alfred Sutro to Wheat. </p>
<p>3 February 1943, TLS, from secretary of Jean Hersholt to Wheat; 1 March 1943, TLS, from Hersholt to Wheat. </p>
<p>3 February 1943, handwritten postcard from Anna Duick to Grabhorn Press. </p>
<p>3 February 1943, ALS, from Matella Arnold to Wheat; 14 February 1943, ALS, from Arnold to Wheat. </p>
<p>4 February 1943, TLS, from Agnes Meyers to Wheat. </p>
<p>8 February 1943, TLS, from Arthur B. Lisle to Wheat. </p>
<p>10 February 1943, TLS, from William Hawley Davis (Stanford University Press) to Wheat. </p>
<p>16 February 1943, TLS, from Herbert Fahey (bookbinder) to Wheat. </p>
<p>22 February 1943, signed acknowledgement card from Otto Kinkeldy (Librarian, Cornell University) to Wheat. </p>
<p>23 February 1943, TLS, from L. Carrington Goodrich (Columbia University) to Wheat. </p>
<p>24 February 1943, ALS, from Ludwig Emge to Wheat. </p>
<p>25 February 1943, signed acknowledgement card from Elizabeth Richardson (Serial Librarian, University of Colorado) to Wheat. </p>
<p>25 February 1943, TLS, from Louis V. Ledoux to Wheat. </p>
<p>26 February 1943, TLS, from Harold James Bailey to Wheat; 5 March 1943, ALS, from Bailey to Wheat. </p>
<p>26 February 1943, TLS, from Charles W. Smith (Librarian, University of Washington) to Wheat. </p>
<p>28 February 1943, ALS, from H.J. Taylor to Wheat. </p>
<p>1 March 1943, TLS, from Edward D. Lyman to Wheat. </p>
<p>6 March 1943, ALS, from Mildred Bancroft to Wheat. </p>
<p>8 March 1943, TLS, from Dr. Nancy Lee Swan (Curator, Princeton Gest Oriental Library) to Wheat; two-leaf guide to the Gest Library; 17 April 1943, TLS, from Swan to Wheat. </p>
<p>22 March 1943, TLS, from Joseph L. Andrews to Wheat; 12 April 1943, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Andrews.</p>
<p>10 May 1943, ALS, from Captain Gerald Taylor to What. </p>
<p>28 May 1943, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to Chen Shouyi (Pomona College); Chen's business card, 30 June 1943, ALS, from Chen to Wheat. With original envelope. </p>
<p>30 March 1944, TL, retained CC, from Wheat to C.M. Wang (Department of Orientalia, Library of Congress). </p></index></c02><c02 audience="internal" id="aspace_9bd368033088f578d89065c9ace52b1f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Commerical orders from bookstores and Wheat's replies</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate" datechar="creation" normal="1942-11-23/1942-12-16" type="inclusive">1942-11-23-1942-12-16</unitdate><container id="aspace_0a6c4db058a237a7fe35284965f99473" label="Mixed Materials [31924113901718]" type="box">1 </container><container id="aspace_2e2ffc404e79d84ce65a3118934c4e8e" parent="aspace_0a6c4db058a237a7fe35284965f99473" type="folder">10</container></did><index audience="internal" id="aspace_39ab59f699e16cb855c9bd14c4d5f7ad"><p>Orders and inquires from the following bookstores, often with a pro forma TL, retained CC, from Wheat in reply: </p>

<p>Concord, Chicago (23/11/1942; Charles Sessler, Philadelphia (23/11/1942)</p>
<p>Parnassus, Princeton (23/11/1942); Baker and Taylor, New York (28/11/1942)</p>
<p>Brentano's, New York (28/11/1942); Scribner, New York (3/12/1942)</p>
<p>New Dominion, Charlottesville (12/12/1942); Dutton's (12/12/1942)</p>
<p>The Fair, Fort Worth (16/12/1942)</p>
<p>Old Corner Book Store, Boston (16/12/1942)</p>
<p>Scrantom's, Rochester (16/12/1942). </p></index></c02></c01><c01 audience="internal" id="aspace_00b07d8d9eb87217aaf53faaaa692ec4" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series IV. Ephemera</unittitle></did><c02 audience="internal" id="aspace_219b7fb861864624b90f9641e90f876e" level="item"><did><unittitle>"What China Expects of America in the Present Crisis"</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate" datechar="creation" normal="1937-10-01/1937-10-01">1937-10-01</unitdate><container id="aspace_d9aaeeda45b5bb410028ab670b70411a" label="Mixed Materials [31924113901718]" type="box">1 </container><container id="aspace_a12215bd59f1a667250d9ef757b5ca22" parent="aspace_d9aaeeda45b5bb410028ab670b70411a" type="folder">11</container></did><scopecontent audience="internal" id="aspace_1eefda6f8e1a102f9041f1ec0ff328a5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Dittoed transcript of a radio address given by Hu Shih.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 audience="internal" id="aspace_c8ee6435d3710e8b1b62cfacdd47cd97" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Peace Has to Be Enforced"</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate" datechar="creation" normal="1942-05/1942-05">1942-05</unitdate><container id="aspace_383f90c229affa77be44668dce736f95" label="Mixed Materials [31924113901718]" type="box">1 </container><container id="aspace_ee331f014853ed1185e88b214f639179" parent="aspace_383f90c229affa77be44668dce736f95" type="folder">11</container></did><scopecontent audience="internal" id="aspace_c8ea5a67b98a2cce2cc879d6f6882216"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Hu Shih pamphlet reprinted from Asia magazine.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 audience="internal" id="aspace_a34194d659d5f7137c5169c26e226d0f" level="item"><did><unittitle>"The Struggle for Intellectual Freedom in Historic China"</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate" datechar="creation" normal="1942-09/1942-09">1942-09</unitdate><container id="aspace_4ccbb6e238df77e3d2a2da5811d27092" label="Mixed Materials [31924113901718]" type="box">1 </container><container id="aspace_0303746fb603d3403c5ae02d3ee24ec8" parent="aspace_4ccbb6e238df77e3d2a2da5811d27092" type="folder">11</container></did><scopecontent audience="internal" id="aspace_c87ee9c5be7475f70ba89161e9f85ccb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Hu Shih pamphlet reprinted from World Affairs.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 audience="internal" id="aspace_5163cf603ac272195f922f5ec77bb494" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Chinese Thought"</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate" datechar="creation" normal="1942-10/1942-10">1942-10</unitdate><container id="aspace_506b631cf4914c76c7f260cd6e239851" label="Mixed Materials [31924113901718]" type="box">1 </container><container id="aspace_2e849f28ecd28e65960dfdbf9a8003de" parent="aspace_506b631cf4914c76c7f260cd6e239851" type="folder">11</container></did><scopecontent audience="internal" id="aspace_ab1192108c57db5d33f6386feced058b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Hu Shih pamphlet reprinted from Asia magazine.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 audience="internal" id="aspace_babe2c30f7aaa7fa62bc9ea88729c3b6" level="item"><did><unittitle>Life magazine profile of Hu</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate" datechar="creation" normal="1941-12/1941-12">1941-12</unitdate><container id="aspace_1ecffaf1f8563b52d472407097dca7fc" label="Mixed Materials [31924113901718]" type="box">1 </container><container id="aspace_1d11f0f18e697b76beaa852dd75ae19b" parent="aspace_1ecffaf1f8563b52d472407097dca7fc" type="folder">11</container></did><scopecontent audience="internal" id="aspace_eaf344ca795a1e96dc20666ad3b1bacb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Profile of Hu from Life magazine written by Ernest O. Hauser.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 audience="internal" id="aspace_85b9bb1e2f0db518d9cc98b944349678" level="item"><did><unittitle>Sun Yat-Sen 5-cent stamp article</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate" datechar="creation" normal="1942-07-20/1942-07-20">1942-07-20</unitdate><container id="aspace_d925352d3a73cb4239684c2e5a09a6bc" label="Mixed Materials [31924113901718]" type="box">1 </container><container id="aspace_ee0c64cad63308b1943b0f417105c94f" parent="aspace_d925352d3a73cb4239684c2e5a09a6bc" type="folder">11</container></did><scopecontent audience="internal" id="aspace_43b0734b6e3fa6c7f53134e4830ecb67"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Article on the Sun Yat-Sen U.S. 5-cent postal stamp from a July 1942 issue of Lincoln Lore. Includes an example of the stamp.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 audience="internal" id="aspace_3f4a10cf35706b951fadd903f165617c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Edward Larocque Tinker's review</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate" datechar="creation" normal="1942-11-01/1942-11-01">1942-11-01</unitdate><container id="aspace_6bb2c1f7bf6fa86cd67207b6015ab748" label="Mixed Materials [31924113901718]" type="box">1 </container><container id="aspace_bba7d82a00fb4b68e2c05c7648936e9f" parent="aspace_6bb2c1f7bf6fa86cd67207b6015ab748" type="folder">11</container></did><scopecontent audience="internal" id="aspace_bf52c3a4d8c639c52a0b4a251fb044da"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Multiple clipped copies of Edward Larocque Tinker's review of the publication in the New York Times Book Review.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 audience="internal" id="aspace_c396265dc615c8f97e150fef4113cc67" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hoy Magazine review</unittitle><unitdate certainty="approximate" datechar="creation" normal="1943-02/1943-03-20" type="inclusive">1943-02-1943-03-20</unitdate><container id="aspace_d0c1f13c0f82acb69469f7e9d0e7f8f6" label="Mixed Materials [31924113901718]" type="box">1 </container><container id="aspace_c45b62e4a0afb2f6be6495d3976e611c" parent="aspace_d0c1f13c0f82acb69469f7e9d0e7f8f6" type="folder">11</container></did><scopecontent audience="internal" id="aspace_fadf1aab76d4e72ab0b830269bf99c17"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Spanish-language review of the publication, extracted from the February 1943 issue of the Mexican magazine Hoy and sent to Wheat by Edward Larocque Tinker. Includes correspondence from Wheat to Tinker.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 audience="internal" id="aspace_3c047507ba09cb27fa1f9f6b809ad409" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hu and Wheat</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" certainty="approximate" datechar="creation" era="ce">Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_150516a2b4e2f99959f5bffacab68420" label="Mixed Materials [31924113901718]" type="box">1 </container><container id="aspace_2a2c0eac7496ea281b9aaac4f953ebc8" parent="aspace_150516a2b4e2f99959f5bffacab68420" type="folder">11</container></did><scopecontent audience="internal" id="aspace_c15eaaa03342292aafed6f306695a4c4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Includes 2 matchbook covers printed with Hu's personal seal, a slip from a fortune cookie, and manuscript notes in Wheat's handwriting on the letterhead of Hu's private residence, stamped with Hu's personal seals.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 audience="internal" id="aspace_e0cef7ed58344d6c133c10a04c61925e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Original folders</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" certainty="approximate" datechar="creation" era="ce">Undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_69b37b00a3c19867bda713a3da39940f" label="Mixed Materials [31924113901718]" type="box">1 </container><container id="aspace_ef8138e91d82f881481c40a3e2e89b50" parent="aspace_69b37b00a3c19867bda713a3da39940f" type="folder">12</container></did></c02></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
