<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US">RMM06020</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>First United Methodist Church of Geneva records<num>6020</num></titleproper><author>Compiled by B.D.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections</publisher><p><date>June 2004</date></p><address><addressline>2B Carl A. Kroch Library</addressline><addressline>Cornell University</addressline><addressline>Ithaca, NY 14853</addressline><addressline>rareref@cornell.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://rare.library.cornell.edu/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://rare.library.cornell.edu/" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p><subject>relig</subject> <subject>rghis</subject> <subject>church</subject></p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-11-05 23:21:15 UTC</date>.</creation></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>12/07/2018</date><item>This resource was modified by the ArchivesSpace Preprocessor developed by the Harvard Library (https://github.com/harvard-library/archivesspace-preprocessor)</item></change><change><date>2007-05-29</date><item>converted from EAD 1.0 to EAD 2002</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>First United Methodist Church of Geneva records</unittitle>
    <origination audience="internal" label="creator">
      <corpname source="ingest">First United Methodist Church of Geneva (Geneva, N.Y.)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>6020</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 microfilm reels.</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">1 microfilm reels.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1835/1899" type="inclusive">1835-1899.</unitdate>
    <physdesc id="aspace_6df52dc1d491ede15e82ae3598419477">Microfilm</physdesc>
    <abstract id="aspace_06483f0a1984ccf7f7866dc566895b89">Mainly class leader records (1835-1869) including a decisions on when to hold a Love Feast and a discussion about an anti-slavery convention to be held in Rochester. Also records of the Quarterly Conference Meetings (April 1837-October 1899). Also included is a membership register (1836-1854).</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_13fc8ae6c347c120b22a785fe8110be7">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="041" langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial>
    <container id="aspace_ecb86d2ebef569fc23c3c5aaad78cbb8" label="Mixed Materials" type="microfilm reel">1</container>
    <unitid type="bibid">2098348</unitid>
  </did>
  <odd id="aspace_cb00a92e4d02637727b09dd88d435312">
    <head>General</head>
    <list type="deflist">
      <defitem>
        <label>Contact Information:</label>
        <item>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections 2B Carl A. Kroch Library Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3530 Fax: (607) 255-9524 <extref href="mailto:rareref@cornell.edu">rareref@cornell.edu</extref> <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu">http://rmc.library.cornell.edu</extref></item>
      </defitem>
      <defitem>
        <label>Compiled by:</label>
        <item>B.D.</item>
      </defitem>
      <defitem>
        <label>Date completed:</label>
        <item>Nov. 1978</item>
      </defitem>
      <defitem>
        <label>EAD encoding:</label>
        <item>Andrea Hektor, June 2004</item>
      </defitem>
      <defitem>
        <label>Date modified:</label>
        <item>Marcie Farwell, February 2015</item>
      </defitem>
    </list>
  </odd>
  <bioghist id="aspace_8a92cdac1bf30d4ee20c9ade1cb2133a">
    <head>ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY</head>
<p>The church was established in 1811 by the Reverend George Harrison. The church building was erected in 1821. After the church was erected, the society had its own minister. A second church was built in 1839.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_78ef83b144d67a61697e8a730300ffcc">
    <head>COLLECTION DESCRIPTION</head>
<p>Records mainly contain class leader records (Items 1, 2, 3) (1835-1869). The other large group of records are those of the Quarterly Conference Meetings (April 1837-October 1899). Also included is a membership register (1836-1854).</p><p>  The class leader records include: records of class money received, names of church members who were licensed to preach, reports on class and Sabbath school attendance, accounts of collections received for the poor fund and names of persons who received money from that fund, and rules of order to be observed at official meetings as veil as rules for conducting meetings.</p><p>  Quarterly Conference Records include: records of subscription payments, names of leaders and numbers of students attending classes, reports of the estimating committee, and financial reports.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <prefercite id="aspace_343423eb594f99d8344312c9125a01fa">
    <head>Cite As:</head>
<p>First United Methodist Church of Geneva records, #6020. Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library.</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="aat">Minutes.</genreform>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Ontario County (N.Y.) -- Religious life and customs.</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Geneva (N.Y.) -- Religious life and customs.</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Methodist Episcopal Church -- New York (State) -- Geneva.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Antislavery movements.</subject>
    <persname source="lcsh">Harrison, George, Rev.</persname>
    <corpname source="lcsh">Methodist Episcopal Church. Quarterly Conference</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <unitid type="bibid">2098348</unitid>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_65061b270be567d4208fc6e4d7bb28d6" level="item"><did><unittitle>Leaders Meeting Records, May 18, 1835 - April 11, 1842 , Chronological, not paginated</unittitle><unitid>Item #1</unitid><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1835-05-18/1842-04-11" type="inclusive">May 18, 1835 - April 11, 1842</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e9b68d54546e15ef1ff56f3fad8df516"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Meeting records contain: names of members present, records of class money received; names of persons on probation from class, examples of how this session acted as a court, records of persons whose names were removed from church records, names of persons recommended to the Quarterly Meeting Conferences to be licensed as preachers, de cisions regarding when and where prayer meetings were to be held, decisions regarding who guest speakers would be and who would take collections afterwards, decisions regarding the Pastor's salary, names of church members licensed to preach, reports on Sabbath School attendance, records of stewards appointed, and decisions on when to hold Love Feasts.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_8a7fee13e5e1fe898fb9e516fbc735b7" level="item"><did><unittitle>Leaders Meeting Records, September 3, 1849 - June 11, 1855 , Chronological, not paginated</unittitle><unitid>Item #2</unitid><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1849-09-03/1855-06-11" type="inclusive">September 3, 1849 - June 11, 1855</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3c8f98e6ca568aa81b66a5e4e8872d32"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Goodwin. Also contains rules of order to be observed at official meetings Meeting records contain: records of money paid to stewards, names of persons present; reports on class attendance, records of money paid the society by the congregation, records of rent payments for the pastor's house, class account records, records of salary payments to the Reverends Dennis, Gulick, Haines and of order to be observed at official meetings and rules for conducting meetings.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_f6015ca4e57344cce6d48b5256f50db1" level="item"><did><unittitle>Steward Meeting Records, September 1855 - September 1869 , Chronological, not paginated</unittitle><unitid>Item #3</unitid><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1855-09/1869-09" type="inclusive">September 1855 - September 1869</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1798bbfaf53afcfd9595d83475487139"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Minutes contain: names of persons present, reports on class attendance, names of persons put on and taken off probation, records of money paid by class members to class leaders, decisions on times to hold prayer meetings, names of persons made full members of church, decisions on when to hold Love Feasts, discussion about an anti-slavery convention to be held in Rochester, names of persons recommended to the church, selection of delegates to attend laymen's Convention in Rochester, records of money sent to the American Bible Society, suggestions in reference to a district campmeeting, list of class leaders, accounts of payments to pastor. Also records of pews rented, records of collection money for the poor, money paid out of that collection, and names of persons given money from that fund.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_a321622a61ffd2d1ea1e0891d9d28e86" level="item"><did><unittitle>Membership Register, 1836-1854 , Chronological, not paginated</unittitle><unitid>Item #4</unitid><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1836/1854" type="inclusive">1836-1854</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9414ad6bb0f7c48db11c75c6ab31aa4b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains: list of members, how they were received (by letter or admission), how they left the church (death, dismissal, expulsion), list of persons on class probation, their leaders' names, and how they were removed from the probation list.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_acae3c9e44de75c23ee8778fc4d25e83" level="item"><did><unittitle>Quarterly Conference Meeting Records, April 1837 - October 1899 , Chronological, not paginated</unittitle><unitid>Item #5</unitid><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1837-04/1899-10" type="inclusive">April 1837 - October 1899</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_50cb63aae8300d75a712e62cd8b5976e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Contains : unarranged list of leaders and stewards in the front of the book and minutes of Quarterly Meeting Conference which contain: names of persons present, names of persons elected stewards, Centneary of Methodism (October 21, 1839), record of subscription payments, names of persons wishing to be licensed to preach by the Conference, records of complaints and appeals, numbers of teachers (male and female), numbers of students (male and female), number of volumes in the library, reports of the estimating committee, financial reports, pastors' reports on the state of the church, names of persons elected district stewards, names of persons on various committees, accounts of funds raised for benevolent purposes, letter to General Conference of Methodist Episcopal Church (May 1, 1884), reports from Missionary Committee, reports from Temperance Committee, class leaders' reports.</p><p>  Rear of volume contains a listing of classes, leaders and students.</p></scopecontent></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
