<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US">RMM08737</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Columbia University Atlantic Philanthropies oral history project<num>8737</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections</publisher><address><addressline>2B Carl A. Kroch Library</addressline><addressline>Cornell University</addressline><addressline>Ithaca, NY 14853</addressline><addressline>rareref@cornell.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://rare.library.cornell.edu/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://rare.library.cornell.edu/" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-01-28 18:40:07 UTC</date>.</creation><langusage>English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
    </langmaterial>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Columbia University Atlantic Philanthropies oral history project</unittitle>
    <origination label="source">
      <corpname source="ingest">Columbia University. Oral History Research Office</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>8737</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">557.46 gigabytes.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="2005/2017" type="inclusive">2005-2017</unitdate>
    <unitid type="bibid">11064304</unitid>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_349c2056b148d4b63c01a7d632a56088">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>The Oral History Research Office at Columbia University began work on  Phase I of the Atlantic Philanthropies Oral History Project in 2005. Interviewees include Atlantic Philanthropies executives, business associates of Chuck Feeney, institutional partners, and grantees. Chuck Feeney himself was interviewed during this phase. Interviews were focused on documenting Feeney's life, with particular focus on the creation of Duty Free Shoppers, the establishment of Atlantic Philanthropies, and Feeney's philosophy of "Giving While Living". Upon its completion in 2008, the first phase contained over 560 hours of testimony given by 138 different narrators. </p><p>In 2014, the Columbia Center for Oral History Research at INCITE (formerly OHRO) received a grant from Atlantic Philanthropies to conduct a second set of interviews. Interviews for Phase II were taken between 2014 and 2016, with the focus on documenting the last years of Atlantic's existence, particularly the changes in its grantmaking, as well as the challenges inherent in becoming a spend-down foundation. Phase II contains 142 oral history sessions with 84 narrators totaling 220 recorded hours.  </p><p>In 2018, Columbia sent digital copies of the recordings and their transcripts to Cornell University's Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections. </p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_1e1194d01779f7a9dadd166ba8e3b76d">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>Phase I interviews: Gerry Adams, Harold Adler, Suzanne Aisenberg, Le Vu Anh, David Beanland, Bob Beck, Adrian Bellamy, Padraig Berry, Gail Bianchi, Alec Broers, Michael H. Brown, Robert J. Bruso, Geoff Budlender, Bob Butler, Jean-Paul Camus, Michael J.R. Carlton, Gerhard Casper, Jack Clark, Ron Clarke, Edwin Cohen, Mark Conroy, Suzanne Cory, Angela Covert, Ara Daglian, Harvey Dale, Steven Denning, Bill Dietel, David Dittman, Roger Downer, James Downey, Christine Downton, Daniel Doyle, Robert Edmonds, Sara Engelhardt, David Erskine, Fred Eydt, Charles Feeney, Peter Fithian, Arlene Fitzpatrick, Joel L. Fleishman, William Flynn, Robert J. Futoran, John Gentzbourger, Dennis Gibson, Pierre Godé, Robert Goldman, Michael Gwinnell, Raymond Handlan, Paul Hannon, John Hay, John A. Healy, John R. Healy, Ursula Healy, David C. Hodgson, Ted Howell, Joseph J. Jamison, Jean Karoubi, Keith Kennedy, Gerald Kraak, Theodore Kresge, Gara LaMarche, Edward Lansdale, Kenneth J. Logue, Hugh D. Lunn, Joseph P. Lyons, Roy J. Magee, Jeffrey Mahlstedt, Michael Mann, Martin Mansergh, Robert Matousek, Craig Mayor, Aine McCarthy, Elizabeth McCormack, Grainne McCoy, Colin McCrea, Peter McCue, Martin McGuinness, Bob Miller, Truong Tan Minh, George J. Mitchell, Thomas Mitchell, Fabian Monds, John Monteiro, Jack Moore, Bruce A. Morrison, Michael P. Mortell, Frank Mutch, Jacques Nordeman, Connor O'Clery, Brian O'Connell, Jill O'Donnell Tormey, Niall O'Dowd, Danny O'Hare, Rita O'Hare, Sean O'Huiginn, Christopher Oechsli, Lloyd J. Old, Alan M. Parker, Robert Payton, Christine B. Pendry, Le Nahn Phuong, Tony Pilaro, Lawrie W. Powell, Mamphela Ramphele, Hunter Rawlings, Albert Reynolds, Stephen Reynolds, Frank H. T. Rhodes, Cynthia R. Richards, Charles G. Rolles, Alan Ruby, James Scannell, Frederick A. O. "Fritz" Schwarz, Jr., Ted R. Sizer, David Smith, Peter Smitham, Michael Sovern, James Spencer, Ciaran Staunton, Leon Sterling, Ernie Stern, David Sternlieb, Bonnie Suchet, Eugene Tempel, John Terzano, Dr. Donald Thornhill, Huynh Thi Trang, Myron Ullman, Laurence Vogel, Luigi Votano, Edward Walsh, Sue Wesselkamper, Michael Windsor, Gerold Wunderlich, Phan Quang Xung (with translator Ha Le Hung), and Cummings Zuill.</p><p>Phase II: Annmarie Benedict, Deepak Bhargava, Kenneth Bowman, Gail Birkbeck, Brad Brockman, Julie Brown, Phil Buchanan, Duc Phu Bui, Amit Chandra, Madeleine Clarke, Peter Coaldrake, Philip Coates, Eoin Collins, Paul Connolly, Sarah Cooke, Tom Costello, Steve Denning, Christine Downton, Frances Fitzgerald, Siobhan Fitzpatrick, Joel Fleishman, Joanne Florino, Ian Frazer, Marc Freedman, Tony Gallagher, Robert Greenstein, Billy Hall, Nguyen Trong Hau, John R. Healy, John A. Healy, Dmitri Holtzman, Joanne Hughes, Doron Isaacs, Patrick Johnston, Stanley Katz, Brian Kearney-Grieve, Regis Kelly, David Kennedy, Rose Anne Kenny, Ben Kerman, Gara LaMarche, Sara Lawrence-Lightfoot, Janet Love, Zola Madikizela, Robert "Bob" Matousek, Steve McConnell, Elizabeth McCormack, Bruce Miller, Tom Mitchell, Mario Morino, David Morse, Cecilia Munoz, Paul Murray, Martin O'Brien, Brian O'Connell, Niall O'Dowd, Chris Oechsli, Alan Parker, Christine Pendry, Le Nhan Phuong, Tony Proscio, Marian Quinn, Padriac Quirk, Duong Hoang Quyen, Cynthia Richards, Ian Robertson, Anthony Romero, Kieran Rose, Jack Rosenthal, Albie Sachs, Fritz Schwarz, Pharie Sefali, Frank Sharry, Brian Sheehan, Norma Sinte, David Skorton, Brad Smith, Dave Smith, Peter Smitham, Michael Sovern, David Sternlieb, Chris Stone, Mary Sutton, David Walsh, and Ian Young.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_978b9bbc8616b66be9d33a8e2d60a208">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Phase I transcripts are restricted until December 2021. Phase II: 2025. (Exceptions in Phase I: Broers, Alec (restricted until death or 1/1/2040); Carlton, Michael (pages 115-125 restricted until 2025); Casper, Gerhard (restricted until death); Dietel, William (restricted until death); Goldman, Robert (restricted until death); Lund, Hugh (restricted until death or 1/1/2028); Gwinnell, Michael: (restricted until death or 2038: pages 126-182, 137-53, 212-13, 262-263, 266-69, 275-79, 281-85, 287-89, 303-13, 319-325)). Transcripts for Chris Oechsli are restricted until 2030.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_a1a61c6519b4aed2bef44b00fc70a109">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Researchers can access only transcripts.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_68f64a51f03f32872f22995bcbb7b2a7">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>The Atlantic Philanthropies Archives, #8540</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <originalsloc id="aspace_b1e2a75d7be1e8be27af665779e686c5">
    <head>Existence and Location of Originals</head>
<p>Columbia Center for Oral History Archives at the Rare Book and Manuscript Library</p>  </originalsloc>
  <custodhist id="aspace_37bd87487eba4b1f91872361ab542d21">
    <head>Custodial History</head>
<p>The oral history recordings and transcripts that compose this collection are digital copies given to RMC by Columbia in 2018 via an external  hard-drive. Originals are housed at the Columbia Center for Oral History Archives at the Rare Book and Manuscript Library.</p>  </custodhist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_55224a31c8d4cc3dd46cfd0c8fcbf53f">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Columbia University Atlantic Philanthropies oral history project, #8737. Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library.</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">Charities -- United States.</subject>
    <subject source="ingest">Endowments</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Peace movements -- Northern Ireland -- History -- 20th century </subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Public health -- Vietnam </geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher -- Vietnam</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher -- United States -- Finance </subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher -- Australia -- Finance </subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher -- Ireland</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Medicine -- Research -- Australia</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Duty-free importation </subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Northern Ireland -- History</geogname>
    <corpname role="fmo" source="ingest">Columbia University. Oral History Research Office</corpname>
    <persname source="ingest">Feeney, Chuck, 1931-</persname>
    <corpname source="ingest">Atlantic Philanthropies (Organization)</corpname>
    <corpname source="ingest">DFS Galleria (Firm)</corpname>
    <corpname source="lcsh">Cornell University</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <unitid type="bibid">11064304</unitid>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_92edb6397f6cd97bee73e92ffd5f62cb" level="series"><did><unittitle>Phase I</unittitle></did><accessrestrict id="aspace_a3546dce97ae2703aeb9ca92f236db52"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Phase I transcripts are restricted until December 2021.</p></accessrestrict><c02 id="aspace_acfa3a56074310101bec9c1ba001ee90" level="file"><did><unittitle>Adams, Gerry</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-01-23/2007-01-23">2007-01-23</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_df5c5a6ec1ab53c94f8ca873831a681a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Personal background: childhood, American popular culture; Ireland: 20th century socio-politics, Northern Ireland, peace process, U.S. visa issue; Sinn Féin: Washington office, public relations, Irish Republican Army, relationship with Irish America, fundraising; Interactions: Charles F. Feeney, Niall O'Dowd, J. Martin McGuinness, William J. Clinton.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_0919215a791819979a4f077fc08dca02" level="file"><did><unittitle>Adler, Harold</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Farber, Myron A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-07-11/2007-07-11">2007-07-11</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6b26de3ebe6fd99967582534e460b9b0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Personal background: childhood in Berlin, family history, Jewish life under Nazis, family migration to Paris in 1930s, anti-Semitism in Europe 20s-30s, migration to the United States, WWII military service: D-Day, French Resistance, liberation of Paris; career: incentive industry, duty free catalogue shopping, product line, Transocean Trading Company, business problems; Duty Free Shoppers: early history, Tourists International, buy-out of Transocean Trading Company and Harold Adler/Stewart Damon-owned Duty Free Shoppers, duty free shop in Mexico City; Interactions: Charles F. Feeney, Jeffrey Mahlstedt, Danielle J. Feeney.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_4f81d464c11baae9f918e566f39e1a23" level="file"><did><unittitle>Aisenberg, Suzanne</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-09-19/2006-09-19">2006-09-19</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_eb4f8760f06db435cb8d397666f57e0e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Personal background: New York childhood, family history, 1960s-70s U.S. politics; Atlantic Philanthropies: anonymity, grant-making decisions, higher education, disadvantaged youth, personnel, board members; Interactions: Charles F. Feeney, Raymond L. Handlan, Angela M. Covert, James W. Spencer, W. Keith Kennedy, Joel L. Fleishman, Harvey P. Dale.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_665acd61522e32355d4a721ae384552f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Anh, Le Vu</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-10-08/2007-10-08">2007-10-08</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1be3923b3e917a6230461738bfb461f6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Family background; education; career: general medicine, epidemiology, public health; Vietnamese public health: issues, awareness, development; Hanoi School of Public Health: early history, government involvement, funding, programs, development, current problems; Atlantic Philanthropies: public health, personnel, interaction with grantees, mission, spend-down; interactions: Charles F. Feeney.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_5f308edd34df382788079964e972fe46" level="file"><did><unittitle>Beanland, David</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-06-28/2006-06-28">2006-06-28</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c7653f2581ab7ba228fce499a377cdd6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Early life in Yallourn and Box Hill, Australia; education as an electrical engineer; teaching and becoming head of department at Caulfield Technical College and Royal Melbourne Institute of Technology [RMIT]; development of Australian higher education system; Charles F. Feeney's funding for RMIT in Australia and Vietnam; development and challenges of RMIT in Vietnam; experimental teaching methods in Vietnam; Learning Resource Centers in Vietnam; Atlantic Philanthropies' [AP] changing priorities with regards to higher education; interactions with AP Board of Directors at 2001 meeting in Vietnam.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_6e1af68b22505a7e3490e1721f84a36e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Beck, Bob</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Rowland, Steven S.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2005-10-17/2005-10-18" type="inclusive">2005-10-17-2005-10-18</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8c0d72db2e50995736fcf61692c1ba14"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Childhood in Boston, MA; education: Cornell University School of Hotel Administration [Hotel School], 1942; relationship between Cornell Hotel School and Cornell University [CU]; World War II and army experiences at Normandy on D-Day; career: professor and dean at the Hotel School;  fraternity culture and segregation at CU in 1950s; reminiscence of Charles F. Feeney [CFF]: relationship as CFF' college advisor; CFF's duty free ventures including early years in Europe, development of Duty Free Shoppers [DFS], and interest in China's tourism industry; the Atlantic Philanthropies [AP] gifts to CU; dynamics of higher education funding and AP's withdrawal from education; participation in Advisory Board for AP; impressions of CFF.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_364e70b2253c4aec9d78c3726fad2b21" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bellamy, Adrian</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Farber, Myron A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-12-27/2006-12-28" type="inclusive">2006-12-27-2006-12-28</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9e8590cc183b9d56227c83964db9248e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Born United Kingdom; reminiscences of Rhodesia, apartheid in South Africa; education: Bachelor of Commerce; career: CEO, Edgars Stores Limited, 1976-1983; CEO, Duty Free Shoppers [DFS], 1983-1994; DFS: hiring process, changes due to new leadership, principles of duty-free retail operations, luxury brands, company expansion, airport concession bids, efforts to centralize operations, revenue growth and positive impact of Japanese tourism, economic downturn due to negative impact of Persian Gulf War on tourism; interactions with Charles F. Feeney, Alan M. Parker, Robert W. Miller, Anthony M. Pilaro.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_0630193e87e7a9a4057428cdc7a9f798" level="file"><did><unittitle>Berry, Padraig</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Grele, Ronald J.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-02-05/2007-02-05">2007-02-05</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ba37e0129ae26fd99b816358b8d4e7c6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Born Ireland; education: B.A. Hotel Management, Galway-Mayo Institute of Technology, M.B.A. International Hospitality Management, Cornell University in Paris; career: analyst for Hilton International in Africa, consultant for Laventhol &amp; Havarth Stoy Hayward, management consultant for Strategy Coaching Unlimited; principles behind Ireland's economic growth; Charles F. Feeney: meeting and initial impressions, personality traits; work for Erin Go Braugh in Ireland: investments, philosophy behind operations, use of Irish cultural symbols for marketing, focus on developing language skills, Ireland as economic model for former Soviet republics.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_06b504671d20c4b0dfc5e2f6f35b1164" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bianchi, Gail</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Rowland, Steven S.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-05-30/2006-05-30">2006-05-30</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4807abed670215f86e75b27d8cafa1a6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Administrative manager at InterPacific Group; family background; employment history; InterPacific Group: organization, holdings and investments: Western Athletic clubs; Atlantic Philanthropies: higher education in Vietnam, Australia, and California; interactions with David Smith, Gerold Wunderlich, Charles F. Feeney.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_3fd00e10d377d6bc9131ee2c3f2474a6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Broers, Alec</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-04-16/2007-04-16">2007-04-16</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c146916de4abdf5e3d120f51ab7768c5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Family background; childhood and early life; education; career: engineering, nanotechnology, academia, higher education administration; higher education in the U. K.: government influence, structure, funding sources, admissions process; Atlantic Philanthropies: higher education grantees, higher education in U. K., personnel, anonymity, funding sources; Interactions: Charles F. Feeney, Michael Gwinnell, Frank H. T. Rhodes.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict id="aspace_edc18ee541a13f390f496fd25ba8433b"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Interview restricted until death or 1/1/2040.</p></accessrestrict></c02><c02 id="aspace_35886f84bc477ec27cc277b4c468394c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Brown, Michael</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-08-16/2007-08-17" type="inclusive">2007-08-16-2007-08-17</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_90c62d8f546e37bb8ebe65453ebd6172"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Childhood and family life in Boston, MA; education: B.A., Harvard University, Social Studies, 1984; J.D., Harvard Law School, 1988; career: co-founder and CEO, City Year, 1988-present; experience working on Capitol Hill, efforts in legislatively galvanizing a national service campaign; City Year: its inception, fundraising efforts, funding support from General Atlantic Partners/Echoing Green and the Atlantic Philanthropies [AP], federal support and impact in formation of new national policy, nationalization of City Year program; AP's anonymity policy and transition into a public foundation; City Year's role in creation of AmeriCorps and work with William J. Clinton administration; remembrances: Alan A. A. Khazei, Edwin C. Cohen.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_3385b32553875b5fd3f4c2f7a052543a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bruso, Robert</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Farber, Myron A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-09-12/2007-09-13" type="inclusive">2007-09-12-2007-09-13</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5a8419d1edddce46fd494e066f6f07df"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Childhood and family life in Whitinsville, MA; education: B.S. in Forestry, University of Massachusetts, 1956; naval training and career, 1956-1961; career: salesperson, Guam and Saipan concession manager, mid-Pacific division president, Duty Free Shoppers, 1961-1989; Duty Free Shoppers: early years with Cars International, creation of Classic Jewelers Ltd., Guam and Saipan duty-free concessions, business strategies and development, impact of Japanese tourism, corporate environment; reminiscences of Charles F. Feeney, Robert W. Miller, Anthony M. Pilaro, Alan M. Parker.</p></scopecontent><processinfo id="aspace_7154f8c7650553b52ddef9dd0df0c6af"><head>Processing Information</head><p>Archivist redacted transcript: pages 143, 144 (removed), 145 (removed).</p></processinfo></c02><c02 id="aspace_bc03f634a68e56fa4622da0aaeee03f3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Budlender, Geoff</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-01-23/2007-01-23">2007-01-23</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8d18cea8fb0222ad19b8d7d8c543d33b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Personal background: grew up in Port Elizabeth, South Africa; English-speaking; Jewish, middle-class, highly segregated community; moderately liberal family; involved in studies and sports in school; period of national service; student days at University of Cape Town; personal political development; involvement with NUSAS and SASO; law career; beginning and funding of LRC; contact with American legal system; relationship with AP: impressions of John R. Healy and Harvey Dale, candidate attorneys program; professionalizing LRC fundraising operations; successful vs. unsuccessful grants; years working in government; reflections on 1994 and the end of apartheid; on not being appointed as a judge; involvement with TAC; childhood, American popular culture; Ireland: 20th century socio-politics, Northern Ireland, peace process, U.S. visa issue; Sinn Fein: Washington office, public relations, Irish Republican Army, relationship with Irish America, fund-raising; Interactions: Charles F. Feeney, Niall O'Dowd, J. Martin McGuinness, William J. Clinton.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_95d7e15367c2e1d750be45c38eb508bb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Butler, Bob</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-04-10/2006-04-12" type="inclusive">2006-04-10-2006-04-12</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_72aab5654f2f5e490321168fafff75fe"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: B.A., Columbia University, 1949; M.D., Columbia University, 1953; motivation for studying issues of aging; creation of the International Longevity Center [ILC] in New York and Japan and Atlantic Philanthropies' [AP] contribution/support; reflection on AP's change of direction, spend down policy, and its interaction with grantees, and grant administration; impressions of the AP staff, board members and advisors; efforts and struggles to raise awareness about aging/longevity, including securing adequate resources, problems of ageism, quality of care, etc.; relationship with Charles F. Feeney and Raymond L. Handlan</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_4bda31eb849d31f9c51813edde97cf9b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Camus, Jean-Paul</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Farber, Myron A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-08-22/2006-08-23" type="inclusive">2006-08-22-2006-08-23</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_04ef89bf7e4ab8c4c7d2524ed9b0770c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Background: family history, World War II in France, education; cognac: history, distillation process, marketing; Camus Overseas Limited: history, corporate structure, development, products, business strategies, relationship with DFS, competitors; Duty-Free Shoppers: history, business strategies, sale of DFS; interactions with Charles F. Feeney, Robert W. Miller, Alan M. Parker, Anthony M. Pilaro, Jean Gentzbourger, Norberto F. Herrero, Robert J. Futoran, Adrian Bellamy</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_2896306761764bc40012a357d7f6437c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Carlton, Michael</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Farber, Myron A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-03-10/2006-03-11" type="inclusive">2006-03-10-2006-03-11</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7ad18c072171d5fcff7bdc6053c0c7ce"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Born in United Kingdom; early career in investment banking in South Africa 1966-1979; investment work for General Atlantic 1980-1993; structure of and positions at General Atlantic [GA]; interactions with George M. Parker; beginnings of GA investment office in London; GA and issues around anonymity; subsidiaries of GA; dispersal of GA funds for philanthropic activities; management of and investments in Duty Free Shoppers [DFS]; Charles F. Feeney [CFF] and Danielle J. Feeney divorce and effect on DFS and Atlantic Foundation; interactions with CFF.</p></scopecontent><processinfo id="aspace_52d3f4f06690e77e7b58d6fd070dceea"><head>Processing Information</head><p>Archivist redacted transcript: pages 115, 125; 116-124 removed.</p></processinfo><accessrestrict id="aspace_25d8c749cf000fb1acec54ddaa00a664"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Transcript pages 115-125 restricted until 2025.</p></accessrestrict></c02><c02 id="aspace_42689f4b2b530bc21cd908026ea4246d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Casper, Gerhard</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-08-23/2006-08-24" type="inclusive">2006-08-23-2006-08-24</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_04a4ca3cfcec913f67173d6236100e65"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Born December 25, 1937 in Hamburg, Germany; early life and education in Germany; memories of World War II; participation in New York Herald Tribune Youth Forum; attendance at Yale Law School; twenty-six years at University of Chicago as professor and then dean of  the law school; interactions with Harvey P. Dale; interactions with Charles F. Feeney [CFF]; CFF and anonymous giving; Atlantic Philanthropies [AP] funding for construction of: Center for Clinical Sciences Research, cancer research, BioX lab complex, and specialty treatment buildings at Stanford University; AP gift of President's Discretionary fund.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict audience="internal" id="aspace_f89dee0f11f88e6a157ef68875a311a1"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Restricted until death.</p></accessrestrict></c02><c02 id="aspace_3b9164e617ca58df0351d18806edbe36" level="file"><did><unittitle>Clark, Jack</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-03-07/2006-04-04" type="inclusive">2006-03-07-2006-04-04</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dc31eb064482f407ddbc7cdd75ea5102"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Dean Emeritus of Cornell University's School of Hotel Management; background: family history, working-class childhood, educational history; career at Cornell University: student/faculty interactions, administration, advancement; Cornell University: Hotel Ezra Cornell, fund-raising, endowments, DFS scholarships, Marriott Corporation grants, Atlantic Philanthropies involvement; interactions with Robert A. Beck, Charles F. Feeney, Raymond Handlan, Jacques Nordeman, Fred Eydt, Charles Rolles, Harvey Dale, Frank Rhodes.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_6043b4db0fe9581328547055246642a8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Clarke, Ron</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-07-11/2006-07-15" type="inclusive">2006-07-11-2006-07-15</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_363ce453ba9e04e7dfe21fc86f9b49f5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Personal background: family history, high school education in Melbourne, philanthropy in Australia; Career: accountant, entrepreneur, development of sports clubs in Australia, early business ventures with Jack Chia and Charles F. Feeney, relationship with InterPacific Group, Runaway Bay; Couran Cove Resort: architectural design, tourism industry, hotel industry, development costs, financial problems, management problems, personnel; Atlantic Philanthropies: Australian grantees, Australian higher education, Australian medical research; Personal recollections: Charles F. Feeney, Paul S. Slawson, Daryl Jackson; Interactions: Charles F. Feeney, Christopher G. Oechsli, Daryl Jackson, Harvey P. Dale.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 audience="internal" id="aspace_07138d68c53f8d635a26b241b6d8462d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cohen, Ed</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Farber, Myron A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-12-13/2007-12-13">2007-12-13</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d5186347c72beb034dad84b51f7830a5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Early life and education: Born in 1942, grew up in Scarsdale, attended Amherst, started law career, father had an influence on him.  Career: Worked dually in law and business, began working as director with Urban Development Corporation, left to be a McKinsey Partner, eventually became highly ranked with General Atlantic, working in real estate and "venture philanthropy".  Description of conflicts within General Atlantic.  He started the Echoing Green Foundation, worked in computer and technology investing, developed philanthropic and business theories.  Interactions with Charles Feeney, Harvey Dale, Steve Deening, Paul Slawson, David Hodgson.  Separation with AP, continues philanthropic work.</p></scopecontent><processinfo id="aspace_75246f7591274f4044ac503d9edd113c"><head>Processing Information</head><p>Archivist redacted transcript: pages 130, 145</p></processinfo></c02><c02 id="aspace_6968b851173e83e58081f56dd00ab40d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Conroy, Mark</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-06-20/2006-06-22" type="inclusive">2006-06-20-2006-06-22</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7d7b402cb0dfdf05a1e0c22f684c1cfd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Born December 25, 1945 in Plattsburgh, New York; life on a dairy farm in Upstate New York until 1992; first marriage 1967-1996, two daughters; Peace Corps in Guatemala early 1990s; working for East Meets West [EMW] in Vietnam starting 1994; second marriage to vice director of EMW Hoang Thi Hang Tam, with two sons; non-profit health clinics for children in Vietnam; Charles F. Feeney's [CFF] and Atlantic Philanthropies [AP] funding for EMW construction projects; AP funding for EMW to establish electronic library at University of Da Nang; CFF concerns about anonymity; collaboration between Vietnamese and Australian universities; grant reporting to AP and for EMW; EMW expansion of funding base beyond AP; interactions with Robert Matousek in Vietnam; interactions with CFF.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_3796907d031da2b239d72f5f30eb3c21" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cory, Suzanne</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-06-29/2006-06-29">2006-06-29</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e6a22bc455684a0ffef6ed6d761db575"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Personal background: born and raised in Melbourne, Australia, studied biochemistry at Melbourne University, Ph. D. at Cambridge, post-doctoral fellowship in Geneva; research at Walter and Eliza Hall Institute [WEHI]; becomes WEHI director in 1996; funding research in Australia; interactions with Charles F. Feeney, Christopher G. Oechsli, Ronald W. Clarke; grants from Atlantic Philanthropies; projects undertaken with AP money; parasitic disease control and research in Vietnam.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_e0e208424455cf07809e445cebd145ca" level="file"><did><unittitle>Covert, Angela</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-11-14/2006-11-27" type="inclusive">2006-11-14-2006-11-27</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c190d8ac8b129d0f985fbfac394b6d99"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Childhood; education: opportunities for women in 1950s; career: education policy, education reform, education for children with disabilities; Atlantic Philanthropies: anonymity, grant-making decisions, focus on education, youth programs, impact of school reforms; grants: Consortium for Policy Research in Education, Summerbridge, Johns Hopkins University Talented Youth; interactions: Atlantic Philanthropies Board of Advisors, Raymond L. Handlan, Patricia Smalley, James W. Spencer, W. Keith Kennedy, Harvey P. Dale, Joel L. Fleishman, John R. Healy.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_68a0c10324b593ed11323e7f57686a91" level="file"><did><unittitle>Daglian, Ara</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Rowland, Steven S.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-01-31/2007-02-08" type="inclusive">2006-01-31-2007-02-08</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ad1cc69a716f5f8fcc0bb1944998d366"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Born in Washington Heights, New York; early life in New York City; United States Navy V-12 Program at age seventeen; early undergraduate education at Columbia University; active duty in Korean War; experiences at Cornell University Hotel School; early work at Cornell Club; Century Club; managing director of New York City Chapter of Club Managers Association (current); Charles F. Feeney [CFF], early life; reminiscences of John Harney; CFF's involvement in creation of Cornell Club; reminiscences of CFF and family.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_caefdd2feb966965eea1f130a3dc61cc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dale, Harvey</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Grele, Ronald J.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2005-10-12/2007-12-06" type="inclusive">2005-10-12-2007-12-06</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5d7158d252e1426891b30f155a1169f4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Personal background: childhood in New York, education, career as tax lawyer; Duty Free Shoppers: history, financial problems in 1960s, tax structuring; Atlantic Philanthropies: history and development, mission, grants [education and bio-medical research], personnel, strategic planning, anonymity; Interactions: Charles F. Feeney, Frank H. T. Rhodes, Raymond L. Handlan, John R. Healy, Joel L. Fleishman, F. A. O. Schwarz, Jr., Elizabeth J. McCormack, Leon P. Sterling, Anthony M. Pilaro, Ira M. Millstein.</p></scopecontent><processinfo id="aspace_28178314aeb93f23e1e50e3e064f479b"><head>Processing Information</head><p>Archivist redacted transcript: pages 317, 327; pages 318-326 (removed)</p></processinfo></c02><c02 id="aspace_1cb75d32930992056df779dd4649dff3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Denning, Steve</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Rowland, Steven S.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-03-13/2006-03-13">2006-03-13</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e27aabb2cf95c3089abedee0319355f8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Personal background: family history, Mormon childhood in Salt Lake City; Education: B.S, Georgia Institute of Technology, 1970; M.S. in management science, Naval Postgraduate School; M.B.A., Stanford Business School, 1978; Career: management consultant, McKinsey &amp; Co, General Atlantic Corporation; General Atlantic Corporation: investments strategies, investment areas, personnel; Atlantic Philanthropies: mission, areas of focus, grantees; Interactions: Charles F. Feeney, Edwin C. Cohen, George M. Parker.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_dc3debd93f12081a27bc4c4f691d2970" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dietel, Bill</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-11-29/2007-11-29">2007-11-29</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d1038b204846fed81ea3aefd5a9fb9a4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Childhood: Raised in Churchville, New York, education: Phillips Exeter Academy (1945), Navy service (1945-1946), Princeton (AB) 1950, married 1951, Yale (MA) 1952, University of London/Institute of Historical Research (1953-1954), Yale (Ph. D.) 1959; five children; career: professor at University of Massachusetts – Amherst (1954-1959), Amherst College (1959-1961); Principal of Emma Willard School (1961-1970); work with Rockefeller Foundation as strategist, Executive VP, and President (1970-1987); comparison of old and new philanthropic foundations; consultant work with Atlantic; relationships with Harvey Dale, Chuck Feeney, Joel Fleishman and Ray Handlan; general thoughts on modern philanthropy.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict audience="internal" id="aspace_cefb39e7bf1ba6f2bb4d96fafb7964ed"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access restricted until death.</p></accessrestrict></c02><c02 id="aspace_c578caa09966a4b66d6745443754c952" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dittman, David</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-03-08/2006-03-08">2006-03-08</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e20f601674db8fbbe6f2d0d6abcb9a61"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: 
Personal background: family history, childhood in Ohio, education, military service, career in academia (accounting); Cornell University School of Hotel Administration: deanship, higher education administration, funding, fund-raising, alumni affairs, financial problems, relationship with Atlantic Philanthropies, Atlantic Philanthropies-funded programs; Interactions: James Clark, Charles F. Feeney, Frank H. T. Rhodes, James W. Spencer, Raymond L. Handlan.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ac3bd30bd5bc9bd15cd7a4b2ad49f417" level="file"><did><unittitle>Downer, Roger</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-11-12/2007-11-13" type="inclusive">2007-11-12-2007-11-13</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2e390779e7edff5cab2304cd71622183"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Background: Born Belfast, only child of working-class Protestant family, very active in sports; English father, telephone engineer; Irish mother, active in church; education: BA and MA, zoology, Queens University; Ph.D., zoology, University of Western Ontario; career: high school teacher of science and rugby; professor at University of Waterloo, Hokkaido University, and Oxford University; Vice-President of University of Waterloo; President of Asian Institute of Technology in Bankok, Thailand; President of University of Limerick [UL]; consultant and lecturer; Atlantic Philanthropies [AP]: meeting with Charles F. Feeney in 1998, recounting of conversations and meetings with Charles F. Feeney; recounting of problems and solutions around fundraising in early years at UL, building of research programs, collaboration with industrial partners, description and critique of Program for Research in Third Level Institutes, collaboration between universities on research; consideration of various funding programs including AP, description of AP's involvement with UL and affect of AP support on UL, development of physical facilities at UL, interaction with AP after cessation of grant making activity in Ireland; change in fundraising culture in Ireland; description of trip to Cuba with AP and meetings with Fidel Castro; involvement with the Irish Peace Institute; involvement with creation of Medical School at UL; thoughts on different types of philanthropic organizations.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_26dcffb990b2d24dde252a323b157747" level="file"><did><unittitle>Downey, James</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Grele, Ronald J.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-06-15/2007-06-15">2007-06-15</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1d7b4213ffd71978dd5e70be823ba9eb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Personal recollections: Paul S. Slawson tenure, Charles F. Feeney's business ventures in Prague, Trade Management Institute; General Atlantic Corporation: personnel, influence of Charles F. Feeney, Pacific Islands Clubs, Western Athletic Clubs, Couran Cove; Atlantic Philanthropies: mission, grantees, higher education in Ireland, Interactions: Charles F. Feeney, Christopher G. Oechsli, Paul S. Slawson, Paul B. Hannon.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_1b3aded0db38746d12c8650e37b4a236" level="file"><did><unittitle>Downton, Christine</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Grele, Ronald J.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-04-17/2007-10-30" type="inclusive">2006-04-17-2007-10-30</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_efbc93eadca4e63657ab40f29e0e8e84"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Childhood: England, Cotswald, father a clerk in civil service, mother an elementary school teacher, brief biography of father, class consciousness; education: Caerphilly Grammar School for Girls, London School of Economics, New School for Social Research M.A., London School of Economics Ph.D., University of Leeds; career: gender discrimination, University of Bath (Lecturer), The Bank of England, Rothchild's, County Bank, Pareto Partners, Atlantic Philanthropies; New York: impressions of America, life in Greenwich Village; Latin America: impression of Venezuela, Colombia and Mexico; personal life: husband; Atlantic Philanthropies: impressions of Atlantic Philanthropies, work in Ireland and South Africa, colleague reminiscences</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_49d676d625860a204e4bdfb4848356d2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Doyle, Dan</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-01-09/2007-01-09">2007-01-09</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_36f531cbf48166ad3affcf09d759ae5a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Personal background: family history, childhood in Massachusetts, education, athletics, coaching career; Atlantic Philanthropies: Institute for International Sport, disadvantaged youth, grant-making decisions, mission; Interactions: Charles F. Feeney, Charles J. Haughey, Christopher J. Dodd, Raymond L. Handlan.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_2428a1cd84a71076feeb99077d5a85fe" level="file"><did><unittitle>Edmonds, Robert</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Farber, Myron A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-08-05/2006-08-05">2006-08-05</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2c67cdcfae528df0aec8d5185ff46da9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Born 1927 in Paris to French mother and Welsh/Australian father; early life in France and England during World War II; brief military career as air craftsman 1 in England and Egypt; tour of United States in early 1950s; mid-1950s entry into duty free business and selling liquor on U.S. Navy ships in Europe; meeting and hiring Charles F. Feeney [CFF] in 1956 or 1957 to sell duty free liquor; business partnerships and CFF selling duty free goods to tourists; CFF and Duty Free Shoppers [DFS]; impressions of and interactions with CFF.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_46d8e886e31d78f8b117d1fd17e8854f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Engelhardt, Sara</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-07-19/2007-07-23" type="inclusive">2007-07-19-2007-07-23</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9fc6a8fad433468310d589d3c4f02802"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Philanthropy: history and development in U.S., philanthropic trends 1990s, grant-making decisions, tax structuring, foundation laws and regulations, innovation in philanthropic theory, GuideStar; Foundation Center: database redesign/online project, personnel; Atlantic Philanthropies: history, Charles F. Feeney, mission, spend-down, anonymity, relationship with grantees, relationship with other philanthropic foundations, areas of focus, leadership, personnel; Personal recollections and interactions: Raymond L. Handlan, John R. Healy, Harvey P. Dale, Joel L. Fleishman, Thomas R. Buckman.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_a46e166a3391e1b9c5fcd676456f01a9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Erskine, David</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Grele, Ronald J.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-09-19/2007-09-19">2007-09-19</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f561e7204bdde9969ff014e57418abe1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Personal background: childhood in Devon, England, family history, university experience, early career as investment officer for IBM's UK pension fund and Global Asset Management, recruitment and employment at Atlantic Philanthropies; Atlantic Philanthropies: investment policies, grant-making decisions, board of directors, personnel issues, mission, anonymity, management, strategic planning; interactions: Philip Coates, Harvey P. Dale, Christine V. Downton, Michael Gwinnell, Elizabeth J. McCormack, Frederick A. O. "Fritz" Schwarz, Jr., Margaret A. Hern, Margaret V. Hill, Charles F. Feeney, Edwin S. Cohen, Jr, John R. Healy.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_6c22cda495e67999350ef0d14b14d05e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Eydt, Fred</unittitle><unitdate normal="2005-12-28/2006-10-17" type="inclusive">2005-12-28-2006-10-17</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4836cb035ee061386b5cff3670e5d69e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Educational history; career: Cornell University: alumni association, fund-raising; endowments; philanthropy in the United States: history, development, philanthropists; Atlantic Philanthropies: mission, board of advisors, grant-making decisions, anonymity, spend-down, investments, higher education in Ireland; Interactions with Charles F. Feeney, Jacques C. Nordeman, Harvey P. Dale, Frank H. T. Rhodes, W. Keith Kennedy, Raymond L. Handlan.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_0a1feb122de31a4b87257c3eccf7ca55" level="file"><did><unittitle>Feeney, Charles F</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Clark, Mary Marshall</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2005-11-30/2005-12-07" type="inclusive">2005-11-30-2005-12-07</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_15b274f6400021ee535a90438fede41e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Personal background: Grew up in Elizabeth, NJ; Two older sisters, one younger; Irish-American parents Enlisted in army in 1948: served as U.S. Air Force radio operator during the Korean War; Went to Cornell University of Hotel Administration on Korean G.I. Bill: sold sandwiches for money; Graduated from Cornell and road tripped to California stopping in Reno to gamble for money; Enrolled in summer course in Russian at UCLA; studied French at University of Grenoble; Set up summer camp for children in the South of France; Worked at Naval Port locker storage in Villefranche; Began to sell alcohol and cars to people on Naval ships in Europe; Developed tourist home delivery system in 1958; First concession opened in Honolulu in 1961, first Duty Free Shop in 1962 when airport opened; Reminisces of other Duty Free Shops opened in Hong Kong, Paris, Guam, Anchorage, Tokyo, Saipan, Frankfurt; Established Duty Free Shoppers scholarship at Cornell as early act of Philanthropy; 
With discussion of colleagues: Harry Adler, Bob Miller, Jeff Mahlstedt, Tony Pilaro, Harvey P. Dale, Peter S. Fithian, Lee Sterling, John Gentzbourger, Bob Edmonds, Bob Bruso, Michel Camus</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 audience="internal" id="aspace_0a864c3abe1bff343ab766a4a9fd7b2d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fithian, Peter</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Grele, Ronald J.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2005-11-15/2005-11-16" type="inclusive">2005-11-15-2005-11-16</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_77b0facdf074a3eaaf1b916f1dfb4b3e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Born 1928 and raised outside of Boston; educated at Mt. Hermon School for Boys and Cornell University School of Hotel Administration; 1950s in Naval Reserve Officer Training Corps; career in hotel business, especially in resorts and in Hawaii; establishing and growing Hawaiian greeting business; building business of Duty Free Shoppers [DFS] in Hawaii in early 1960s; tourism and shopping patterns in Hawaii; sale of DFS; interactions with Robert W. Miller and Charles F. Feeney.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_7c1941db36cb69cc5eb5660cbbbcbd20" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fitzpatrick, Arlene</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-10-10/2008-11-08" type="inclusive">2006-10-10-2008-11-08</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d351a6cdc2373de47f4c305c20cf28d5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: New Jersey childhood, education, family history; reminiscences: Feeney family members, Danielle J. Feeney, Daninos family members, Desmond Kinney; Atlantic Philanthropies: history, anonymity, mission.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_b39380a80c15b4d8ee707be4ac121fbe" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fleishman, Joel</unittitle><unitdate normal="2006-04-24/2007-04-02" type="inclusive">2006-04-24-2007-04-02</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f47738eb766b4413793f43feafe3fbc0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Career: Duke University law professor; founder of Terry Sanford Institute of Public Policy
Philanthropy: history and development in U.S., focus areas, philanthropic philosophies, philanthropic initiatives, Foundation Center; Atlantic Philanthropies: anonymity, BridgeSpan, BridgeStar, areas of focus, higher education, disadvantaged youth, personnel, mission, grantees, Urban Institute; Interactions: Jacques C. Nordeman, Charles F. Feeney, Harvey P. Dale, James W. Spencer, Personal recollections: Charles F. Feeney, Harvey P. Dale, Raymond L. Handlan.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_330e5002403e41ff23424dfe1f8327f7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Flynn, Bill</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-03-20/2007-03-22" type="inclusive">2007-03-20-2007-03-22</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d702e49241c2e4f55a8edcb0f3cc4297"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Personal background: Irish-American childhood, family history, education, military service, career in insurance industry; Ireland: relationship with Irish-America, 20th century socio-politics, religion, violence in Northern Ireland; Irish peace process: involvement of American government, British government involvement, U.S. visa issue, Sinn Féin, Irish Republican Army, ceasefire negotiations; Interactions: Charles F. Feeney, Niall O'Dowd, Gerard Adams, Jr., William J. Clinton, J. Martin McGuinness.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_c523daaf14ac6ed85fa4cabdeafbdd6e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Futoran, Robert</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Farber, Myron A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-01-19/2007-01-21" type="inclusive">2007-01-19-2007-01-21</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b741741eb1f52a86cab2141d017d6b32"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Personal background: family history, childhood in Brooklyn, NY, education, military service, career in retail; Duty Free Shoppers: history, business strategies, airport concessions, products, personnel, employee compensation, management, business expansion; Interactions: Charles F. Feeney, Adrian Bellamy, Anthony M. Pilaro, Robert W. Miller, Alan M. Parker, Joseph P. Lyons, Richard Wade, John Monteiro.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ca4847952c3d1d60b4d50cd0947ef3dd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Gentzbourger, John</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Farber, Myron A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-06-17/2006-06-18" type="inclusive">2006-06-17-2006-06-18</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_06e66f140d02c453f8b8dd7ca558f714"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Personal background: family history, impact of World War II, childhood in France, education, military service, relationship with Morali-Daninos family; Duty Free Shoppers: history, Tourists International, products, relationship with Camus family, business development, Japanese tourist trade, personnel, business strategies, airport concessions, Far East operations, European operations, management issues; Camus Overseas Limited: business development, products, management; Interactions: Leon P. Sterling, Charles F. Feeney, Danielle J. Feeney, Robert W. Miller, Robert J. Bruso.</p></scopecontent><processinfo id="aspace_3ba6c5fb72eeb4938ecb60bab94fa644"><head>Processing Information</head><p>Archivist redacted transcript: pages 190-196 removed</p></processinfo></c02><c02 id="aspace_fb14d0c50568dd44e2eedd29fb67633b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Gibson, Dennis</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-06-27/2006-06-27">2006-06-27</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_eaf50a506e92af6cc897f8f09eb08a25"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Personal background: childhood in England, family history, education, career in higher education administration in Australia;
Australia: higher education administration, government involvement, funding, the Green Paper, fund-raising, philanthropy; Atlantic Philanthropies: Australian investments (tourism), Australian grants (bio-medical research, higher education), higher education in Vietnam; Interactions: Charles F. Feeney, Christopher G. Oechsli, Le Nhan Phuong, David Beanland.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_2617916fa3fe8eba3f699a717fbd573a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Godé, Pierre</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Rowland, Steven S.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-11-14/2006-11-16" type="inclusive">2006-11-14-2006-11-16</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a729f3102304af59b25f5018a20cd32a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Career: commercial barrister, law professor, law consultant; Bernard Arnault: interactions, history of Louis Vuitton Moet Hennessy, acquisition of Duty Free Shoppers, products, business strategies; Duty Free Shoppers: LVMH buyout interactions: Charles F. Feeney, Anthony M. Pilaro, George M. Parker, Robert W. Miller, Ira M. Millstein, Myron E. Ullman, III.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_92e976bebdfca137ff6ff72806da508a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Goldman, Robert</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Grele, Ronald J.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-05-25/2006-05-25">2006-05-25</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e5c4d05ac37b5b7fc576fd0007f47d42"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Personal background: family history, childhood in Los Angeles, education, American socio-politics 1960s-1970s, Atlantic Philanthropies: grant-making decisions, mission, personnel, board members, investments; General Atlantic Corporation: InterPacific, Western Athletic Clubs, Pacific Islands Club; Interactions: Charles F. Feeney, Paul S. Slawson, Gerold C. Wunderlich, Jr., David Smith.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict audience="internal" id="aspace_5a32c8ccd88b5289f87c886dba8fe22d"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access restricted until death.</p></accessrestrict></c02><c02 id="aspace_fc07b14d87af57108be46b5e61a3dbdc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Gwinnell, Michael</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Farber, Myron A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-11-13/2006-11-16" type="inclusive">2006-11-13-2006-11-16</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_32d97a7dcc58cb3820f4931f00a8c4f4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Personal background: family history, childhood in England and Canada, impact of World War II, education, career in finance; Atlantic Philanthropies: General Atlantic Corporation, investments, board members, personnel and staffing issues, management, DFS profits, grant-making decisions, mission, anonymity; Interactions: Charles F. Feeney, Paul B. Hannon, George M. Parker, Paul S. Slawson, Harvey P. Dale, John R. Healy.</p></scopecontent><processinfo id="aspace_4e87fa86c800d03042689d169c815ede"><head>Processing Information</head><p>Archivist redacted transcript: pages 266; Removed: pages 126-128, 137-53, 212-13, 262-263, 267-69, 275-79, 281-85, 287-89, 303-13, 319-325.</p></processinfo><accessrestrict id="aspace_9ecdfdbbeb2906ebfe842eb7d81440d9"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>An unredacted transcript can be made accessible in 2038 or upon death of interviewee.</p></accessrestrict></c02><c02 id="aspace_9608c0c1a139ac9bc38e714a7bc5ccd8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Handlan, Ray</unittitle><unitdate normal="2005-12-01/2006-03-31" type="inclusive">2005-12-01-2006-03-31</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6a578b5e4cdd201d3d3c4eb69ace722e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Career: vice-president of development Syracuse University 1981, director of development Cornell University 1975-80, president Atlantic Services Company; Atlantic Philanthropies: early history, mission, areas of focus: higher education, disadvantaged youth, personnel, anonymity, trends in philanthropy, board members; Personal recollections: Charles F. Feeney, Interactions: Charles F. Feeney, Frederick J. Eydt, Harvey P. Dale, Joel L. Fleishman, John R. Healy, Frank H. T. Rhodes.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ff283a665c64a66c2f97f78f68085f55" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hannon, Paul</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Farber, Myron A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2005-11-14/2005-11-15" type="inclusive">2005-11-14-2005-11-15</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_49beacd8c1c1cf2e79c2dabc0e2794a0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: ...subsequent economic turnaround and massive success of DFS; specific targeting of the Japanese tourist/consumer; DFS partners' contribution to and roles in company's governance; Charles Feeney's working relationship and tensions with DFS partners; dynamism of target market and difficulties adjusting to these changing demands; creation of COL and DFS' role in marketing and expanding Camus' global market; DFS competition with other duty-free entities; creation of GAGL and General Atlantic Partners [GAP] as investment branches for Charles Feeney's interests; complexity of GAGL organizational structure; internal dynamics and tensions within GAGL, plus its failed economic ventures; legal ownership and division of DFS/GAGL shares; sale of DFS to Moët Hennessy Louis Vuitton; creation of Atlantic Philanthropies [AP]; impressions of Charles Feeney, his work ethic, intuitive approach to investment and philanthropic drive.</p></scopecontent><processinfo id="aspace_be22b23ed8eba85487ad4f18f478d5d1"><head>Processing Information</head><p>Archivist redacted transcript: page 80, pages 74-79 (removed)</p></processinfo></c02><c02 id="aspace_846d7cd8e695c83e97beee3e0cfa64c3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hay, John</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-07-04/2006-07-05" type="inclusive">2006-07-04-2006-07-05</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_92645d92581ef27dc4f2779762dcc4d3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Born September 21, 1942 in Perth, Australia; early life and education in Western Australia; Hackett Research Scholarship for PhD in eighteenth-century English and French literature at Cambridge, England; fundraising at Australian universities; Atlantic Philanthropies [AP] funding for creation of Institute of Molecular Bioscience, Queensland Brain Institute, Australian Institute of Biomaterials and Nanotechnology, and Borough of Brisbane Women's Hospital; AP support for other institutions in Brisbane, Australia; Australia and AP role in developing higher education in Vietnam; Charles F. Feeney's [CFF] interest in Ireland; interactions with CFF.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_b73229712a64ce9fe0815a2607bc053d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Healy, John A</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-04-03/2007-11-15" type="inclusive">2007-04-03-2007-11-15</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5da6cef18726baec099bbf22eb2c79e7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: ...Strategic Learning and Evaluation Director, program executive for higher education;  Atlantic Philanthropies (AP): reflection on office culture, discreet nature of AP grant operations, development of  Irish higher educational system, discussion of Programme for Research in Third-Level Institutions (PRTLI), discussion of  Higher Education Authority, AP transformation in anonymity policy, change in AP Board structure,   interaction with AP New York office, AP decision to transition from higher education, transition from AP's broad grant allocation to organization's four distinct program areas, research in potential funding initiatives for AP in public health arena, AP work with HIV/ AIDS crisis in South Africa, discussion of the Board's opinion in relation to AP's four distinct programs, grant work in Cuba, work in the Strategic Learning and Evaluation program;colleague reminiscences</p></scopecontent><processinfo id="aspace_93fde8a1ff462a3aaea4e651e96f33d1"><head>Processing Information</head><p>Archivist redacted transcript: pages 138, 145, 148; pages 146-147 (removed)</p></processinfo></c02><c02 id="aspace_df537943de944886f6a3b3f2dd44a226" level="file"><did><unittitle>Healy, John R</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Clark, Mary Marshall</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2005-08-23/2007-02-15" type="inclusive">2005-08-23-2007-02-15</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2f4b2a133229c69b9a1c46c02a25aa4b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Personal background: Dublin childhood, English boarding school recollections, family history, educated at Trinity College Dublin; Ireland: politics '50s-'80s, employment opportunities '60s, civil strife, Irish-American Partnership; Irish Republican Army, peace process, post-peace process economy; Atlantic Philanthropies: early history, mission, areas of focus, grantees, Atlantic Foundation Services Company, Irish higher education, Vietnamese higher education programs, Australian higher education, human rights, disadvantaged youth, anonymity, personnel; Interactions: Charles F. Feeney, Padraig Berry, Edward M. Walsh, Harvey P. Dale, Joel L. Fleishman.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_5702206dd768cc68058855e05f61e126" level="file"><did><unittitle>Healy, Ursula</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-10-10/2006-11-08" type="inclusive">2006-10-10-2006-11-08</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8243247e4916cbcb79d57362bef735d7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: New Jersey childhood, education, family history, 
community structure and relations in Union, N.J., 
nursing career, reminiscences of Feeney family 
members, Danielle J. Feeney; Atlantic Philanthropies: board members, history, mission, Irish higher education.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_822d0d24625a16d08bc6d5261631c4c8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hodgson, David</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Rowland, Steven S.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-11-08/2006-11-10" type="inclusive">2006-11-08-2006-11-10</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ffdf8e8b8824ac72b1ea0dc4332484f9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Personal background: family history, education;
 Atlantic Philanthropies: investments (technology),
 mission, grants (education, bio-medical research,
 disadvantaged); Interactions: Charles F. Feeney, 
Steven A. Denning, Edwin C. Cohen, George M. Parker.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 audience="internal" id="aspace_355b8cdc9e9021d3381e9f66037a8050" level="file"><did><unittitle>Howell, Ted</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-04-04/2007-04-04" type="inclusive">2007-04-04</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0c088ce04966fbe5c976a6242a5217fe"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Personal background: family history, politics; Ireland: 20th century Irish socio-politics, trade and labor unions, community relations in Belfast, peace process, Sinn Fein, Irish Republican Army; Atlantic Philanthropies: Irish higher education, community development projects; Interactions: Charles F. Feeney, Niall O'Dowd, Gerard Adams, Jr., George J. Mitchell, Bruce A. Morrison, William J. Flynn.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_5b67fb3635ce31d8cffba8a1270448b5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Jamison, Joe</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-03-14/2007-05-11" type="inclusive">2007-03-14-2007-05-11</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b4baf3bef55baebcc3e5b51fbcd08f04"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Personal background: childhood in New York, family history, education; New York: 20th century socio-politics, labor unions, minority groups; Ireland: 20th century socio-politics, interaction with Irish America, labor unions, peace process, Sinn Fein, Irish Republican Army; Interactions: Charles F. Feeney, Niall O'Dowd, John R. Healy.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_2886a49fce39b6341aeff223de77856b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Karoubi, Jean</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Farber, Myron A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-02-03/2006-02-09" type="inclusive">2006-02-03-2006-02-09</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_220606dd9aacaa798a5c0b71b673dc95"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Personal background: childhood in Algeria, impact of post-World War II French colonialism, education in 1950s France, relationship with Morali-Daninos family, history of Morali-Daninos family; Duty Free Shoppers: history and development, personnel, products; General Atlantic Group: hotel ventures, acquisition of retail chains; Feeney divorce proceedings and settlement; Interactions: Danielle J. Feeney, Charles F. Feeney, Harvey P. Dale.</p></scopecontent><processinfo id="aspace_6cb92c23cd42ba72841c20de2d21378d"><head>Processing Information</head><p>Archivist redacted transcript: pages 119, 147, 161, 175, 201 ; pages 120-146, 176-200 removed.</p></processinfo></c02><c02 id="aspace_f09ebd2eddabadce98c8259aea3d9a81" level="file"><did><unittitle>Kennedy, Keith</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-05-02/2006-05-03" type="inclusive">2006-05-02-2006-05-03</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b2a8a2ea3fa78321253e904aa1f47d63"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Born near Vancouver, Washington; education through PhD in agronomy; career as administrator at Cornell University; grant-making process at Atlantic Philanthropic Service Company [APSC]; development of work-study program Cornell Tradition at Cornell University; APSC funding at Cornell University; issues around APSC anonymity.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 audience="internal" id="aspace_64aa9821db79aa69e9e420651e4853a5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Kraak, Gerald</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-09-13/2007-09-13">2007-09-13</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_aa77ecd6293c64257ea5836c47ab5ca7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: born 1956 in Johannesburg, South Africa, Dutchfather, mechanical engineer, mother of British ancestry, secretary in Parliament; Education: Christian National education under Apartheid, studied history and literature at University of Capetown, wanted to become teacher; evaded South African Army conscription; moved to Netherlands on political asylum; Moved to London; Work: National Union of South African Students, South African Labor and Development, Dutch antiapartheid movement, International Defense and Aid Fund in London, Interfund in South Africa, joins Atlantic after five years at Interfund; Reminisces of early Tara days and the relationship between Interfund and Tara, how Kraak came to work for Atlantic; With discussion of colleagues: John R Healy, Harvey P. Dale, Stephen Burkeman, Achmat Zackie (Treatment Action Campaign), Charles F. Feeny, etc.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 audience="internal" id="aspace_61af50662d70ef4b7b2ba6a21c160921" level="file"><did><unittitle>Kresge, Ted</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Farber, Myron A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-10-26/2006-10-27" type="inclusive">2006-10-26-2006-10-27</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bad59e68ea03c46aa7bd7fdaa10d9c78"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Born in Westerly, Rhode Island, January 1945; early life on New Jersey Shore; S.S. Kresge: philanthropist; grandfather's cousin; founder of K-Mart; anti-Vietnam War protests at University of Virginia law school in late 1960s; marriage to Margaret Feild Kresge in 1970; Anthony M. Pilaro as tax client at Price Waterhouse in 1970s; Duty Free Shoppers [DFS] tax issues; restructuring of DFS for tax purposes; philanthropy and taxation; General Atlantic Group Limited offices and business developments in Bermuda; United States taxes, citizenship and residency; creation of Atlantic Foundation and Atlantic Trust; transfer of DFS shares to Danielle Feeney; transfer of Charles F. Feeney's [CFF} wealth to Atlantic Philanthropies; sale of DFS to Moët Hennessy Louis Vuitton [LVMH]; divorce between CFF and Danielle Feeney; relationship between CFF and Helga Flaiz; CFF support of Gerald Adams, Jr. and Northern Ireland; interactions with Charles F. Feeney and colleagues.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_61484a7094b50fe09493deeb73895f60" level="file"><did><unittitle>LaMarche, Gara</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Clark, Mary Marshall</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2008-05-08/2008-05-08">2008-05-08</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a265ff66eef815777009b63d16b4a567"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Personal background:  born 1954 in Westerly, Rhode Island; recount of family history and great-grandfather; Disappearance of grandmother and grandfather; Discovery of estranged half-aunt (daughter of missing grandfather) with strong feminist and liberal views – an ACLU member; Research into mother who was committed to mental institute forty plus years until death; Trace of family history back to the seventeenth century in Montreal, Canada; Eldest of three children; Attendance of Catholic School in Rhode Island; Attendance of St. Bernard's, which is a Catholic boys' high school in Connecticut; French and Italian on father's side; Episcopalian mother; Modest middle-class upbringing; Recollection of  early curiosity in biography and presidential information, but non-involvement of parents in education; Family's residence on shore and regular attendance of beach club in childhood; Acceptance onto Junior Varsity Debate team; Remembrance of a progressive high school experience, though Catholic; Position as Editor of school newspaper; Acceptance to and study at Columbia University; Part-time job as staff associate for the American Civil Liberties Union in New York on Academic Freedom Committee; Elected by the Board of the ACLU to be a member of the Academic Freedom Committee; Elected vice-chair of the committee after two years; twelve-year career at ACLU; ACLU Board Member; Executive Committee of ACLU; Work at Human Rights Watch, and then at Open Society Institute; Discussion of anomalous career and white male privilege</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_c6e3687c0aca5f01f1536e7a3471c491" level="file"><did><unittitle>Lansdale, Edward</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Grele, Ronald J.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-09-07/2006-09-07">2006-09-07</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_705d0f3a4742be6ea22157bb2542eb98"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: 
Personal background: family history, military service, early career, employment at Fleishman-Hillard; Atlantic Philanthropies: anonymity, public relations; Interactions: Peter McCue, Charles F. Feeney, Joel L. Fleishman, Harvey P. Dale.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_3e12eda5774c7573ea99353a5858e198" level="file"><did><unittitle>Logue, Ken</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-11-11/2007-01-22" type="inclusive">2006-11-11-2007-01-22</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ab4f29658a430da70a6a3ec48004eb44"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Born Glasgow, Scotland; education: B.A. in history, University of Edinburgh; Ph.D. in history, University of Edinburgh; career: work for Northern Ireland Council on Alcohol, freelance community relations consulting, consulting for Community Development Review Group, program officer for the Atlantic Philanthropies' ageing program; board memberships: Northern Ireland Council for Volunteer Action, War on Want, Glencairn People's Project; work with Institute for International Sport basketball project; shift from nonsectarian to anti-sectarian policies in dealing with Irish organizations; interactions with paramilitary organizations and individuals; impact of Belfast Agreement on reconciliation work; impact of revealing Charles F. Feeney's [CFF] ties to charity work; work with educational institutions; discussion of CFF's involvement in political reconciliation; work on issues related to ageing; reflections on Irish political progress.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_7ef335967ac4e5627266c143a9e0a904" level="file"><did><unittitle>Lunn, Hugh</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-06-06/2006-06-06">2006-06-06</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_356ac7da77ca23ea18e888f805d47e36"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Former foreign correspondent for Reuters,
 author; Australian childhood: education, family history, political climate; interactions with Colonel Ahn, Kenneth N. Fletcher, and Charles F. Feeney; recollections: travels and job assignments from 1960s-80s, Atlantic Philanthropy involvement in Australian higher education (Queensland University, Royal Melbourne Institute of Technology), Australian government, Couran Cove and Ron Clarke, Irish peace process, Paul Slawson.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict audience="internal" id="aspace_d0894cf4a2ba1f2f924ce3c785a59c86"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access restricted until death or 1/1/2028</p></accessrestrict></c02><c02 audience="internal" id="aspace_e5ea82237f66f61515030c8a40416740" level="file"><did><unittitle>Lyons, Joseph</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Farber, Myron A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-12-22/2007-01-04" type="inclusive">2006-12-22-2007-01-04</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_db0a2826225cf0ea076d699a9f120972"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Born March 20, 1939 in Providence, Rhode Island;
 early family life; stint in Europe working in army intelligence 1960-1962; employee of Tourists International, Duty Free Shoppers [DFS], Moët Hennessy Louis Vuitton [LVMH]; car sales to Americans in Europe;  duty-free sales of liquor, tobacco and perfume; establishment and growth of DFS in Hawaii; rise of Japanese tourism and tour groups in Hawaii in the late 1960s; DFS in: Anchorage and Fairbanks, Alaska; Hong Kong; Guam; Saipan; sale of DFS to LVMH; arbitrations between four partners in DFS during sale; Charles F. Feeney's (CFF) tendencies towards philanthropy; refusal of DFS to grant press interviews; interactions with CFF.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 audience="internal" id="aspace_1dbf7711f8e7b5a8ac7cf270dcb05918" level="file"><did><unittitle>Magee, Roy</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-11-06/2007-11-06">2007-11-06</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3f0e2843232dbedd7cafa1f5d498d1ca"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Early life: Born in Belfast, Northern Ireland 1930, happy childhood, working at 14 in mill, noticed some separation between protestants and Catholics.  Career: a strong individual, but lacked spiritual and emotional depth, thus went to ministry school, became priest, ordained 1958, served at several churches, The Troubles soon broke out, life surrounded by paramilitary violence and rioting of Irish factions.  Role in conflict: La Mon bombing helped him realize need for peace, began speaking to loyalist organizations about a cease fire 1981, held groups responsible for their violence and retaliatory acts, focused on political rather than military options.  Relationship with Atlantic Philanthropies: originally given anonymous funding for his peace initiatives, later worked more directly with Chuck Feeney, Ken Logue and Colin McCrea, the IRA announced a cease fire, AP continues to support Northern Ireland.  Later life: he now has Parkinson's and is less involved with the political/peace leaders, but remains supportive and serves as a resource.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_dc1be308782251f98d089cd9b1771bf2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mahlstedt, Jeff</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Farber, Myron A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-01-20/2006-01-20">2006-01-20</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_921c4f955e7ccc537527b12908f0a538"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview:  Personal background: childhood, family history, education, military service; Duty Free Shoppers: history and development, Far East operations, personnel, financial crisis of 1960s, products, concessions, Interactions: Charles F. Feeney, Robert W. Miller, Alan M. Parker, Anthony M. Pilaro, Leon P. Sterling, Jean E. Gentzbourger, John Monteiro, Joseph P. Lyon.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_2d79ce564caba43180036448e08285d7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mann, Michael</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-06-07/2006-06-07">2006-06-07</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cc7371ae354f14f240b372c9d8f12e81"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Born July 27, 1949 in Sydney, Australia; careers as
 journalist, ambassador and chief executive officer of Australian Broadcasting Corporation; connections to the Order of Malta; Australian ambassador to Vietnam beginning in 1998; development of Royal Melbourne Institute of Technology and Learning Resource Centers in Vietnam; relationship with Atlantic Philanthropies [AP] beginning in 2001 after board's visit to Hanoi; problems in Vietnamese higher education system; Australian quality control for education in Vietnam; AP funding for stadium; AP movement away from funding higher education; AP and concerns about anonymity; Australian philanthropy; interactions with Charles F. Feeney.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_d9a92cd04c149c94842586424ebe4462" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mansergh, Martin</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-03-28/2007-03-28">2007-03-28</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_68c65cbf2483e58a00b8a8b2cd59a8f0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: 
Early interactions with Charles F. Feeney [CFF]; discussion of Irish national policy concerning science education and research; reflection on impact of Irish Americans in supporting Ireland; discussion of influence of American government in Irish peace process; Irish domestic concerns over American financial support of Irish factions; assessment of CFF's impact on Ireland.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_9c411ea4266f6062bcbfb0059bab1327" level="file"><did><unittitle>Matousek, Robert</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Farber, Myron A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2005-10-05/2005-10-06" type="inclusive">2005-10-05-2005-10-06</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9780befaa7ab8bff28fca0ed205aaf38"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Born South Dakota; education: University of South Dakota (1961); reminiscences of rural upbringing; military service in Europe; career: Cars International in Germany, Duty Free Shoppers [DFS] in Hawaii (1969-1973) and Paris (1974-1976), termination (1981); Duty Free Shoppers: importance of 747 and expansion, description of operations, corporate philosophy; Atlantic Philanthropies: foundation, work in Ireland, Vietnam, Cuba and Operation USA, South Africa; Charles F. Feeney [CFF]: history of relationship, differences between Robert W. Miller and CFF, interest in French culture, personality traits, relationship with Michel Camus, origins of philanthropic interest, personal influences; interactions with: Joseph P. Lyons, Robert W. Miller, Alan Parker, Anthony M. Pilaro.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_b7265cf52e174a8d1106bb99d5894c96" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mayor, Craig</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Grele, Ronald J.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-05-18/2006-05-18">2006-05-18</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8dc410da91c52de74030f8b7aeb484c8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Personal background: Bermudian childhood, family history, education, accounting career; Atlantic Philanthropies: General Atlantic Corporation, investments, tax structure, accounting, personnel; Interactions: Charles F. Feeney, Paul B. Hannon, George M. Parker.</p></scopecontent><processinfo id="aspace_4b438ca565b75fd88cb5abed7d99dc51"><head>Processing Information</head><p>Archivist redacted transcript: page 48</p></processinfo></c02><c02 id="aspace_6f35fafa90902113b7707181a028500a" level="file"><did><unittitle>McCarthy, Aine</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Grele, Ronald J.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-01-31/2007-01-31">2007-01-31</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c6b389f91f1f995a19e828856b81b705"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: childhood, family history, early education, career in hospitality management; Ireland: 20th century socio-politics, peace process, tourism, higher education; General Atlantic Corporation: Irish investments, grants to Irish universities, Couran Cove, Western Athletic Clubs, InterPacific, Pacific Island Clubs, Kiltiernan, Castletroy; Interactions: Charles F. Feeney, Padraig Berry, John R. Healy, Paul S. Slawson, James Downey.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_36395b0d752dab7e2258c3385e3ec7f8" level="file"><did><unittitle>McCormack, Elizabeth</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Clark, Mary Marshall</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2005-09-28/2005-09-28">2005-09-28</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bf967963c944c8f51adfc8665cdd9a1f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Born in New York City, grew up in Larchmont, NY; will attend Catholic school run by Dominican nuns; departure from Westchester to join Maplehurst: Convent of the Sacred Heart to finish high school; Enrollment at Manhattanville College; Decision to join the Society of the Sacred Heart in Albany; Attendance of school in Greenwich, Connecticut after two and a half years in Albany; After five years in Greenwich, travel to Rome to complete final vows; Return to Albany to Convent of the Sacred Heart at Kenwood to work in school; Will become headmistress of the Convent of the Sacred Heart at Greenwich for four years; Travel back to Manhattanville to work with school's President; Decision to obtain Ph.D. in Philosophy from Fordham University; Acceptance of Academic Dean position at Fordham after incumbent falls ill; Will write dissertation on British philosopher, F.H. Bradley; ... Acceptance of position as President of Manhattanville College in 1966; Instead of nun, decision to employ a man as Chief Financial Officer who will become McCormack's husband; Decision to leave the church; Reminisces of church politics and reorganization of antiquated orders; Travel to West Virginia to advise Jay Rockefeller; Acceptance of job offering at Rockefeller Brothers Fund after leaving Manhattanville; acceptance of position as chairman of the MacArthur Foundation; Meeting of Ray Handlan and Harvey P. Dale; Invitation to join Atlantic Philanthropies; Transition of CEO position from Harvey Dale to John R. Healy; Reminisces of Feeny and his order of anonymity; The sale of Duty Free Shoppers by Chuck Feeny; The pursuit of philanthropic ventures publicly; Process of identifying donees; Decision to bring gifts to an end;</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_1dde1a682671e911f2b439e2410ac963" level="file"><did><unittitle>McCoy, Grainne</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-11-07/2007-11-08" type="inclusive">2007-11-07-2007-11-08</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ed66cbbef3566ed6917c7ed34df62d99"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Born Armagh, Northern Ireland; childhood and convent school education in Moy, Northern Ireland; early awareness of religious and cultural segregation, internment policy; education: B.A. Textiles, University of Ulster, Ph.D Youth and Community Development, Queen' University; career: Educational Development Officer, Benburb Youth Center; Education and Welfare Officer, East Belfast; Community Relations Officer, Belfast City Council; Preparing for Post Conflict Trust grant recipient, Joseph Rowntree Charitable Trust and The Atlantic Philanthropies; grant-funded work in comparative conflict studies and conflict management; professor and researcher, Queen's University and University of Ulster; other: political awareness, Good Friday Agreement, family and friends in civil rights movement and paramilitary groups, government and non-governmental approaches to post conflict management, death threats; interactions: Charles F. Feeney, Ken Logie, Pamela Montgomery, Colin McCrea.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_79d018cfe0a43d564f4c0d061a65d25b" level="file"><did><unittitle>McCrea, Colin</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-11-09/2007-11-15" type="inclusive">2007-11-09-2007-11-15</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_20e8669d72f9513157ec63efd4f96082"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Childhood in west of Ireland; education at boarding
 school in Dublin; thoughts on social class division in Ireland; university in Dublin; career in marketing: Irish Export Board, emigration to and return from Germany, relationship with John Healy; career at Atlantic Philanthropies: development of Program for Research in Third-Level Institutions, relationship with Chuck Feeney, development of human rights programming; grant-making procedures.</p></scopecontent><processinfo id="aspace_77692bd9cac510ef2fd5dde4fe17809a"><head>Processing Information</head><p>Archivist redacted transcript: page 155</p></processinfo></c02><c02 id="aspace_10d2c835e1465ca8ec97facf4ba449f2" level="file"><did><unittitle>McCue, Peter</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Grele, Ronald J.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-08-24/2006-11-07" type="inclusive">2006-08-24-2006-11-07</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bc79133b05e4af1b64103bdabbcdc4b8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Personal background: childhood, family history, politics, religion, education, career in public relations; Atlantic Philanthropies: Irish peace process, Irish higher education, anonymity, funding, investments; Interactions: Charles F. Feeney, Edward Lonsdale, Paul B. Hannon, Harvey P. Dale, Edwin C. Cohen.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_0b6ca8a39819af863d6344ada6ec87b3" level="file"><did><unittitle>McGuinness, Martin</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-01-24/2007-01-24">2007-01-24</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bf4c4d3be76ca658ce3a2ee729a5bc65"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Young adulthood: political education in North
 Ireland, civil rights activism, connection to Irish-Americans; Irish peace process: involvement of William J. Clinton, Gerard Adams, Charles F. Feeney, John Hume, and Niall O'Dowd; interactions with Charles Feeney, cease-fire, creation of Sinn Fein office in Washington, D.C; Atlantic Philanthropy in Ireland: politics, higher-education.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_38c636de26c52dec0b84265c23e3172f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Miller, Bob</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Farber, Myron A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-02-13/2007-02-19" type="inclusive">2007-02-13-2007-02-19</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_974ce191216c489e8950c7d993129ddc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Personal background: childhood in Quincy, M.A., education at Cornell University, military service, family history; Duty Free Shoppers: Duty Free Shoppers: history, tax structure, business practices, financial problems in 1965, airport concession bids, impact of Japanese tourism, products, business expansion 1970s-1980s, economic downturn in 1990s; LVMH buyout; Wise Man intervention, philanthropy, personnel; Interactions: Charles F. Feeney, Alan M. Parker, Anthony M. Pilaro, John Monteiro, Bernard Arnault, Ira M. Millstein, Danielle J. Feeney, Desmond Byrne, Robert J. Bruso, Peter S. Fithian.</p></scopecontent><processinfo id="aspace_49aaa07bf42bf932b07179488b71cf05"><head>Processing Information</head><p>Archivist redacted transcript: pages 276-77, 332-33.</p></processinfo></c02><c02 id="aspace_6ffa2cc2ccdb255df5848a83f4bc438e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Minh, Truong Tan</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-10-09/2007-10-09">2007-10-09</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d17f2519d41d4fb8ce33bf8f4989ecd7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Early Life: Born in rural Vietnam, went to school under difficult conditions, worked also on farm, Vietnam war affected him and his community.  Attended medical school, moved to Saigon, attended many conferences around the world in leprosy and dermatology.  Discusses current position as director of health for his province, and the associated difficulties.  Worked to improve preventive care, talks about how the health care system works in Vietnam.  Funding: from Ngo's and AP, which has been a major funder to build hospitals and improve resources available to the medical community.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_fb1472483a10cc54a87a6265076ab6a3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mitchell, George</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-02-23/2007-02-23">2007-02-23</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_673962f21b2ff25d1becc54af6215d49"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: United States Senator (D-ME) 1989-1995 and
 17th Senate majority leader; Charles F. Feeney [CFF] and involvement in philanthropy; CFF and involvement in Irish peace process; organization of Good Friday Agreement; creation of Mitchell Scholarship Fund [later Mitchell Institute] with assistance of the Atlantic Philanthropies [AP]; leadership in AP-funded Northern Ireland Fund for Reconciliation; interactions with Harvey P. Dale.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_5eed517693615fe5f9722c5d158b3ec7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mitchell, Tom</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination></did><scopecontent id="aspace_933563819b4f97ef7acb6bb3151e494c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: ...; provost, Trinity, 1991-2001; Director, Atlantic
 Philanthropies, 2002- ; reflections on university life, life in US, pedagogical differences between American and Irish/European teaching, Ireland's economic problems and poor funding of higher education, efforts as Trinity provost to raise university's profile, formation of CARC [Comprehensive Academic Review Committee], reformulation of Trinity's academic orientation with introduction of American university traits; fundraising efforts as provost: establishment of Trinity Foundation; campus development and expansion plan with aid from Atlantic Philanthropies; member of Conference of Irish Universities [CHIU], chairman of CHIU, 1994; conflicts with educational funding policy, CHIU's efforts in pressuring funding policy reform; government's establishment of Program for Research in Third Level Institutions [PRTLI]...</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_a197a926e174bca84dcc07723d80f0fa" level="file"><did><unittitle>Monds, Fabian</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-11-03/2006-11-03">2006-11-03</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ad47c56cfd3db78eefbe710ecff9874b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Born November 1, 1940 in Omagh, Ireland;
 education: Omagh Christian Brothers grammar school, Queens University Belfast, Ph.D. at Purdue University in Indiana; lecturer and reader at Queens university Belfast in 1970s; University of Ulster positions beginning 1987: Head of School, Dean, and Pro Vice Chancellor for Research, Pro Vice Chancellor for Planning, and Provost of Magee College; Atlantic Philanthropies [AP] involvement with University of Ulster and Magee College in late 1990s; AP impact on higher education in Ireland; AP and issues of anonymous giving; impressions of and interactions with Charles F. Feeney and John R. Healy.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_d8b76dcbd08a85f2f47e37a3a9cca253" level="file"><did><unittitle>Monteiro, John</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Farber, Myron A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-06-21/2006-06-21">2006-06-21</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a0edc0bbb17992115303cb31864ebcdc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Personal background: childhood, family history, Portuguese community in Hong Kong, World War II; Duty Free Shoppers: early history, Hong Kong duty-free concession, business strategies and development, competition, impact of Japanese tourism, sale of DFS; personal interactions with Charles F. Feeney, Robert W. Miller, Anthony M. Pilaro, Alan M. Parker, Robert J. Bruso,  Adrian Bellamy, Robert J. Futoran.</p></scopecontent><processinfo id="aspace_0b023978b0237d6e8facb400cf64427d"><head>Processing Information</head><p>Archivist redacted transcript: pages 216, 220. pages 217-219 removed.</p></processinfo></c02><c02 id="aspace_feca10cfc9bc6b49bb09cc357ae41f26" level="file"><did><unittitle>Moore, Jack</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Farber, Myron A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-07-30/2006-07-31" type="inclusive">2006-07-30-2006-07-31</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5b0d10c840187ce72894d9bc278117a2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Born 1936 in Cologne, Germany; early life in 
England during World War II; education at British school in Germany 194-1953; clerking and early legal career as solicitor in London and lawyer for Price Waterhouse in Frankfurt; international tax services work in Europe and Singapore; independent tax services work; Charles F. Feeney [CFF] as client at Price Waterhouse; Duty Free Shoppers and issues with U.S. withholding tax on corporations and branches;  General Atlantic offices in Bermuda; establishment of the Atlantic Foundation and Atlantic Trust in early 1980s; CFF's concerns about anonymous giving; transferal of CFF funds to Atlantic Foundation and Danielle J. Feeney [DJF]; CFF and DJF divorce; interactions with CFF.</p></scopecontent><processinfo id="aspace_533772e88e4d8da7aab266138ba75f53"><head>Processing Information</head><p>Archivist redacted transcript: pages 121, 129; 123-128 removed.</p></processinfo></c02><c02 id="aspace_ab22c6aab39afb631cc3200d158e9ff0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Morrison, Bruce</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-02-26/2007-02-28" type="inclusive">2007-02-26-2007-02-28</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1936bbfca1d68fce88c7e9d1f3b98183"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Born October 8, 1944 in New York City and raised 
by adoptive parents; bachelors' in chemistry at Massachusetts Institute of Technology; dropped out of University of Illinois graduate school to attend Yale Law School; early career as public interest lawyer; grass roots organizing and advocacy; involvement with Irish activism; career as a congressman from Connecticut; Morrison Visas and immigration reform; William Jefferson Clinton's presidential 1992 campaign and presidency; Charles F. Feeney [CFF] interest in Irish education and freedom struggle; CFF relationship and negotiations with Gerry Adams; communications and peace-process work in Northern Ireland; mid-1990s Ireland cease-fire and negotiations; CFF personal funding of Sinn Fein; interactions with CFF.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_e069480e9b46644ff3cf51868cb1a372" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mortell, Michael</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2005-12-19/2005-12-20" type="inclusive">2005-12-19-2005-12-20</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_53b8567a11106a9baacaa1d5cb6be0e9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview:  </p><p>...Charles F. Feeney's philanthropy in Ireland and impact on higher education; Atlantic Philanthropies' contributions to UCC; reflections on AP's administration and anonymity policy; campus expansion projects; establishment and function of CHIU; negotiations and passage of Universities Act of 1997; reflections on the appointment of his successor'; impressions of Charles Feeney and other Atlantic Philanthropies staff members</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_9d7a58c2094c3c71222d9284910994d8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mutch, Frank</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Grele, Ronald J.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2005-10-18/2006-05-15" type="inclusive">2005-10-18-2006-05-15</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_14e903c908258c1c5c62100e1472f440"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: </p><p>Educated in law in England; moved to Bermuda
 in 1962; Charles F. Feeney [CFF] and his experiences in Bermuda; Atlantic Foundation [AF] and the challenges of anonymous giving; AF and the grant-making process; issues around maintaining AF as a Bermudan company; activities of the AF Board of Directors; CFF involvement in Irish peace process and funding of higher education; CFF and funding for programs in Vietnam and Australia; CFF and spend-down decision; AF philanthropic activity in Bermuda; legacy of Atlantic Philanthropies [AP]; AP and encouraging philanthropy and giving while living; change and development of program areas.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 audience="internal" id="aspace_639110436b168dcf44b2d17723d7166e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Nordeman, Jacques</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-04-06/2006-04-28" type="inclusive">2006-04-06-2006-04-28</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7828c5afabe88a7ac6c760e45de15df1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Personal background: childhood in New York City, family history, education, military service, career in recruiting/staffing industry; Duty Free Shoppers: history, airport concessions, regional operations, personnel, management, LVMH buyout; Atlantic Philanthropies: General Atlantic Corporation, management, personnel, board members, grant-making decisions, mission, anonymity, higher education in Ireland; Interactions: Charles F. Feeney, George M. Parker, Harvey P. Dale, Jean Karoubi, Edwin C. Cohen, Robert W. Miller, Anthony M. Pilaro, Alan M. Parker, Joel L. Fleishman, Raymond L. Handlan, John R. Healy.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_25082716965312fb32a5495ff390fc59" level="file"><did><unittitle>O'Clery, Conor</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Clark, Mary Marshall</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-10-26/2007-10-26">2007-10-26</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8989a0806eef59bddd91c48130afdcc7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: </p><p>Duty Free Shoppers, history of General Atlantic, philanthropy philosophy, no detail about his private life, traveling with person whom with the biography concerns, interview process, experience in Korean War, uncomfortable with wealthy, Cornell University donation, the rebuilding of the universities if Ireland, contentions of the Atlantic Philanthropy board, involvement with Sinn Fein, opinions on American foreign policy, death of parents, giving while alive, Cuban affairs, general impressions of Cuban people,  health organization, funding of documentary on Cuban health organization, Duty Free Shoppers, eventual downsizing,</p></scopecontent><processinfo id="aspace_c1de76f47a0346e4c40abeddd2d04a62"><head>Processing Information</head><p>Archivist redacted transcript: pages 12-13, 35, 48, 49, 66; 33-34, 62-65 removed</p></processinfo></c02><c02 id="aspace_51c4a497b10b759bdc5cf1329728a57a" level="file"><did><unittitle>O'Connell, Brian</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-04-14/2007-04-14">2007-04-14</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7277116b1a93f4e501e6c9170958dc53"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: 
Personal background: childhood in Worcester, M.A., family history, U.S. Depression '20s, World War II, early education, higher education Tufts University, military service, U.S politics '50s-'70s, Independent Sector; Atlantic Philanthropies: early history, mission, spend-down, grantees: Bridgestar, Independent Sector, Bridgespan; Interactions: Raymond L. Handlan, Charles F. Feeney, Virginia A. Hodgkinson, John R. Healy, John W. Gardner, James Joseph, Thomas J. Tierney, Joel L. Fleishman.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_aa173009ede5e06204df641f306b5e0a" level="file"><did><unittitle>O'Donnell-Tormey, Jill</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-02-14/2006-02-14">2006-02-14</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7d89bda423c3ba2a439ddf967f462b45"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Post-doctoral fellowship at Rockefeller University, awarded fellowship with Cancer Research Institute [CRI]; became instructor in Department of Medicine at Cornell University Medical College; had two children, unsure of future career direction; accepted job at CRI as Director of Public Information, 1987; 1988Atlantic Philanthropies [AP] for AIDS research; CRI and issue of AP's anonymous giving;  AP's involvement in grantees' work; George M. Parker and relationship to CRI; impressions of Charles F. Feeney; development of pre-doctoral and clinical cancer immunology programs; 1997, 20 million dollar grant award; change in AP funding priorities; relationship to AP Australian grantees; Couran Cove; insight into AP grant making process.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ccd0c2eb677eb92872895ef1d263642e" level="file"><did><unittitle>O'Dowd, Niall</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-02-15/2007-02-15">2007-02-15</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b1f938075222d66d2432c3573d516390"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Irish childhood: family background, education, 
political and religious climate; emigration to America: recollections, social climate, Irish-American community, activism; publishing: The Irishman; Irish America, The Irish Voice; interactions with Charles F. Feeney: illegal Irish immigration in America, philanthropy, Irish peace process; interactions with Gerry Adams, Martin McGuinness, John R. Healy, Paul Slawson, Danielle J. Feeney</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_6c061ee81dd389eeb5da75e8e0d4b465" level="file"><did><unittitle>O'Hare, Danny</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2005-10-12/2005-12-12" type="inclusive">2005-10-12-2005-12-12</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0b417242eb680ea16fbb01db92790de7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: </p><p>...; establishment of Dublin City University Educational Trust; reflections on university fundraising and the role of government and private industry in financing higher education in Ireland; comparisons to and influence of the U.S. model of higher education on Irish higher education; reflections on the Atlantic Philanthropies' [AP] administration, its anonymity policy, and AP's contributions to NIHE Dublin and to Irish higher education; bricks and mortar projects, funding for campus expansion; creation and funding of the Irish Center for Talented Youth; university strategic planning efforts; creation of the Program for Research in Third Level Institutes; relationship with Charles F. Feeney and John R. Healy.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_a19706f34c8902cfe6e4ea4734f421b1" level="file"><did><unittitle>O'Hare, Rita</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-03-29/2007-03-29">2007-03-29</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cddf3683a92aca8137cb66a16d41f250"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Personal background: Belfast childhood, family history, education; Ireland: labor unions, religion, sectarian violence, socio-politics of 20th century, ; Sinn Fein: development in 1970s-1980s, leadership, involvement with Irish America, Irish Republican Army, publications, diplomatic relations, Irish peace process, U.S. visa issue, Sinn Fein's Washington office; Interactions: Charles F. Feeney, Gerard Adams, Jr., Jean A. Kennedy Smith, Niall O'Dowd.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_3d0a4394df75981e33561d4cd42cb3d1" level="file"><did><unittitle>O'Huiginn, Sean</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-04-12/2007-04-12">2007-04-12</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_324262e6dd89b151df4230287c700746"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Personal background: rural Irish childhood, farming in Ireland, education, Irish foreign service; Ireland: history, religion, politics, socio-politics from 1970s-1990s, Irish peace process, Irish Republican Army, Charles J. Haughey, Albert Reynolds, Gerard Adams, Jr., British government; Interactions with Charles F. Feeney, Niall O'Dowd, William J. Flynn, Rita O'Hare.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_4050ca8ff0926bdb72450f18981f0308" level="file"><did><unittitle>Oechsli, Chris</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Grele, Ronald J.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2005-10-11/2006-02-07" type="inclusive">2005-10-11-2006-02-07</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_668eddeb3798d595d1f27c039dbf64bf"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Personal background: childhood in Costa Rica, family history, law school at the University of Virginia, teaching law in China, U.S. politics '50s-'80s, China politics '70s-80's, Tiananmen Square protests 1989; Atlantic Philanthropies: General Atlantic Group Limited, General Atlantic Partners, early history, personnel, anonymity, tax structure, investments, grantees, mission, areas of focus; Duty Free Shoppers: business decline late '80s-early '90s, share-holders, LVMH buy-out; Interactions: Michael Gwinnell, Harvey P. Dale, Charles F. Feeney, Paul B. Hannon, George M. Parker, Paul S. Slawson.</p></scopecontent><accessrestrict audience="internal" id="aspace_a84614579b38839a555785c403b3e523"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Access restricted until 2030.</p></accessrestrict></c02><c02 id="aspace_e0eb773ea6b7f18f8b617d2665b81339" level="file"><did><unittitle>Old, Lloyd</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-05-16/2006-05-16">2006-05-16</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fcf3c56f5946ae54623815c33d7a29cc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: 
Personal background: family history, childhood,
 education, career in bio-medical research; Atlantic Philanthropies: relationship with Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center, bio-medical research grants, higher education in Australia, higher education in Vietnam, mission; Interactions: Charles F. Feeney, Jill O'Donnell-Tormey, George M. Parker, Jacques C. Nordeman, John R. Healy, Raymond L. Handlan.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_8000ae0321e21271d3afe36560ca7c3f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Parker, Alan</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Farber, Myron A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-12-07/2006-12-09" type="inclusive">2006-12-07-2006-12-09</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1f909c2d14243af9850b1de579e9ea9d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: 
Personal history: family history, childhood in
 Zimbabwe, Zimbabwe race relations 50s-60s, Zimbabwe politics 50s-60s, early career as accountant, relocation to United Kingdom 60s, Duty Free Shoppers: early history, Cars International, early operations in Europe, New York, Asia, business troubles 1960s, airport concessions, product line, business strategies, business management, personnel, sale of DFS, relationship between DFS owners, business relationship with Camus, impact of Japanese tourism, business downturn 90s; Interactions: Charles F. Feeney, Robert W. Miller, Anthony M. Pilaro, Desmond Byrne, Joseph P. Lyons, John Monteiro, Jean E. Gentzbourger.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_6b818b568b94d3132dc3b053df8fb230" level="file"><did><unittitle>Payton, Bob</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-09-05/2007-09-06" type="inclusive">2007-09-05-2007-09-06</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c5be3d0ec2520be59d4d6fff7ea4c9ca"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Personal background: Midwestern childhood, family history, early education, World War II military experience in Pacific; career: newspaper editor, real estate publishing, institutional development and advancement, foreign service; Center for Philanthropy: mission, early history, funding, publications, internal politics, philanthropic trends; Atlantic Philanthropy: anonymity, spend-down, mission, personnel; Interactions: Charles F. Feeney, Eugene R. Tempel, Warren Ilchman, Raymond L. Handlan, Joel L. Fleishman.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_f8f2afad892fc27542653fe7375dec57" level="file"><did><unittitle>Pendry, Christine</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Farber, Myron A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-11-04/2006-12-02" type="inclusive">2006-11-04-2006-12-02</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_900335efbbdcfedf3322a127e54a5a12"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Born in Cincinnati, Ohio; education and early 
career as a lawyer; 1990 hired as Atlantic Philanthropic Service Company [APS] chief of staff; APS and issues presented by anonymous giving; process and negotiations for sale of Duty Free Shoppers [DFS] to Moët Hennessy Louis Vuitton in 1996; creation of coping plans for the possibility that sale of DFS would reveal philanthropy; Charles F. Feeney [CFF] and Northern Ireland peace process; selection of grantees for disclosure and public association with Atlantic Philanthropies; measuring and evaluating success and impact of a foundation; interactions with Harvey P. Dale.</p></scopecontent><processinfo id="aspace_2043502b9bd6aca7d3bb8f27381a1620"><head>Processing Information</head><p>Archivist redacted transcript: pages 19, 28-29; 15-17, 29 removed</p></processinfo></c02><c02 id="aspace_4c12f6f5b04f516511547487e1618cfb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Phuong, Le Nhan</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-10-05/2007-10-08" type="inclusive">2007-10-05-2007-10-08</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_37c5fdee85b88bb2cffef514213f9d57"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Born 1965 in Viet Nam, family history: father's early death, mother's work for Vietnamese and U.S. governments; childhood memories of orphanage and evacuation from Viet Nam; reunion with family; founding of family restaurant; volunteer work in Philippines refugee camp; education at Georgia Tech, University of Cincinnati and Johns Hopkins; return to Viet Nam as medical doctor; work with Ha Noi School of Public Health; consultant for Atlantic Philanthropies; Atlantic Philanthropies investments in higher education and public health in Viet Nam; organizing Atlantic Philanthropies office in Viet Nam; primary health care in Vietnam;</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_1116d373ea3c7a42408d29de79a102c2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Pilaro, Tony</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Farber, Myron A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-03-20/2006-03-24" type="inclusive">2006-03-20-2006-03-24</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_70a297f714f7dd1a14ae0fd8a0a30bb0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Personal background: family history, childhood; 
education: BA in economics, University of Virginia, 1957; JD, University of Virginia School of Law, 1960; career: Wall Street, Butler's Bank, Bahamas; Duty Free Shoppers: history, tax structure, business practices, financial problems in 1965, airport concession bids, impact of Japanese tourism, products business expansion 1970s-1980s, economic downturn in 1990s; LVMH buyout; philanthropy; Interactions: Charles F. Feeney, Robert W. Miller, George M. Parker, Alan M. Parker, Harvey P. Dale, Myron E. Ullman; philanthropic endeavors: education and youth development initiatives, CAP Foundation, Ron Brown Scholar Program.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_b6a3aa383da21eb3e8c0377b5053d362" level="file"><did><unittitle>Powell, Lawrie</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-07-12/2006-07-12">2006-07-12</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9098bfc580070a824132aa66ad4f7953"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Personal background: childhood in Brisbane, educated at Queensland University Medical School; Career: medical researcher,  medical lecturer, Royal Brisbane Hospital, Massachusetts General Hospital, Queensland Institute of Medical Research; Research areas: haemochromatosis, liver disease, cancer, public health and epidemiology; Interactions: Dame Sheila Sherlock, Kurt J. Isselbacher, Niels Tygstrup, Charles F. Feeney, Colin McCrea; Atlantic Philanthropies: areas of focus, medical research in Australia, personnel, relationship with grantees.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_890c2ee84cfb872da4a08dafaa9c9b79" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ramphele, Mamphela</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-09-19/2007-09-19">2007-09-19</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6eebbfb7c3b935fa4f18ee4dadd67dbe"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Role of international philanthropic funding in 
South Africa; state of philanthropy in South Africa; development processes in South Africa;: role in Independent Development Trust project; field stories of work in medicine and development in South Africa; time as deputy vice chancellor at University of Cape Town; political education from Apartheid; support for black academics; race, gender, and discrimination at UCT; developments at UCT and support from Atlantic Philanthropies on projects; post-UCT work: trustee of Rockefeller Foundation, experiences at World Bank.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 audience="internal" id="aspace_87fdbc9585493e06d7a66f557cc48b03" level="file"><did><unittitle>Rawlings, Hunter</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-04-04/2006-04-14" type="inclusive">2006-04-04-2006-04-14</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5acffe5040592e1b9a961923aed1e740"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: 
Personal background: family history, childhood, education; Cornell University: presidency, fundraising, alumni, administration, development and advancement, medical school and bio-medical research; Atlantic Philanthropies: anonymity, Presidential Research Scholars Program; Interactions: Frank H. T. Rhodes, Charles F. Feeney, Harvey P. Dale, W. Keith Kennedy.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 audience="internal" id="aspace_6ff92632f791d6d4093709ef422b335e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reynolds, Albert</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-01-29/2007-01-29">2007-01-29</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_917aa0db5d228b827bc53653d1212306"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Born November 3, 1932 in Rooskey, Ireland; early entrepreneurship and establishing C &amp; D Pet Foods; 1979 became Minister for Post, Telegraphs, and Transport in Ireland; 1992 became Prime Minister; involvement in peace process in Ireland; Charles F. Feeney [CFF] funding of Ireland peace process and Sin Fein office in Washington, DC; CFF philanthropy for higher education in Ireland; Gerry Adams US visa struggle.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_7da077881f6881fbd2eb6e1586b6b351" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reynolds, Stephen</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Rowland, Steven S.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-01-08/2007-01-08">2007-01-08</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5dc01d8cbe3003a745f737471cf15122"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Personal background: family history, education, accounting career; General Atlantic Corporation: investments; Interactions: Charles F. Feeney, Steven A. Denning, W. Theodore Kresge, Jr., Edwin C. Cohen, George M. Parker.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_84b329248f0e92b03da77d74d5bb56de" level="file"><did><unittitle>Rhodes, Frank</unittitle><unitdate normal="2006-01-15/2006-05-23" type="inclusive">2006-01-15-2006-05-23</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_61b01eabb1350b766d663880ccc1ebf2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: 
Duty Free Shoppers: Louis Vuitton Moet Henessey buyout; Atlantic Philanthropies: Advisory Board, grant-making decisions, mission, anonymity, philanthropic focus, impact of contributions, higher education in Ireland, higher education in Africa, higher education in Vietnam, response to 9/11, contributions to Cornell University,  Interactions: Charles F. Feeney, Elizabeth J. McCormack, Frederick Schwarz, Michael I. Sovern, Harvey P. Dale, Joel L. Fleishman, Robert A. Beck, Christine V. Downton.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 audience="internal" id="aspace_3e924c08db58d5cf3ecb6fdf6c4758e7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Richards, Cynthia</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Grele, Ronald J.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-10-23/2006-10-23">2006-10-23</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2c927aafd9f2f91217235820d15f310d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: </p><p>Background: born St. Louis, MO, childhood Richmond, VA, reminiscences of southern segregation; education: B.A. Barnard College, J.D. University of Virginia; career: attorney for Cadwalader Wichersham and Taft, attorney for the Atlantic Philantropies; family struggles with cancer; legal difficulties of maintaining anonymous status; description of Charles F. Feeney; discussion of Harvey P. Dale [HPD] management style; departure of HPD.</p></scopecontent><processinfo id="aspace_606344be6703952d541adfd629e1191c"><head>Processing Information</head><p>Archivist redacted transcript: pages 6-7, 37; pages 38-40 removed.</p></processinfo></c02><c02 id="aspace_8c2ed0380173e6382d3c351868b10101" level="file"><did><unittitle>Rolles, Chuck</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-08-21/2006-08-22" type="inclusive">2006-08-21-2006-08-22</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7ca58b2f1b9d7a289a0fc1f5cf5bf107"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Childhood in Binghamton, New York; B.S. in Hotel Administration, Cornell University School of Hotel Administration, 1956; college friendship with Charles F. Feeney [CFF]; CFF's early entrepreneurial efforts and Duty Free Shoppers; CFF's approach to philanthropy; participation and effect of Board of Advisors at Atlantic Foundation; CFF and donations to Cornell; CFF's financial support for development of Cornell Tradition student aid program; interactions with CFF and his family.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_7da4c82b67d21817ed85976c9be84b56" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ruby, Alan</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-08-03/2007-03-16" type="inclusive">2006-08-03-2007-03-16</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2299eeff0fc31abf6d321c10e1e921d0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Born November 28, 1950 in New South Wales in Australia; early education at agricultural schools and working on farms; education at University of London in English and history; early career in education policy and World Bank in Australia; recruitment by Atlantic Philanthropies [AP] in 2000; AP reaction to September 11, 2001; AP changes in areas of funding and closing out ongoing grants; gender dynamics at AP; interactions with and general impressions of Charles F. Feeney.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 audience="internal" id="aspace_7a92ecf2208498f6c5469ff431c9abb0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Scannell, Jim</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-04-13/2006-04-13">2006-04-13</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6448f65adffa9a46e69a91e108e5c4d6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Born Boston; Assistant &amp; Director of Admissions at Boston College 1971-1980, Dean of Admissions and Financial Aid at Cornell University 1980-1984 , Vice President for Enrollments, Placement, Alumni Relations, and Development at University of Rochester; financial aid and work study programs at universities and colleges; Cornell Tradition financial aid and Charles F. Feeney's [CFF] anonymous giving; complications and mysteries of receiving funds from an unknown donor; interactions with colleagues at Atlantic Philanthropic Service Corporation.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_f74a92e0c20f4fc64858e86f23836614" level="file"><did><unittitle>Schwarz, Fritz</unittitle><unitdate normal="2005-12-02/2007-03-27" type="inclusive">2005-12-02-2007-03-27</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9dab8503662e55a58c920cba8f858990"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Born April 20, 1935 in New York City; education at Collegiate School in New York, Milton Academy near Boston, Harvard University and Harvard Law School; career as lawyer at Cravath Swaine &amp; Moore; Charles F. Feeney [CFF] and his relationship to his money; arbitration between Duty Free Shoppers [DFS] partners during sale in mid-1990s; issues around anonymity of Atlantic Philanthropies [AP]; power transitions at AP 2000-2003; CFF plans to limit money received by his children; shift in AP's areas of focus.</p></scopecontent><processinfo id="aspace_f5bbbdab96f380faa4756a3777c2c222"><head>Processing Information</head><p>Archivist redacted transcript: pages 8, 187, 196, 220. pages 197-198 removed.</p></processinfo></c02><c02 id="aspace_15fd558ee2e38c4d3dc9c4d63cd55bba" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sizer, Ted</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-08-15/2007-08-16" type="inclusive">2007-08-15-2007-08-16</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_563e5f1ebc2a640da523b6c315bc0d16"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Born 1932; family background, education at the Foot School, Pomfret, Yale and Harvard; military experience; teaching career: Dean of Harvard's Graduate School of Education, Headmaster of Phillips Academy, Brown University professor; Atlantic Philanthropies funding of Re Learning Project; publication of Horace's Compromise; founding of Coalition for Essential Schools; philosophy of education; views on education policy; work at the Annenberg Institute for School Reform.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_740092ca045681f15601ddbe4672cfbe" level="file"><did><unittitle>Smith, David</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Farber, Myron A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-01-01/2006-05-31" type="inclusive">2006-01-01-2006-05-31</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cf8c35ae2d2e00d6485072f43befca16"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: ...General Atlantic Partners and InterPacific; InterPacific-run resorts: Guam, Saipan, Phuket, Bali, Couran Cove, Tahiti; upper Fifth Avenue low income housing real estate; InterPacific business investments; Hawaii Retail Group stores and shopping center; San Francisco real estate holdings and Western Athletic Clubs; Atlantic Philanthropies and anonymous giving; interactions with colleagues at InterPacific and General Atlantic Group Limited; interactions with Charles F. Feeney.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_f554fb509293deb8f755c13b9b9bd4d9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Smitham, Peter</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Grele, Ronald J.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-07-21/2007-09-07" type="inclusive">2007-07-21-2007-09-07</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_26a2897efc42ac8112cd3e0aa54926ee"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Personal background: family history, childhood in Swansea, UK, family politics, family religious beliefs, early education, university experience, early career in business management, recruitment and employment by Atlantic Philanthropies; United Kingdom economy 1950s-1980s; Atlantic Philanthropies: programs in Africa, areas of interest, mission, spend-down, personnel, grant-making decisions, board members, personnel issues; Interactions: Harvey P. Dale, Charles F. Feeney, John R. Healy, Sara Lawrence Lightfoot, Elizabeth J. MrCormack, Frederick A. O. "Fritz" Schwarz, Jr., Frank H. T. Rhodes, Christine V. Downton.</p></scopecontent><processinfo id="aspace_b149b06dbf0adc40cb9174350406b2df"><head>Processing Information</head><p>Archivist redacted transcript: pages 120-121, page 122 removed</p></processinfo></c02><c02 id="aspace_bb5943be0729f4f33a83a165282b5710" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sovern, Michael</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Grele, Ronald J.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-04-04/2006-04-05" type="inclusive">2006-04-04-2006-04-05</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_58882a1b51b74104f9118a8e6420c18c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Born 1931 and raised in the Bronx; Atlantic Philanthropies Board of Directors 1995-present; differentiations between Atlantic Philanthropies [AP], Atlantic Trust and the Atlantic Foundation; AP leadership issues; AP and concerns about anonymity; AP grantmaking and grant recipients; AP areas of funding and effectiveness; Charles F. Feeney and Foundation Chairman's Grants; AP spend-down strategy and challenges.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_7e32162c8f192b30ca289e13b69345a9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Spencer, Jim</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-09-26/2006-09-27" type="inclusive">2006-09-26-2006-09-27</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_515897ebe3e59e2953f9538d4b8a5015"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Born and raised in Ithaca, New York; Cornell University [CU]: education in civil engineering, professor, Associate Dean of College of Agriculture; 1989 became program officer at Atlantic Philanthropies Service Company [APS]: higher education, aging; staff  meetings at APS; relationship between CU and APS; program officers: benefits of specialists versus generalists; challenges of APS spend-down; evaluating success of grants and projects; relationship to APS staff and operations in Ireland; APS funding for Stanford University projects; interactions with Raymond L. Handlan.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_47f0d853f9d361155df3aee9beec8c9b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Staunton, Ciaran</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-08-21/2007-08-28" type="inclusive">2007-08-21-2007-08-28</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_acc1cd5aa22573512abaf46eaf5c495c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: ...Irish peace process: Connolly House group, William J. Clinton administration involvement, ceasefire negotiations, Gerard Adams, Jr. visa, Sinn Fein Office in Washington, British government reaction; interactions: Gerard Adams, Jr., William J. Flynn, Charles F. Feeney, Niall O'Dowd, Edward M. "Ted" Kennedy, Nancy Soderberg</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 audience="internal" id="aspace_241d549bc57bd86520cce8a40a1f9a9b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sterling, Leon P</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Rowland, Steven S.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-05-03/2006-05-04" type="inclusive">2006-05-03-2006-05-04</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_35e4616f05c2565d04a16584122c85d3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Born 1936 in Brussels, Belgium; fled Germans to Figuera da Foz, Portugal and then to United States; last name morphed from Serebriany to Sterling; childhood in Great Neck, Long Island; meeting Charles F. Feeney [CFF] at Cornell University; military service in Europe in late 1950s; working for Tourists International in Europe 1960-1966; concept behind duty free shopping: alcohol and cars; Duty Free Shoppers in Hong Kong and Honolulu airports; career as real estate lawyer; CFF as philanthropist; interactions with CFF.</p></scopecontent><processinfo id="aspace_982d0576d273c71fa825dee3ca43e576"><head>Processing Information</head><p>Archivist redacted transcript: page 179</p></processinfo></c02><c02 id="aspace_c6ea00c40a307ff2e3de608548be16fd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Stern, Ernie</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Rowland, Steven S.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2005-09-20/2005-09-27" type="inclusive">2005-09-20-2005-09-27</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_236c5390d2e3f25631778e1db6645fcb"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: ...; involvement with Cornell University affairs: Class of '56 fundraiser; class representative, 1957-1981; Class of '56 president, 1981-present; spearheading role in changing philosophy on fundraising and alumni contribution to Cornell University; upswing in alumni contribution from 1981 onward; Charles F. Feeney's [CFF] and Atlantic Philanthropies' [AP] contributions to Cornell University; CFF's relationship to philanthropy.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_e11ccb4c1464678c2674844fecd00f78" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sternlieb, David</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Grele, Ronald J.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-08-14/2007-09-04" type="inclusive">2007-08-14-2007-09-04</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f5bd0d5922c323ba3cab49baeb651a22"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Personal background: childhood and early life, family background, education, early career; Atlantic Philanthropies: early history, organizational structure, tax structure, funding and investments, personnel, personnel conflicts, spend-down, mission, program areas, foundation troubles, change of leadership, Board of Directors, grantees; interactions: Charles F. Feeney, Harvey P. Dale, John R. Healy, Colin McCrea, Alan R. Ruby, Frederick A. O. "Fritz" Schwarz, Jr., Margaret V. Hill.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_6f1aff82d8041bb7e7ff5e486865f144" level="file"><did><unittitle>Suchet, Bonnie</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Farber, Myron A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-03-06/2006-03-09" type="inclusive">2006-03-06-2006-03-09</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cccf40ee302e7dbd4cfa9edaf32458a5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Born in Staten Island, New York; reminiscences of childhood in Baltimore, Maryland, Birmingham, Alabama and Haddonfield, New Jersey; bachelor's degree, Cornell University, 1963; graduate degree, University of London; personal assistant to Charles F. Feeney [CFF], 1986;  CFF's involvement with Luigi Votano, Ferragamo and N. Peal;  CFF's relationship to Robert W. Miller; CFF's office on Savile Row, London; Castletroy Park and CFF's involvement in Ireland;  issues surrounding anonymity; sale of Duty Free Shoppers to Moet Hennessy Louis Vuitton; reminiscences of CFF.</p></scopecontent><processinfo id="aspace_4b48c33ce7e1346877fcff5588d6b86f"><head>Processing Information</head><p>Archivist redacted transcript: pages 104, 112, 147, 151 ; pages 105-11, 148-150 removed</p></processinfo></c02><c02 id="aspace_e3f982cdf4ccb6a8e6c6e35c0852ff06" level="file"><did><unittitle>Tempel, Gene</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-09-05/2007-09-06" type="inclusive">2007-09-05-2007-09-06</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bc9a9f70fed3d30fa09268ac3ecd7d96"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Childhood and early life in rural Indiana; family background; educational experience; early career in higher education administration; Center on Philanthropy: history, founding staff members, mission, funding, research, current issues, philanthropic trends in the U.S.; Atlantic Philanthropies: board of directors, interaction with grantees, mission, focus areas, spend-down, personnel and leadership; interactions: Raymond L. Handlan, Joel L. Fleishman, Robert L. Payton, Gara LaMarche, Harvey P. Dale.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_1536b0b5bb75783555b0cde82c9d40ad" level="file"><did><unittitle>Terzano, John</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-11-27/2007-11-28" type="inclusive">2007-11-27-2007-11-28</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_944d9689b5388260ab2211b0dff3107a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: ...advocacy of Vietnam veterans rights, efforts to change legislation, first trip of Vietnam veterans to Vietnam, 1981, reconciliation efforts between US Vietnam veterans and Vietnam, landmine ban campaign; the Justice Project: its creation, role in the death penalty abolition movement, fundraising efforts and philanthropic support, Atlantic Philanthropies' financial contribution; reflection on political aspects of philanthropic organizations' involvement in the death penalty abolition movement; philosophy on non-profit organizations' method and responsibility to effect policy change.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_d9a0e10e57ba51362e6f6e06fbd954a2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Thornhill, Don</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-11-02/2006-11-02">2006-11-02</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8ee04dcaa3df4a381cbb3cd13bd4cfb5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Born 1947 in Cork City, Ireland; PhD in 
chemistry from University College Dublin; career in the Irish Civil Service: public policy, taxation and education; struggle for funding at Irish universities; Atlantic Philanthropies [AP] matching funds for Irish higher education research facilities; struggles as chair of Higher Education Authority; creation of Program for Research in Third Level Institutes; AP and concerns about anonymity; interactions with AP board members; interactions with Charles F. Feeney.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_077653cc579397d8f9455fdb447c9d30" level="file"><did><unittitle>Trang, Huynh Thi</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-10-10/2007-10-11" type="inclusive">2007-10-10-2007-10-11</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7de5334011aa20407d68ddb3796ce811"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Childhood in the countryside of Viet Nam; family history; education and study of English language; career as teacher, training as librarian at Simmons College, marriage and family life, construction of Learning Resource Center with Atlantic Philanthropies funding; Sustainability Project; development of curriculum.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_3ee34c4e9422b4ec920d1315a9c6de5c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ullman, Myron</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Farber, Myron A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-02-06/2007-02-07" type="inclusive">2007-02-06-2007-02-07</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a3cfb9c5381335c9beca28e4ca16c7aa"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Personal background: childhood in Ohio, family history, education, military service, early career in retail industry; Duty Free Shoppers: LVMH buyout, personnel, management, regional operations, business strategies and development, airport concessions, DFS business decline, products, employee compensation, Camus Overseas Limited; Moet-Hennessy Louis Vuitton: DFS business decline; Interactions: Adrian Bellamy, Bernard Arnault, Peter Wu, Robert W. Miller, Charles F. Feeney, Anthony M. Pilaro, Alan M. Parker.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 audience="internal" id="aspace_70dc5fc82e7c90742babbaaaba3ce97d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Vogel, Larry</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Grele, Ronald J.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-04-25/2006-04-25">2006-04-25</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e3b463bfdcfb4603f94e94cdc4e65eca"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Personal background: childhood in NY, family history, education, career as tax lawyer (Cadwalader, Wickersham &amp; Taft); Duty Free Shoppers: history – Cars International, 1960s financial problems, Butler's Bank loan, tax structure, business strategy and development, airport concessions, business competitors, personnel, management, employee compensation; Interactions: Anthony M. Pilaro, Charles F. Feeney, Harvey P. Dale, Robert W. Miller, John Monteiro.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_6553592ab97c0f56301052412635101c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Votano, Luigi</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Farber, Myron A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2007-09-27/2007-09-28" type="inclusive">2007-09-27-2007-09-28</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8113a0e703a6e10071eb24ee574e7d2b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: reflections on GAGL's corporate culture and change in its dynamic with subsequent leadership changes; negotiations with Salvatore Ferragamo Italia S.p.A and other fashion houses; career at Ferragamo: managing director, Salavatore Ferragamo Hawaii, 1997-2001; general manager, Salvatore Ferragamo, Bal Harbour, 2005-present; reminiscences of Charles F. Feeney.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_2057aa5d7580d811dd1aa951459604ed" level="file"><did><unittitle>Walsh, Ed</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2005-10-19/2005-12-15" type="inclusive">2005-10-19-2005-12-15</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_feb6cc61be7ae061c9e65596414ba2ed"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: ...relationship between University of Limerick and Cornell University via Charles F. Feeney [CFF]; CFF and funding for Irish peace process; CFF and anonymous giving; CFF investment in Castletroy Park Hotel; CFF and development of Irish tourism; challenges of fundraising for higher education projects in Ireland; founding University of Limerick Foundation; 1997 outing of CFF and reactions; interactions with Lewis L. Glucksman; interactions with John R. Healy; interactions with CFF.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_6853849c1e77d488e6968b95dec116ae" level="file"><did><unittitle>Wesselkamper, Sue</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Grele, Ronald J.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-04-24/2006-04-25" type="inclusive">2006-04-24-2006-04-25</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_062ce749300e32ded51c173d0ebbbe1c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Personal background: childhood, family history, religion, education; U. S. women in the 1960s: education, career choices; career: of social work, education, higher education administration; Chaminade University: administration, presidency, finances, fund raising, endowments; enrollment management; student services; Atlantic Philanthropies: Chaminade University grants, grant matching, grant-making decisions, anonymity; higher education in Vietnam; interactions with Charles F. Feeney, Harvey P. Dale, Elizabeth J. McCormack, Raymond L. Handlan.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_5f9b00504c7dc950294514157885359b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Windsor, Michael</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Grele, Ronald J.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-04-26/2007-12-13" type="inclusive">2006-04-26-2007-12-13</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8f29e7a0ea9b4dcf76e4f46b1482a9ce"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Born 1935 near Lancashire, England; early career as an accountant in England and Hong Kong; accounts of Tourists International and Duty Free Shoppers [DFS]; controller for DFS in Hong Kong [1969] and Hawaii [1970]; DFS ten year concession deal in Hawaii; shutting down Hawaii Retail Group and McInerny Limited; interactions between four DFS partners; CFF and philanthropy at Chaminade University in Honolulu; Internal Revenue Service audit of DFS in Hawaii; investment in Actinium Pharmaceuticals cancer drug; interactions with DFS colleagues; interactions with CFF since 1969.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 audience="internal" id="aspace_3118ae84aa8003bccab29de8493ef9c1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Wunderlich, Gerold</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Rowland, Steven S.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-05-31/2006-05-31">2006-05-31</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c196e552c61f5fdf9920b5e278343581"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Family background; childhood remembrances; B.A., Dartmouth College, 1959; work experiences: general manager/COO, Duty Free Shoppers, Hong Kong, 1968-1972, Hawaii, 1972-1974; recruitment to and experiences working for DFS; DFS business practices and strategies; impact of Japanese tourism; DFS' buyout by Moët Hennessy Louis Vuitton; hotel development ventures in Guam; origins of and development activities of InterPacific in the Far East Asia, including the Pacific Island Clubs and Western Athletic Clubs; impressions of Charles F. Feeney, his work ethic and philanthropic philosophy</p></scopecontent><processinfo id="aspace_c694c9b5575116727bea59b0060a9eab"><head>Processing Information</head><p>Archivist redacted transcript: pages 27, 141, 160</p></processinfo></c02><c02 audience="internal" id="aspace_2da109ccf9d53ba9487ef06dd0003a6e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Xung, Phan Quang</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2006-06-23/2006-06-23">2006-06-23</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_147f729a4cbaadf3c0386d676cc27fe4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Born in Dien Ban, Vietnam; high school education in China; 1969 bachelors' in science and technology in Moscow, Russia; 1983 PhD in East Germany; employment at Da Nang Institute of Technology: 1990-1996 dean of faculty, 1996-1999 vice president, 1999-2005 president, 2005 director of Continuing Education Center; issues with higher education in Vietnam; Atlantic Philanthropies [AP] funding for Da Nang Institute of Technology projects: dormitory, library, physical education center, language study center; AP concerns about anonymity; Vietnamese bureaucracy and problems with acceptance of donations; Charles F. Feeney [CFF] interest in assisting Vietnam; AP changing interests and shifting away from funding higher education; interactions with CFF.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_bb7faee2102f82bc311338bc722bbae6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Zuill, Cummings</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Grele, Ronald J.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2005-10-18/2005-10-19" type="inclusive">2005-10-18-2005-10-19</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_39916dff2d0610b16066cda6c479a77d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Born 1939 in Bermuda; education in the United States and early career in banking; race issues and segregation in Bermuda; 1986 joined board of trustees at Atlantic Foundation [AF]; 1991 joined board of trustees for General Atlantic Group Limited [GAGL]; record-keeping and reasons for establishing GAGL and AF in Bermuda; sale of Duty Free Shoppers and channeling of funds into the Atlantic Trust; Charles F. Feeney and philanthropic gifts around the world; effects of Atlantic Philanthropies [AP] on Bermuda;  role of Board of Trustees in various AP projects; shifts and changes in focus of AP funding areas into: aging, childhood development, population and health; issues of AP's legacy; interactions with colleagues.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_a8804010476a5ccff7bd704f9c3bd4d0" level="series"><did><unittitle>Phase II</unittitle></did><accessrestrict id="aspace_7b45824c8d9ba0aa08f4d10230c091ca"><head>Conditions Governing Access</head><p>Phase II transcripts are restricted until 2025.</p></accessrestrict><c02 id="aspace_6cbab6d5f6ef7f7311ad9893451d6492" level="file"><did><unittitle>Benedict, Annmarie</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-10-23/2016-03-09" type="inclusive">2015-10-23-2016-03-09</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_da17eb722e394575e0cf7a8fe70c7683"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Benedict begins by outlining the state of AP's Reconciliation and Human Rights (R&amp;HR) program when she joined it in 2003, including its strong focus on criminal justice reform, especially the juvenile death penalty. She discusses AP's efforts to band with other major funders in death penalty advocacy to establish a nationwide campaign, the strategy involved in that campaign, AP's partners in advocacy (especially the Proteus Action League), the campaign's funding structure, and the internal critiques and tensions that eventually to be an obstacle to the campaign's success. Benedict discusses the impact of Gara LaMarche's tenure at AP on the work of the R&amp;HR group in the United States and how the death penalty work fit within AP's broader vision of criminal justice reform and social justice. She reflects on AP's efforts to build a racial justice portfolio; a discussion about the role of evaluation in advocacy work then shifts to the topic of the schisms within the activist community, and the problems and consequences for manageing a nationwide strategic campaign. Benedict then reflects on length about her experiences with the spending down, especially the impact of the spend-down on the 8th Amendment project, a response to the earlier 2025 campaign.Finally, she explains the new Civic Participation Action Fund (CPAF) and how it fits in the vision of the dissolution of the foundation.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_89235b28c9bb2ac52f7a722b0fdf4bfe" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bhargava, Deepak</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2014-10-06/2015-02-09" type="inclusive">2014-10-06-2015-02-09</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_efbe1cedfcc5b0503cef1f57eee0250f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Bhargava begins by discussing his childhood and early influences. He grew up in the Bronx in New York City. He grew up in a family of academic Indian immigrants. He discusses attending Harvard and becoming involved with campus activism about ROTC and South African apartheid. After being advised to pursue activism instead of academia, he joined ACORN in doing campaign research. He discusses race in American and movement culture. He discusses his move to the CCC and its place in movement organizing. He relflects on his relationship with Gara LaMarche. He discusses immigration reform. He talks about retreats organized by AP. He discusses the meaning of funding and the spend down.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_cceb77737b9b716bb4ea9b4232a825b2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Birkbeck, Gail</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Thurner, Lance</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-06-03/2015-06-03">2015-06-03</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_58253833fd6807e6980943172a2dbf44"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Birbeck reviews her life and educational history, including her path to her current career; when pursuing a PhD didn't pan out as she had hoped, she founded a consultancy business that aided NGOs and government agencies with research, filling a crucial niche within the health sector of Ireland. Birbeck then describes her transition to AP; when she arrived, SLAE was just getting on its feet, and much of the evaluation work had yet to be designed, let alone implemented. Birbeck discusses her experience, including challenges and drawbacks, over the course of this process. Birbeck describes the geographic distribution of SLAE work and the working relationships she developed through SLAE, particularly those pertaining to population health and human rights in South Africa. She describes how evaluation transitioned from designing the programs to documenting and improving them, and how receptivity to this varied among grantees in different fields. She gives a detailed overview of changes in the structure and focus of SLAE over time, and discusses the larger picture of evaluation and grantmaking as regards Atlantic's big bets and capacity building strategies.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ddbe454fec89863e873b3cd1b232d5d4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bowan, Kenneth</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Thurner, Lance</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2016-03-01/2016-03-01">2016-03-01</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_93ae567f7ffd912754ebaf28bb11c34d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Bowman begins by discussing AP's 2001 grant to the Institute of Health and Biomedical Innovation (IHBI), and how that grant enabled unprecedented interaction between IHBI and the larger public. Bowman talks about his unique working relationship with Chuck Feeney, and how IHBI's research goals shifted to incorporate Feeney's input from his experience in ageing. Later, Bowman talks talks briefly about his relationship with Phong in Vietnam and how their programs interacted. To conclude his interview, Bowman touches very briefly on IHBI's work with indigenous people in Australia.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_522c7171b6f99c9b261542895f0f682c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Brockman, Brad</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Thurner, Lance</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-06-15/2015-06-15">2015-06-15</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4939d55cb98d4309267dff9adb046006"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Brockman starts off by talking about his childhood, and how he initially went to a school for black elites before going to a white school. He touches on the impact that his family had on his life, because his family was fairly progressive, which led to him developing progressive ideals and believing in organizations like the ANC. He talks about his experience in university, where he initially wanted to become a historian in order to study the anti-apartheid movement and the struggles of activists who helped to bring about the end of the apartheid. Brockman then talks about the work that he did with Equal Education and both how he initially got involved in the organization and what his role has transformed into as his involvement as increased. The interview moves on to talk about how he transitioned within Equal Education to being the head of Youth and Community Development. Brockman ends his interview emphasizing the importance of reflecting back on work that has been done in order to figure out where to move forward, as well as to reflect on the relationships (like the one that Equal Education had with Atlantic) that will and have allowed the organization to continue.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_72664a5fd30d87a5f16ba0198df1356e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Brown, Julie</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Bearman, Peter</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-07-16/2015-07-16">2015-07-16</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a2cbaeec9902048a4a399e7ea59549af"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Julie Brown began by discussing her dad who is Protestant and her mom is Catholic, which led to discrimination within her employment pathway. Once her story gets to Tara Consultants, Brown discusses the anonymity aspects that the foundation required at the time and her impressions of both Chuck Feeney and of working for Tara. She talks about how the organization inspired her to go back to school and to become a successful mother of two. Once changes started to rock Atlantic, Brown went to work in the ageing programs, where she stayed until moving over to the ageing NGO that Atlantic gave money to. Julie highlights her role as a self-proclaimed "bad cop" and how she was the coordinator between Atlantic and grantees that helped insure that they completed the projects that they paid for. Further along in the interview, Brown discusses the changes in her office and in her job after Atlantic experienced the troubles in the early 2000's, as well as her opinions of working under Gara's leadership.  Brown also discusses the different leadership styles under the various CEOs and the tactics that were employed during the spend-down phase. Finally, she concludes with her opinions of the spend-down now that she has experience working for a grantee, arguing that it left a huge void in the philanthropic community in Northern Ireland.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_630343035d50c3c630fc69ae7ed52d3f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Buchanan, Phil</unittitle><origination audience="internal" label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="local">Fairhead, Jonathon Tyrrel</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-02-04/2015-02-23" type="inclusive">2015-02-04-2015-02-23</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4c388d8dd84149be6d3e9cb7ad18ec14"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Buchanan speaks first about CEP's early years and its work in surveying foundation leaders to assess their approaches to strategy and effectiveness. He discusses the history of strategic thinking in the nonprofit world and the work involved in forging reports with foundations, including the process of finding areas of commonality between grantmakers. Buchanan then offers reflections on the development of the Grantee Perception Report and its use for Atlantic's purposes in 2006 and 2010. He speaks about differing approaches to project evaluation and Atlantic's role in legitimizing this field. Buchanan touches upon the role of foundations in politics and the Citizens United case, concluding with thoughts on both limited life philanthropy and the Giving Pledge.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_1ee627e899b2fec524c23ceeb3113efe" level="file"><did><unittitle>Chandra, Amit</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Bertin-Mahieux, Caitlin</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-07-21/2015-07-21">2015-07-21</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_967c83124a200dfe19796a009ace93d0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Chandra discusses how his upbringing and early life shaped his values and influenced his views on philanthropy, including several "inflection points," or moments that directly inspired his later attitudes towards giving. He then describes how reading about Chuck Feeney's philanthropy inspired his own personal philanthropic efforts and his efforts to integrate philanthropy into his career and workplaces. He also talks about the evolution of his giving, and how he has developed giving strategies over time. Chandra describes the program areas in which he has chosen to focus his personal giving, including education, disadvantaged youth, and healthcare, all in urban areas. He then describes the broader giving 'ecosystem' of India, i.e. the various types, sizes, and focuses of NGOs currently present and operational in the country.  Chandra speaks about his work with the First Givers' Club— of which he and his wife are founding members— and his desire to encourage others in India to give while living. He notes, however, that very few Indian families are willing or able to make commitments on the scale of the Giving Pledge, and suggests potential solutions to this issue.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_0a1bca1adfafcd409a98663c1425d991" level="file"><did><unittitle>Clarke, Madeline</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Thurner, Lance</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-07-14/2015-12-04" type="inclusive">2015-07-14-2015-12-04</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3684d901c9235415c953bafa626ebd94"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Madeline Clark speaks about her upbringing in Dublin and the trajectory of her schooling. She discusses her early career in psychology, evaluation, and work on developing a sign language system for people with intellectual disabilities. Clark speaks about her time at Barnardos, the UK's largest children's charity, during which time she helped found the Children's Rights Alliance (CRA). She speaks about the leadership structure of the Alliance, their coordination with government, and their response to the UN Convention on the Rights of the Child. Clark then discusses her contact with Atlantic and the invitation to submit a proposal for CRA funding. She details her work in consulting, her time at Tara House, and the expansion of her work on public health across disadvantaged populations. She wraps up with a discussion about her consulting work with Atlantic on disability services and the formation of Genio as a cross-sector service organization.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_3d7d8e0ceb2ada9da1b2e38abf6bbe67" level="file"><did><unittitle>Coaldrake, Peter</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Gavrilis, George</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2016-03-01/2016-03-01">2016-03-01</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_46e39bc9002b96b4e44969d63febc2a1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Coaldrake begins with the story of how he met Chuck Feeney; he describes his interactions and working relationship with Feeney and outlines Feeney's involvement with programs like Smart State in Queensland. Coaldrake then discusses Atlantic's impact on QUT, including the design and construction of a new campus and the implementation of initiatives to foster community engagement, and how Chuck Feeney's ideas about project scope and management shaped and helped define these efforts. The discussion then shifts back to Smart State— one of the programs that Coaldrake helped to start with Atlantic funding— and how this program represented the relative newness of philanthropy to Australia in general. Finally, Coaldrake closes out the interview with a reflection on the Giving While Living pledge.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_d7853e4b43607d08f4aa5851b16578d7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Coates, Philip</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Bertin-Mahieux, Caitlin</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2016-05-03/2016-05-03">2016-05-03</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_11864911bd4feb1bb07f71fd2918e030"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Coates discusses Atlantic's investment strategy and governance structure, including the various arms of Atlantic's investments. He speaks about the decision to liquidate Atlantic's remaining market-related assets and the impact of the financial crisis on the foundation. He further details the trajectory of Atlantic during Gara LaMarche's leadership, his grant making processes, and the role of the Board throughout this time. Coates concludes with the transition to Chris Oechsli and the final development of financial strategies before his own departure from Atlantic.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_f14b6f973cda0fca6fd813a7fa04dce6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Collins, Eoin</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Bearman, Peter</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-08-27/2015-09-15" type="inclusive">2015-08-27-2015-09-15</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bb3d54b9d374020112685b09c5335277"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Collins begins by describing the bleak atmosphere of 1970s and 1908s Ireland— in general, but especially for LGBTQ-identified people— and the huge shifts towards LGBTQ acceptance beginning in the 1990s. He reviews GLEN's [originally the Gay and Lesbian Equality Network] early history and the genesis of its relationship with Atlantic, then describes the impacts of Atlantic's multi-year grant on GLEN's work and capabilities. For instance, Atlantic funds allowed GLEN to work towards securing the CPB (Civil Partnership Bill), which passed in 2010. Speaking in detail about the bill, he explains that the greatest opposition came from more radical gay and lesbian groups who hated GLEN's incremental approach to gay rights and willingness to compromise with government. Collins also shares several deeply personal stories about his own relationships in the context of gay and lesbian rights in Ireland.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ee053637177dce5ad2529cd85714abc7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Connolly, Paul</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Gavrilis, George</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-12-08/2016-04-05" type="inclusive">2015-12-08-2016-04-05</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e94ab422ab39c818cd10d0bf71e06ac9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Connolly explains studies of how early prejudices can develop in young children. He then covers how that research led to successful programs in Northern Ireland and to establishing Una, a global research network promoting programs for early childhood that are aimed at reducing ethnic conflicts. Connolly also details the inner workings of the Improving Children's Lives Initiative and Centre for Evidence and Social Innovation at Queen's University Belfast. Atlantic Philanthropies funding was key to solidifying and growing all those initiatives, and Connolly discusses his experiences with the foundation.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_f5d99e9d99cc31590545751a2cd673b2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cooke, Sarah</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Gavrilis, George</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-03-27/2015-03-28" type="inclusive">2015-03-27-2015-03-28</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_165f53fcfe41c8951284d70714b7256f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Cooke discusses how the sale of Duty Free Shoppers brought in both substantial funds and an organizational structure to Atlantic, and speaks about the transition of leadership from Harvey Dale to John R. Healy as well as the adoption of the limited life framework. She then discusses the roles of Chuck Feeney and Fitz Schwarz on the appointment of Gara LaMarche as a successor to Healy. Cooke reflects on Healy's impact on the Supreme Court decision to void the death penalty for juveniles and LaMarche's influence in providing a large grant to aid passage of the Affordable Care Act, both achieving social change goals through differing approaches. She goes on to offer commentary on the establishment of the Founding Chairman program, Feeney's unbudgeted spending, and his developing criticism for a number of Atlantic's grants and operational costs. She briefly speaks about Feeney's continuing role in these efforts, even after he took ill in recent years.</p></scopecontent><processinfo id="aspace_c3969664a0f575c941d2b9c31094a616"><head>Processing Information</head><p>Archivist redacted transcript: page 11</p></processinfo></c02><c02 id="aspace_a962dc41c723ad8177c5e217ac07b226" level="file"><did><unittitle>Costello, Tom</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Bertin-Mahieux, Caitlin</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-07-28/2015-07-30" type="inclusive">2015-07-28-2015-07-30</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b024d3c8b53c46d67eaf728a3d5c38b3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Costello begins by reviewing his upbringing and life history, including his work with the Union of Students in Ireland and his efforts to encourage young people to become politically involved. He then traces his early career work in providing job opportunities to young people and developing apprenticeship programs, his recruitment by Tara Consultants, and his transition to Atlantic. He reflects on the impact of using private money to influence public policies and the scope of Atlantic's investments in Ireland. In particular, Costello discusses his work on children's issues in Northern Ireland and America. From here, Costello touches on the foundation's involvement in ageing causes as well as the child poverty issue in Ireland. Lastly, Costello discusses the transition between J.R. Healy to Gara LaMarche, and reflects on his experience with the spend-down process.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_d3495e25c7b312567da406667eb592eb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Denning, Steve</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Farber, Myron A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2014-11-10/2014-11-10">2014-11-10</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_da4b1afc1447d1b6470e6ccdea144ebd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Denning briefly speaks about the consequences of the 2008 stock market downturn for the Atlantic portfolio, which through the generation of liquidity and good investments stabilized within the year. He mentions the disinvestment of General Atlantic in the Atlantic Philanthropies' endowment in 2010, as part of the organization's wind down process. He concludes with a reflection on Chuck Feeney's work and the notion of giving while living.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_b7ab432e0756ed518efdab7fce9bc4b0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Downton, Christine</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Bertin-Mahieux, Caitlin</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-01-16/2015-11-06" type="inclusive">2015-01-16-2015-11-06</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6442cf16b9b452b0b75f7741d469bf8c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Downton begins with a broad overview comparing and contrasting the leadership of J.R. Healy, Gara LaMarche, and Chris Oeschli. She then transitions to discuss her work on AIDS advocacy in South Africa, including the impact of the Treatment Action Campaign. Next, she discusses her experience on the Atlantic investment committee, noting that Atlantic's conservative attitude towards investment helped it weather the 2008 financial downturn. She describes various site visits and fact-finding missions undertaken by the Atlantic Board, most notably to Ireland and Vietnam, and the importance of these trips in connecting the board to the relevance of the grants and the work of the foundation in those locations. Downton then discusses the impact of certain programs, including shared schools in Northern Ireland and the Elev8 program in Oakland, California. Downton closes out the interview with a reflection on her working relationship with Chuck Feeney and how she came to understand his attitudes and the rationale behind many of his goals. Downton then touches Atlantic's LGBT grants in South Africa and Ireland, noting the pushback against those grants by certain members of the foundation's board. The discussion shifts briefly to Atlantic's work on ageing, especially during the tenure of Gara LaMarche, before broadening to a more general conversation about Atlantic's legacy. Downton specifically discusses the role of Atlantic's board in shaping its operations and Downton's own experience of the spend-down process.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_08691d197960be659073c2566fa3102c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fitzgerald, Frances</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Grele, Ronald J.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-07-27/2015-07-27">2015-07-27</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8cdba8593dcc52546eca83d90d837123"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Fitzgerald begins by discussing her political activism within the Irish government, the motivation behind her career choices, and her introduction to Atlantic. She speaks about her early employment as a social worker in hospitals and her inspiration for leading a charge to have more women in government after seeing firsthand the gender imbalance in the Dáil Éireann. Fitzgerald then reflects on the experience she gained working in the European and Irish government sectors, and her initial election to office. She offers further insight into her work with Atlantic, including a presentation see gave to the Board for funding and her views on the foundation's support of political and social change. Fitzgerald touches upon the reputation that Atlantic has in Ireland, where they have been instrumental in committing funds for children's causes, and Atlantic's role in inspiring future philanthropic efforts.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_fc308a6d94d8557bc12ba0c4bcf04e2d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fitzpatrick, Siobhan</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Gavrilis, George</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2016-04-04/2016-04-04">2016-04-04</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2f2fadbdf1f56cc50e3de5ddaecc57bd"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Siobhan Fitzpatrick has been the Chief Executive of Early Years since 1989. In her interview, she  describes how she came to work for Early Years, and the importance of peaceful shared spaces for young children and families before, during, and after the culmination of The Troubles in Norther Ireland. She details the development of the organization with the support of the government and of Atlantic Philanthropies. Atlantic Philanthropies was especially helpful in funding Early Years to gather its own research and evidence for programs. One program discussed in detail is the Media Initiative for Children. Fitzpatrick also talks about her childhood in County Down, and her perspectives on The Troubles as a university student in Belfast.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_640af329acb4f1515ea6384a8269c5f5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fleishman, Joel</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Bertin-Mahieux, Caitlin</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2014-10-16/2014-10-17" type="inclusive">2014-10-16-2014-10-17</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_02e63d74333198f2692e175c3fe9a48d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Fleishman begins with an analysis of the work that foundations do, and then moves into a description of his hectic lifestyle while working for Atlantic. He discusses charitable donations and AP's impactful influence in how they occur. He addresses internal AP conflict. He discusses how the board works. He touches specifically on education.  He discusses leaders that AP has had and evaluates Atlantic on the three essentials that he argues foundations need to succeed (outlined in his book): discipline, boundaries, and persistence.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_a61efb390476066b9e0648f877bf9857" level="file"><did><unittitle>Florino, Joanne</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Bertin-Mahieux, Caitlin</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2014-12-11/2015-04-16" type="inclusive">2014-12-11-2015-04-16</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4145b22ac0a2b55a83eefd3504cda67c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: </p><p>
This initial session was devoted to her career in philanthropy with Atlantic Philanthropies, the Park Foundation and the Triad Foundation prior to her tenure at the Roundtable. The discussion focused for the most part on grants to Cornell University since fourteen million of the first fifteen million in AP grants went to Cornell. Grants discussed include grants to the Arts Center, the Hotel School, The Cornell Tradition, the Cornell Glee Club and various programs in the fields of gerontology, education and faculty development.  She also talked about various grants in the Ithaca area to Ithaca College, Syracuse University and various scientific and cultural institutions in Tomkins County, and the impact of AP on the area. A good deal of the interview centers on various lessons learned about philanthropy from her early experiences. Later, Florine also touches on some of the shortcomings of foundations, drawing from her experience working with multiple foundations to highlight the problems that she's seen within each. Florino also mentions different approaches to foundations, and how they are impacted by various laws and regulations.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_3935e04fb6dc5279d004e37ee9f86b0f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Frazer, Ian</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Clark, Mary Marshall</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2016-03-01/2016-03-01">2016-03-01</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2856f242a5b4ae7dfa9397a840109e80"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Among the subjects discussed in this interview are the value of partnering specialized areas of biomedical science, the significance of having a physical space where they can work effectively together, and how the biomedical sciences are developing both nationally and abroad. Frazer speaks to the inception of TRI, the process of building partnerships, and courting both Atlantic Philanthropies and government funding. He highlights Charles F. Feeney's role in leverageing philanthropy, and inspiring a growing culture of giving in Australia.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_4209765256952117820580eb62dfb683" level="file"><did><unittitle>Freedman, Marc</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Grele, Ronald J.</persname></origination></did><scopecontent id="aspace_723b960a7b5002064b53cfb268aa9b60"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Freedman speaks about his early life and education, particularly how his time at Swarthmore College helped shape his understanding of the world. He discusses his work in various charities, and how these experiences helped spark his fascination with relationships and how much they can help at-risk youth. He further reflects on how Encore developed to both help provide jobs for older people and also support low-income students. Freedman then discusses Encore's relationship with Atlantic, the extensive funding it received from the foundation, and the projects the company has worked on. He goes on to speak about how Atlantic's support shifted over time and the foundation's relationship with its grantees headed into the spend-down efforts.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_14a092276177df40ed1747aea942c801" level="file"><did><unittitle>Gallagher, Tony</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Bearman, Peter</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-07-16/2015-12-06" type="inclusive">2015-07-16-2015-12-06</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_756b39c90faebfe8034ae3dae6495b9c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Gallagher begins by discussing his research work and interests, which have fallen mostly within intersections of education, equality, and social inclusion. He then discusses his current work with the Sharing Education Programme (SEP), beginning in September 2007. Gallagher gives an overview of his family history and upbringing including his experiences of the Troubles and his own role as a student organizer. Gallagher tells the story of how he became acquainted with Atlantic, the secrecy involved in Atlantic's early years of operation, and how Atlantic eventually came to work towards integration— or "shared education"— in Irish schools. Gallagher discusses at length the many trials and obstacles faced and the strategies adopted along the path of this campaign.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_9088384f6e75843c85c5908ce83b7a89" level="file"><did><unittitle>Greenstein, Robert</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Clark, Mary Marshall</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-07-09/2015-07-10" type="inclusive">2015-07-09-2015-07-10</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_55fcd7a4133dd04bbb8842b5a5128906"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Greenstein speaks first about his politically engaged upbringing, including his opposition to the Vietnam War and his work for the U.S. Department of Agriculture during the Carter Administration. He spoke about the establishment of the Center on Budget and Policy Priorities (CBPP) as a separate non-profit to serve unmet public needs when Ronald Reagan took office. He discusses the role of CBPP in supporting organizations doing similar social welfare advocacy work throughout the U.S. and internationally, and their work with the American government. Greenstein then speaks about the CBPP's introduction to Atlantic and coordination with the Foundation's staff.  He wraps up with reflections on the CBPP's plans and long-term strategies for the latest funding granted by Atlantic, and offers thoughts on the spend-down of the Foundation.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 audience="internal" id="aspace_5aea2c953a5650143be2dd1a8b4ded97" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hall, Billy</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Bertin-Mahieux, Caitlin</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2017-06-03/2017-06-03">2017-06-03</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a457e9fd93214f6468882b1af4a7ad05"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Hall begins by reviewing his upbringing and education, then describes how he became associated with Chuck Feeney through Niall O'Dowd. Hall's early work with Feeney included travels in Vietnam, which he describes in some detail, as well as his views on Atlantic's later and current projects in that country. Hall discusses his experience on the Atlantic board, including the turbulence under Gara LaMarche, and Feeney's reaction to that conflict. Hall briefly discusses Feeney's overall view of grantmaking and his preference towards capital projects, then describes Feeney's recent decline in health and the logistical problems resulting from Feeney's subsequent need to take a step back from Atlantic. He discusses the spend-down efforts in detail, focusing on the moral authority of the living donor. Other topics include the Cornell Tech Campus endowment and Feeney's legacy in medicine and public health.</p></scopecontent><processinfo id="aspace_44d90f73e9de2e389ea9d49fc263193d"><head>Processing Information</head><p>Archivist redacted transcript: pages 54, 56-57, 62-64, 84; page  85-87 removed</p></processinfo></c02><c02 id="aspace_f2bf45bcabf850b9f2f7d550efc2a3c8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hau, Nguyen Trong</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Farber, Myron A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2016-05-13/2016-05-13">2016-05-13</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_de05ef4f7e57484b0519b6c042745ebc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Trong Hau Nguyen discusses the projects that he worked on with the ministry of health in Hanoi to try and improve public health faculties and how, in the middle of an ambitious project, he received an invitation to apply to Atlantic in the Hanoi office.  After receiving the offer, Nguyen discusses the long interview process that he went through to get the position.  Once hired, he was introduced to the three main objectives of the Vietnam program: improving primary care health system, improving human resources for health and developing a health advocacy program.  He highlights some of his memorable experiences with Atlantic, and gives an anecdote concerning the relationship between Atlantic and the government.  He also touches upon the challenges and successes of the programs and his times at Atlantic, and how they went about removing funding from the grant programs once the time came to shut down Atlantic.  Toward the end of his interview, he reflects upon how, even though he never met Chuck Feeney, he has a high opinion of him because of his dedication to helping people.  Finally, Nguyen summarizes his interview by talking about what Atlantic's legacy will be now that they have shut down.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_b119bd1d3e6387e6110a158a1ca1d152" level="file"><did><unittitle>Healy, John A.</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Gavrilis, George</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-03-23/2015-06-03" type="inclusive">2015-03-23-2015-06-03</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_142db33acccdf24f6f54d504d4ee5095"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: These interviews emphasize the latter years of Healy's time at Atlantic. He discusses the divided Board reception towards the increased focus on evaluation and strategic planning, and the formation of SLAE to find ways to work with grantees to improve practice. He speaks about the difficulties of evaluating programs in different contexts with the expanded geographic reach of Atlantic and the problematic professionalization of evaluation practice. Healy then discusses the mixed approaches towards the spend-down, with some programs better prepared than others to seek comparable funders after Atlantic's dissolution. He offers thoughts on the surprising increase in the SLAE budget under Gara LaMarche and the transition to a social justice framework, the latter of which caused substantial staff turnover and impacted relations with grantees. In order to avoid another round of reevaluation after LaMarche's departure, Healy speaks about how he chose to depart Atlantic to finish his PhD at Trinity College despite Chris Oechlsi's invitation to stay. He further reflects on Atlantic's effectiveness and legacy in the area of evaluation, and how it may have affected practice more widely in the non-profit sector.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_df4003657e88df8084d8f5892d1a19b4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Healy, John R.</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Bertin-Mahieux, Caitlin</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2017-07-27/2017-07-27">2017-07-27</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_5cfaaf1114e8bf727f379a0e67d3b762"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Healy offers reflections about working with Chuck Feeney, and on changing operations of the philanthropy over time. He provides some specific focus on Atlantic Philanthropies' programs on ageing and youth, as well as work in the geographic regions Ireland and Cuba. Healy also delves into how the limited life model of philanthropy was developed within Atlantic Philanthropies, and reflections on how it worked. Ultimately he provides some speculation about what Atlantic Philanthropies' legacy may be, while acknowledging it may be too soon to tell. Other topics discussed include the Trinity College Center for Nonprofit Management, the Trinity Foundation, and the Community Foundation for Northern Ireland.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_07a410a05e89f05f55b23e70be61c71e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Holtzman, Dmitri</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Thurner, Lance</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-07-09/2015-07-09">2015-07-09</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_507c882e90ad4629daa58a14c4831ca4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Holtzman speaks about his mother's (Zelda Holtzman) involvement in the armed struggle, her training in Angola, and detention by the apartheid security apparatus. He discusses his upbringing and education in Cape Town, and his mother's appointment to Deputy Commissioner of the Police for the Western Cape after the fall of apartheid. Holtzman then discusses his politicization during his legal studies at the University of Cape Town and University of the Western Cape, his introduction to Doron Isaacs, and contributions towards Students for Law and Social Justice. He reflects on his work in social justice-oriented Jewish youth camps at Habonim Dror and role in helping establish Equal Education (EE) as an activist, research, and policy writing organization. Holtzman wraps up with thoughts on the founding of the Equal Education Law Center, and the role of lawyers within social movements like EE.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_be11afb772a3a24d318058a093fc8511" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hughes, Joanne</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Bertin-Mahieux, Caitlin</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2016-04-05/2016-04-05">2016-04-05</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cea38e0fe22d1a41a788b6c067c37dc0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Hughes describes her longitudinal research in shared education in Northern Ireland. A central focus is the role of Atlantic Philanthropies' funding for shared education research at Queen's University. She describes her working relationship with Atlantic Philanthropies, and the impact of their support. Hughes also talks about potential implementations of shared education models abroad, providing examples of its strengths and challenges from her work in Macedonia. Other subjects include her experiences growing up in aProtestant community of East Belfast to her PhD research in the 1980s on integrated education.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_9069d9c6a609b557eb4553b753d8c036" level="file"><did><unittitle>Isaacs, Doran</unittitle><origination audience="internal" label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="local">Fairhead, Jonathon Tyrrel</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-06-24/2015-06-24">2015-06-24</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b9f1cebd19e4ae555529e06461602105"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Isaacs speaks about his introduction to politics through the Jewish youth camp Habonim. He discusses his work with the Treatment Action Campaign, and the establishment of Students for Law and Social Justice at the University of Cape Town. Isaacs speaks about his early efforts at Equal Education and offers reflections on the multiple strands of leftist thinking and activism in South Africa. He continues to discuss Zachie Achmat's founding of the Applied Education Research Organization in 2008 and its transformation to Equal Education one year later, with an emphasis on collaborative structures and reporting back to its member-constituents. Isaacs concludes by reflecting on the people and processes that helped the organization cross lines of race, class, and understanding as they began to canvas the community and observe the state of schooling.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_78c7489466c6d51cbdf48f31b85cfab7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Johnston, Patrick</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Bertin-Mahieux, Caitlin</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-03-031/2015-03-031">2015-03-031</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ecaa2f24c3b6ed298ebe8eb4ec2ba469"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Johnston speaks about the impact of Chuck Feeney and Atlantic funding on the development of the University, including the renovation of central buildings and the creation of the Centre for Experimental Medicine. He discusses the development of the Centre for Cancer Research and Cell Biology (CCRBC) with the help of Atlantic, and its impact at Queen's and on cancer survival rates in Northern Ireland. Johnston wraps up by discussing the state of philanthropy in Northern Ireland.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_102bc856210e8915f23d00d9a0a33eab" level="file"><did><unittitle>Katz, Stanley</unittitle><origination audience="internal" label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="local">Fairhead, Jonathon Tyrrel</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-04-29/2015-04-29">2015-04-29</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e8e75f37e2a82e2c3ddfafb000f1aac0"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Katz begins by discussing the varying methods foundations employ to keep track of their donations and the importance of recordkeeping to the philanthropic field. He discusses the various approaches to philanthropy employed by different foundations and the challenges faced by the field overall. Next, he gives an overview of the material he teaches in a seminar on philanthropy and non-profits, and what he has gained from working with young people in this class. Katz then narrows in on the impact of the philanthropic sector versus the charity sector, and how the Atlantic model has changed what these both look like. Katz also addresses the broader impacts that a foundation like Atlantic appears to have had on the field as a whole. Finally, Katz addresses what he believes the implications of Atlantic going out of business will mean for the foundations still running.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_8c57274885fabbb7a2c56f9db51cf435" level="file"><did><unittitle>Kearney-Grieve, Brian</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Gavrilis, George</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-12-14/2015-12-14">2015-12-14</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_e2b296b89f09b7acff59a1458b9c40e5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Kearney-Grieve reflects on the Board's difficult discussion not to focus on Travellers and gender issues due to the contentious and broad scope of these matters in Ireland, and speaks about the establishment of partners and advocates as a way to balance the constraints of his small staff. Kearney-Grieve then discusses the differing approaches between the church and Atlantic's programs— the former providing services and the latter choosing a path of systematic change by funding network-building, advocacy efforts, and litigation. Finally, Kearney-Grieve reflects on the role of international networks in the cross-pollination of ideas, and Atlantic's restructuring by country versus thematic concentrations under Gara LaMarche. He discusses Christopher Oeschli's decision to end support to offices and causes earlier than expected, and the anticipated legacy of Atlantic's wind down on the organizations it funded. Kearney-Grieve concludes by offering thoughts on Atlantic's role in creating sectoral and social transformation, professionalization, and legal infrastructure in Ireland.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_3bd5fe0777a4958b3b6d4ce586807a86" level="file"><did><unittitle>Kelly, Regis</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Bearman, Peter</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2014-12-13/2014-12-13">2014-12-13</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7b1f623c1c30197d8e3d70dda3deb321"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Kelly has known Chuck Feeney since 2004 and worked intimately with him on the development of the University of California, San Francisco (UCSF) Mission Bay campus. He speaks about Feeney's interest in donating buildings for their permanence and long-term impact, and discusses the development of Atlantic Philanthropies under Gara LaMarche, particularly the organization's focus on funding advocacy initiatives. He further reflects on their close friendship and Feeney's recent decline in health.</p></scopecontent><processinfo id="aspace_5be6e80dd032f2766067057229a1c4b3"><head>Processing Information</head><p>Archivist redacted transcript: pages 75, 79; pages 76-78 removed.</p></processinfo></c02><c02 id="aspace_1b219a8f0e0e616c95633b199d30a939" level="file"><did><unittitle>Kennedy, David</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Gavrilis, George</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2016-03-30/2016-04-01" type="inclusive">2016-03-30-2016-04-01</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bcbfdab9cc4aed9c2672406f9f416c9f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: In this interview Kennedy discusses vetting a funding proposal for Victor Chang Cardiac Research Institute, and how he then came to establish an Atlantic Philanthropies office for Feeney in New South Wales, Australia. Kennedy also reflects on leadership styles of different Atlantic Philanthropies CEOs, as well as his perspective on the organization's interactions with Feeney as founder. He also illustrates the influence Feeney had on the culture of philanthropic giving in Australia</p></scopecontent><processinfo id="aspace_22a1469c93a9f594bb21b1565d738876"><head>Processing Information</head><p>Archivist redacted transcript: pages 24, 102, 104; page 103 removed</p></processinfo></c02><c02 id="aspace_4ef5c940c6e13f449b9a5b274f5b85b0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Kenny, Rose Anne</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Farber, Myron A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-12-03/2015-12-03">2015-12-03</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0db573f9fc6fb60572d8ff547869fd03"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Kenny discusses recent trends in geriatric medicine and education on ageing. She speaks about St. James Hospital's initial approach to Atlantic for funding in partnership with Health Service Executive. She goes on to offer reflection on the objectives of TILDA and its work with preexisting international datasets on ageing. Kenny wraps up with thoughts on the flexibility and shared passion offered by Atlantic as a grantee.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_a16a72adc0a9d5f30d3a22e3b769a959" level="file"><did><unittitle>Kerman, Ben</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Bearman, Peter</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2014-12-16/2014-12-17" type="inclusive">2014-12-16-2014-12-17</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2dc2ab2aad512fbcec9fe9a3f0846b15"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Kerman discusses the development of a field of professional evaluators and its impact on philanthropy. He speaks about evaluating the vast scope of Atlantic's efforts and difficulties involved in measuring advocacy, particularly immigration reform. He reflects further on the process of curating Atlantic's legacy, with an emphasis on timeliness, transparency, and targeted and user-friendly reports. Kerman concludes with a discussion of the process of dismantling Atlantic's staff and offices, including the challenges, missteps, and expectations that have occurred along the way.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_ab7e3e83fecf0b891dcb9b845eaccca0" level="file"><did><unittitle>LaMarche, Gara</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Bertin-Mahieux, Caitlin</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-04-27/2015-04-27">2015-04-27</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_17062103e8f2b84184c40e422d82cd64"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: LaMarche begins with the process of being hired to Atlantic Philanthropies and early interactions with the search committee and Chuck Feeney. He then goes into depth about developing a focus for Atlantic Philanthropies' mission, addressing staffing issues, and taking full advantage of the 501(c)4 status to invest in political advocacy.  He touches on some of the key misunderstandings that took place between himself, Feeney, and the board in his latter years with Atlantic Philanthropies.</p></scopecontent><processinfo id="aspace_2206e41f61389057456d3a8d541ba996"><head>Processing Information</head><p>Archivist redacted transcript: page 10</p></processinfo></c02><c02 id="aspace_5785881fa152004cb2f8683330afc2dd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Lightfoot, Sara Lawrence</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Thurner, Lance</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-05-04/2015-05-05" type="inclusive">2015-05-04-2015-05-05</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_683684d83772c7a5b4d3ad7af48347c5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Lawrence-Lightfoot begins by reviewing her upbringing and education in some detail. She briefly discusses her experiences with philanthropic organizations before Atlantic, including the MacArthur foundation, before describing her early impressions of Atlantic and how she came to be involved with the Atlantic board. Lawrence-Lightfoot offers her impressions of and views on Chuck Feeney and John R. Healy, the conflict between Feeney and the Atlantic board under Gara LaMarche, and the evolution of the Atlantic board over time. Other topics include the evolution and genesis of Atlantic's racial equity program, Lawrence-Lightfoot's vision for the end of Atlantic, and Atlantic's place in the changing philanthropic landscape, and its impact and legacy.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_180f65c3c1b7ef22e4655f6fa28bc0ec" level="file"><did><unittitle>Love, Janet</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Clark, Mary Marshall</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-07-20/2015-07-21" type="inclusive">2015-07-20-2015-07-21</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9906e8b6f6194953c58ca2b62f272de3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Love speaks about her family and upbringing; early on volunteering, organizing, and activism. She reflects on her work in exile in Europe and Africa, including work with the African Council of Trade Unions and other organizations. Love then speaks about her undercover work in South Africa with Operation Vula, her role in the Council for a Democratic South Africa (CODESA) negotiations, her election to the first ANC parliament, and her efforts in helping draft the South African constitution. She speaks about her work at the Reserve Bank and transition to the Legal Resources Centre, where she reconnected with Gerald Kraak, Program Executive for Atlantic's Reconciliation and Human Rights Program. She goes on reflect on the transition of LRC's relationship with Atlantic in regards to the spend-down and Kraak's recommendations to diversify funding streams. Love wraps up with thoughts on the development of the Constitutional Fund by Atlantic and the lasting impact of support from the Open Society Foundation.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_17f9917b249270fc7d1ca1577881f1ef" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mandikizela, Zola</unittitle><origination audience="internal" label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="local">Fairhead, Jonathon Tyrrel</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-07-03/2016-01-11" type="inclusive">2015-07-03-2016-01-11</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f663adcf4409899f0642accc012192cc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Zola Madikizela's childhood in the rural Eastern Cape in the then "homeland" of the Transkei, his resultant politicization as part of the Madikizela clan, his education, and his work in media and public health for the government and UN during the transition to democracy. Madikizela discusses their recruitment to Atlantic Philanthropies, their 14 years working within the organization, and specifically their work around HIV/AIDS through the Treatment Action Campaign, funded by The Atlantic Philanthropies. Madikizela discusses other health initiatives including efforts to retain nurses in South Africa and The Atlantic Philanthropies funding approach.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_a57cde999329b185b1252a7436fc43f6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Matousek, Robert</unittitle><origination audience="internal" label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="local">Fairhead, Jonathon Tyrrel</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-09-16/2015-09-17" type="inclusive">2015-09-16-2015-09-17</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a67852e89c519b65f704843f9b12947b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Matousek describes his early encounters with Chuck Feeney and how he formed a friendly relationship with Feeney during his experience working for DFS throughout the 1970s. The strength of friendship meant that Feeney often asked Matousek for help with solving problems both personal and professional. Matousek describes finding out about Feeney's philanthropy and being asked to evaluate a number of Feeney's early philanthropic efforts as Feeney's personal emissary to places such as Australia, Cuba, Thailand, Cambodia, and Vietnam. Matousek discusses Feeney's current health and activities and describes the roots and outcomes of Feeney's conflict with the Atlantic board between 2009 and 2011. Finally, he discusses Feeney's view of the Giving Pledge and Feeney's own legacy.</p></scopecontent><processinfo id="aspace_a458f9a8d4e2bc68f65d35a54616d20d"><head>Processing Information</head><p>Archivist redacted transcript: pages  104, 107, 121, 123-125, 149 ; pages 105-106, 122 removed</p></processinfo></c02><c02 id="aspace_c6fef521214083b068001643b365d9ce" level="file"><did><unittitle>McConnell, Stephen</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Farber, Myron A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-11-15/2016-06-16" type="inclusive">2015-11-15-2016-06-16</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_115339f0197091f13e428b1aa3a86bdc"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Among the experiences he recalls from working with Atlantic Philanthropies, McConnell offers his perspective into how the field of ageing advocacy is unique in the US, and on the ways philanthropy and government can play a role. His reflections on the work of the Civic Participation Action fund include examinations of politically involved non-profits and effective tools for voter engagement. This interview also includes memories of his time as Chief of Staff for US Senate ageing Committee in the '70s and '80s. In addition, he describes his role as Vice President of Public Policy for the Alzheimer's Association, and opening their Public Policy Office in DC in 1989.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_997d3bddcfcce4f475cdd5aa988fd2d7" level="file"><did><unittitle>McCormack, Elizabeth</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Clark, Mary Marshall</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-02-20/2015-03-20" type="inclusive">2015-02-20-2015-03-20</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_dc541cf98644fcb5eae71497a27b2b7e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: McCormack responds to Conor O'Clery's book, The Billionaire Who Wasn't. Specifically, she attempts to expand on a narrow representation of conflicts within Atlantic Philanthropies' leadership in 2010, which concluded as Gara LaMarche stepped down as President and CEO, and the Atlantic Philanthropies Board went through reorganization. Events described include, McCormack's recruitment to the Board of Atlantic Philanthropies in 1996, her early impressions of Charles F. Feeney, the search for a new President and CEO in 2006 to replace John A. Healy, and the hiring of Gara LaMarche in 2007. McCormack also reflects on different philanthropy models and provides comparisons between foundations she has served and advised over her long career.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_51f05602a0f1860b0e6424767c8481f7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Miller, Bruce</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Clark, Mary Marshall</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2016-02-16/2016-02-16">2016-02-16</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_17a961d830eabbc588a0bc265602f88a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Miller describes how GBHI was conceived, as well as its core goals and potential legacy. Also detailed in this interview, is his research on the Alzheimer's disease and dementia. He covers his early work with Frank Benson at University of California, Los Angeles, in the 1980s, when dementia research was slowly beginning to gain more recognition. He also explains how the field has grown, how he came to University of California, San Francisco, and the trajectory in between.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_fd4760eda8b982a0f1a0019af534b262" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mitchell, Tom</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Bertin-Mahieux, Caitlin</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2014-12-18/2015-09-08" type="inclusive">2014-12-18-2015-09-08</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_2c3706b7890c77ecf1c9981c4106f21f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Mitchell speaks about the 2002 adoption of Atlantic's core programs and evaluative measures, and then discusses recent programs in Ireland, including initiatives for disadvantaged youth and ageing. He goes on to reflect on the search for a new CEO following John R. Healy and Chuck Feeney's unbudgeted spending. Mitchell discusses Gara LaMarche's growing emphasis on social justice, advocacy, and capacity building. He discusses Feeney's concerns about the financial crisis and management of the Foundation, including growing tension with the Board, a report about senior management, and appointment of Chris Oeschli. He reflects on the establishment of the GOAL program, limited-life philanthropy, and Feeney's role in Giving While Living. Mitchell wraps up with a reflection on Atlantic's impact in Ireland and some reflections on the spend-down efforts and the unexpected longevity of this last phase of funding.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_8fe5f99e3010d12418bf626487407603" level="file"><did><unittitle>Morino, Mario</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Gavrilis, George</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2014-11-14/2015-05-19" type="inclusive">2014-11-14-2015-05-19</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b1ccd8e087aa89e3ca9a220f3438099c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Morino starts off his interview with a discussion of his childhood, and how growing up in a poor/working-class family shaped how he perceived helping others because of how his community would come together to help people when they needed it. Morino, throughout his interview, talks extensively about what philanthropy means to him and how he has interacted with the philanthropy world, even though he does not like the word "philanthropy" itself. Morino discusses his time at General Atlantic, and how he moved from that field to doing more philanthropic work with his own institution, the Morino Institution and with Venture Philanthropy Partners. Morino talks briefly about his relationship with Chuck Feeney and how he became involved with Atlantic, specifically mentioning that he greatly respected Feeney and used the Atlantic model as a guide for his own philanthropies. At the end of the interview, the interviewer asks Morino questions specifically about his view of the world, and the new economy. These questions, while unusual for these types of oral histories, provide insight about Morino and wrap up his interview on a more personal note.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_e4478008beb9245c5485101d7a0e4e23" level="file"><did><unittitle>Morse, David</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Grele, Ronald J.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2016-07-12/2016-08-09" type="inclusive">2016-07-12-2016-08-09</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b720e0ffa71ad9ba30e58fecd7cb6015"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Morse begins by reviewing his educational and early employment history, including his early work in government with the Senate's Education, Arts, and Humanities Subcommittee. He then discusses his transition to and roles at the University of Pennsylvania, the Pew Charitable Trusts, and then the Robert Wood Johnson Foundation. He speaks about the differences in leadership and organizational style between the latter two foundations and the impact of the passage of the 2008 recession on the Johnson Foundation's endowment. Morse then outlines how he came to Atlantic and how he came to understand the Atlantic philosophy of philanthropy and how it translated into organizational structure. Finally, David reviews his experience with the spend-down process and closes out the interview with a brief recollection of the 2007 book by Conor O'Clery that outed Chuck Feeney as the man behind Atlantic.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_129847c772ff2f35848b0b193def348f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Munoz, Cecilia</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Bertin-Mahieux, Caitlin</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2014-12-15/2015-04-01" type="inclusive">2014-12-15-2015-04-01</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f38e33cb5a291c95dcc401efb30ff778"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Muñoz provides an overview of the prospects for comprehensive immigration reform during the Bill Clinton and George W. Bush administrations, with the latter indicating interest in pursuing concrete measures prior to the terrorist attacks of September 11, 2001, before shifting to an emphasis on border security. Muñoz reflects on the process of getting Democrats on board with immigration reform throughout the Obama administration and being in the position of having to defend the White House to movement leaders during this process.  She speaks about Atlantic's role in helping the movement regroup, convening major activists for a consequential weekend retreat, and offering effective hand-off funding to invest in the cause.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_8890c3be4aff1e63936dba7b7c2f448b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Murray, Paul</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Thurner, Lance</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-12-07/2015-12-07">2015-12-07</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b3f75ed67d36cebdc97b325933b2a57c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Murray provides some context about his early career with non-government organizations in Northern Ireland during the cease fire and the end of the Troubles. He joined Atlantic Philanthropies when it was Tara Consultants and still operated anonymously. The foundation and leadership changed considerably over his time there, and he shares his perspective on those changes from the vantage point of his country and program area. Murray details the development of the Children and Youth Program at Atlantic Philanthropies, as well as some of their signature grants such as Early Years.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_05a8235e1773894d4a90ec38376a3b98" level="file"><did><unittitle>O'Brien, Martin</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Bertin-Mahieux, Caitlin</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-05-27/2015-05-28" type="inclusive">2015-05-27-2015-05-28</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b2c889f017d28ba165bfbc924fa87f05"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: O'Brien begins by discussing his recruitment to Youth for Peace and his role in peace processes in Northern Ireland, like the Good Friday Agreement. He reflects on his work with the Committee on the Administration of Justice and unexpectedly filling the role of Program Executive at Atlantic. O'Brien offers thoughts on Chuck Feeney's influence, and the importance of both global networking and peer review in their program. He goes on to speak about the social justice framework put in place under Gara LaMarche and the tensions that arose at that time. The conversation transitions into a discussion about his work on Atlantic's strategic review process, including the assessment, spend-down, and sustainability of funding to grantees. He concludes with the establishment of the Social Change Initiative and its support for emerging human rights activists.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_f28efa90dcec25d6418a332491c5b402" level="file"><did><unittitle>O'Connell, Brian</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Thurner, Lance</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-07-01/2015-07-08" type="inclusive">2015-07-01-2015-07-08</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_322a02ed928b208ed4574f67eed24a84"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: O'Connell was a lecturer at UWC  and served as superintendent general for the Western Cape before being appointed rector of UWC in 2001. He is told that UWC is slated to be immediately closed, declared bankrupt, or absorbed into another university.UWC was at this time mainly known for its work in the humanities. It has a small public health program, which is why Atlantic on a tour of its projects in South Africa decided to make a quick stop at UWC. It had received small support in the past from Atlantic. There are several things that are noteworthy about this visit. It occurs during the transition of Chuck Feeney running the Philanthropy single-handedly to the passing of its administration to the board. He is touring all of the work the foundation has done with his new board when they make what they have planned to be a quick stop at UWC. Had the visit come a year later, UWC might not have benefited so tremendously from Mr. Feeney's generosity: it is the connection between just two people, Feeney and O'Connell, that leads to the massive capital expansion of UWC's campus. The decision is made and acted upon within 24 hours.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_de855e6ca9c5b04227ccb356c3c9a568" level="file"><did><unittitle>O'Dowd, Niall</unittitle><origination audience="internal" label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="local">Fairhead, Jonathon Tyrrel</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2014-09-24/2014-10-01" type="inclusive">2014-09-24-2014-10-01</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4aa9390bfd09cc2623160c206ea68831"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: These sessions include further reflections on the Troubles, the cease-fires in 1994, and the proposal of a Truth and Reconciliation commission. O'Dowd reflects on the work of Irish and British ministers in the Downing Street Declaration and Good Friday Agreement. He discusses President Bill Clinton's role in advancing the peace process and Feeney's funding for Friends of Sinn Fein. O'Dowd speaks about Atlantic Philanthropies' involvement in reconciliation projects, and the development of Feeney's philanthropic contributions and legacy.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_32518628c8a3ab9150234c12f069bcd5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Oeschsli, Chris</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Farber, Myron A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2016-04-14/2016-08-03" type="inclusive">2016-04-14-2016-08-03</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_77ef245d5c8b76392c24df40acd96c54"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Chris succeeded Gara as CEO in 2011.  Ron and Amy conducted four sessions with Chris in 2006, focusing on his then-roles as program director, economic and legal advisor to Atlantic. Chris spent approximately three years apart from Atlantic working in DC, but reconnected with Chuck in 2009 and played a key role in leading Chuck and AP through the internal crisis.</p></scopecontent><processinfo id="aspace_283caf2bd07bab8572808bf4412a8678"><head>Processing Information</head><p>Archivist redacted transcript: page 106</p></processinfo></c02><c02 id="aspace_38a27bcbb4bd79788c1eac64109e1ab4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Parker, Alan</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Gavrilis, George</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2017-04-28/2017-04-28">2017-04-28</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b42e2370c3d5f4e6dfe0ea73f04458b9"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Parker discusses his relationship with Chuck Feeney, Chuck's relationship with Atlantic leadership in recent years, and his and Chuck's relationships with the other two (of four) original partners in Duty Free Shoppers (DFS). Parker gives his opinion on Chuck Feeney's decision to not include his children in the running of Atlantic and compares that decision to his own choice to include his family in the Oak Foundation. He also describes the leadership, grant making, and program area organizational structures at Oak and how they differ from their counterparts at Atlantic. Parker also discusses how Chuck has influenced his own views on philanthropy and how those views have evolved over the years. Finally, he describes the challenges of evaluating philanthropic work.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 audience="internal" id="aspace_4adb47520949177d190f0fdd862d518a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Pendry, Christine</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Bertin-Mahieux, Caitlin</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2017-07-05/2017-07-05">2017-07-05</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_10a6765910babddc2ebfc6c8f5d0c2c2"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Pending revisions from Pendry and potential redaction of audio. See correspondence.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 audience="internal" id="aspace_8c3774a005c1320c19a4106140371418" level="file"><did><unittitle>Phu, Bui Duc</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Bertin-Mahieux, Caitlin</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2016-05-12/2016-05-12">2016-05-12</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_710ed3b9bf94447e2dcf8785f410e507"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: ...Chuck Feeny promises to aid in the construction of a cardiac center if the pediatric projecthe funds is successfully built and functional.  By this time Atlantic Philanthropies has established its office in Hanoi. In 2003, the AP board visits to aid Feeny in his decision because the project fund has become quite large. The board grants $3.8 million dollars for the construction of the building after intense interviewing and promises the complete sum (of $10 million) incrementally over a period within which Phu's hospital is expected to meet goals before being rewarded subsequent portions of the project fund. Bui draws architectural inspiration for the design of the new cardiac center from France, which is completed in 2007. It is the first of its kind and Bui begins to contact community centers and non-profits to acquire patients in need of care. He creates a children's fund and begins a list that names potential candidates for surgery. Bui's hospital becomes an example and teams from the Ministry of Health visit to study its model. Bui's hospital continues to functionally operate and Atlantic maintains their promise, granting the hospital its next installment for medical equipment and training for its doctors. Phu thanks Atlantic for its generosity – for giving doctors work in Vietnam and ailing peoples the access to care. He laments about Atlantic's imminent close and voices concern over the fact that his hospital will now have to self-sustain.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_b58e3389341da02af5819adc500e2e96" level="file"><did><unittitle>Phuong, Le Nhan</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Bertin-Mahieux, Caitlin</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2016-05-17/2016-05-17">2016-05-17</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ba698c6bb11193c04229a25cc1c3c0c7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: In Le Nhan Phuong's interview, he begins with a discussion of his experience working for Atlantic as Gara was taking over as CEO.  He specifically touches upon how Gara re-focused the aim of the Vietnam programs on social justice, and how one of the lasting legacies of the Atlantic's Vietnam program is the development of a social worker profession, which didn't exist before.  From here, Phuong states that he was very thankful that Chuck stepped back and allowed the Vietnam people create their program into something sustainable and something that could be continued in the future, even after Atlantic closed its doors.  Phuong talks about the struggles during troubled times at the organization and how it seemed like Chuck would get mad with everyone's suggestions and would refuse to give his approval to donations because of a bad meeting.  He also notes how, because of the distance, most of what he heard about the struggles in the organization at this time was just through the grapevine of the organization and not from immediately witnessing it.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_648b778ab948f9e7651f3dfe6ab91cda" level="file"><did><unittitle>Proscio, Tony</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Farber, Myron A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-01-20/2015-01-21" type="inclusive">2015-01-20-2015-01-21</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ec4fb46248a3c63550dca5133889cd83"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Proscio speaks about the process of researching and writing the reports for Atlantic and the meetings he shared with Chuck Feeney. He discusses Feeney in relation to other philanthropists, and their differing approaches to anonymity, secrecy, and control. Proscio reflects on the work of John Healy and Tom Tierney in bringing a sense of order to the Foundation in 2001 and implementing key decisions about the spend-down process. He goes on to discuss the development and contributions of major Atlantic programs in South Africa, Viet Nam, and Ireland. Proscio reflects on Atlantic's role in advocacy and politics, and the transitioning dynamics and leadership of the Foundation in regards to these topics. He reflects on the spend-down process timeline, the unveiling of its legacy over time, and the sustainability of the organizations and causes Atlantic has funded.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_3cf6fcbc3f0107b3696587c58c697af3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Quinn, Marian</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Bertin-Mahieux, Caitlin</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2016-04-06/2016-04-06">2016-04-06</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_8715eeba52262f4f7e36d445a6ba9677"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Quinn details the earliest days of CDI, the staffing process, building a strong work environment, and developing their goals and programs. Atlantic Philanthropies helped introduce evaluation structures that CDI built on in order to monitor their programs' successes and to quickly adapt if desired outcomes were not met. Quinn gives a few examples of programs that had to be phased out over time, as well as examples of programs that could be successfully mainstreamed. Other subjects discussed include advice from others working in disadvantaged communities, the importance of partnerships with established local organizations, and how to encourage parents' involvement. She concludes with her thoughts on the process of closing CDI at the end of Atlantic Philanthropies' funding, and the prospects of local partners carrying on the programs developed at CDI.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_0427d81afccb259b8f8adfe3d841a2e2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Quirk, Padraic</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Gavrilis, George</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-03-30/2015-03-30">2015-03-30</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_68135589a71c3e8e71b8cd81d0a06552"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Quirk speaks about his early work at Atlantic around reconciliation and Atlantic's position outside of public scrutiny in Northern Ireland. He discusses the differing leadership styles within Atlantic, including those of John Healy, Gara LaMarche, Chris Oeschli, and Martin O'Brien. He goes on to reflect on SPUR and Atlantic's grantmaking to universities in Ireland and Northern Ireland. Quirk offers insight into peace building processes in Northern Ireland and navigating sectarianism as a grantmaker. He adiscusses exchange strategies between Atlantic's Northern Ireland and South Africa offices. Quirk wraps up with reflections on Atlantic's role in supporting shared education and advocacy efforts through the Children and Youth and Ageing Programs.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_b1a7ba9c05b69a2b8c60fc57bb196fb1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Quyen, Duong Hoang</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Bertin-Mahieux, Caitlin</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2016-05-16/2016-05-16">2016-05-16</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_691dc1e85659270efaf6cf9be3165da6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: In Quyen's interview, she begins talking about her personal history, and how coming from a family of doctors influenced her to enter into the medical profession as well.  She then moves on to a discussion of her time at UNAIDS and how during her tenure there she worked to change the way that people and politicians thought about public health issues.  From here she talks about how the Gates Foundation helped her get her degree in Public Health, which helped further her career in the sector.  After that she talks about when she first considered joining Atlantic, only she didn't know what it was when she applied for her position.  She goes into a discussion of the hiring process that Atlantic had at the time and how, throughout a three month trial probationary period, she eventually learned the truth about the organization that Atlantic actually is.  From here she discusses the initiatives that she worked on to help increase the public health standards in Vietnam, specifically touching on changes to ambulatory/paramedic responses and tobacco control.  Quyen then speaks about how she is most proud of the contributions that Atlantic was able to make in the field of social work and how collaboration with other Atlantic programs in different countries helped her develop programs in Vietnam.  Overall, Quyen ends her interview on an appreciative note, remarking upon how glad she was to have worked for Atlantic and how much it shaped her direction in life.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_0b25b4d9dad6b80ffeb7fea9c3760058" level="file"><did><unittitle>Richards, Cynthia</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Thurner, Lance</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-02-25/2015-02-25">2015-02-25</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_684ce1d4050da9421d455945d847ab8e"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: This session picks up with Richards discussing the last days of working under John Healy, and the expectations of Gara LaMarche as he joined Atlantic. She discusses LaMarche's leadership style, division isolation, turnovers in staff, the hiring of consultants, and reorganization of the grantmaking side of Atlantic from theme to country. Richards discusses the development of the Advocacy Fund and growing emphasis on social justice causes. She discusses the move of Atlantic's offices to Varick Street and the impact of the economic recession, including the creation of cash caps on their programs. She wraps up with reflections on the divide between new and longtime staffers, and LaMarche's tenure and legacy.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_fc54b5885d5db9756933af14a09268c6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Robertson, Ian</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Bertin-Mahieux, Caitlin</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2016-04-07/2016-04-07">2016-04-07</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_203fc2c5b6d9aa321e69453d5f540dd8"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Robertson explains the impetus for beginning GBHI. He also describes his experiences of working with Atlantic Philanthropies over the course of a decade. Other topics detailed in this interview include the intersections of dementia research and socialequity, and how the field of neuroscience has grown to acknowledge potential for rehabilitation of damaged brain cells.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_9304ad535a632eecd4c258987448a344" level="file"><did><unittitle>Romero, Anthony</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Clark, Mary Marshall</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2014-11-12/2014-11-12">2014-11-12</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_f98b0f7663ec26b2499db4ce63073476"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: In this oral history interview, Romero recalls his earliest experiences with the ACLU in 2001, a year which held the September eleventh terrorist attacks, and the enactment of the U.S.A. Patriot Act. He explains how those events marked a new era of acute challenges to civil liberties in America, and a continued need for the efforts of the ACLU. When the financial crisis of 2008 hit, the ACLU's funding base was weakened. The Atlantic Philanthropies' support was crucial to the organization's continued stability during that time. Romero also comments on more contemporary developments, including his views on several controversial actions by the Barack Obama Administration, and the Fourth Amendment implications of Edward Snowden's revelations about government data surveillance.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_44add56113c9c1ab7351ffcf48d51929" level="file"><did><unittitle>Rose, Kieran</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Gavrilis, George</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-09-01/2015-09-13" type="inclusive">2015-09-01-2015-09-13</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_533b74933cf8f17c82742da10d3be757"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Rose gives a brief overview of the history of LGBTQ rights in Ireland from the 1960s through the 1980s, then reviews his involvement with GLEN, beginning with its founding in 1988 and its early efforts in response to the HIV crisis and Ireland's criminalization of homosexuality. Rose then describes the process and effects of the infusion of Atlantic money into GLEN's operations through a multi-year grant, including Atlantic's efforts (in part through the grant) to unite various wings of a somewhat fractured gay rights movement, each with various goals and approaches. Like his GLEN colleagues Eoin Collins and Brian Sheehan, Rose discusses GLEN's work on the Civil Partnership Bill— which made marriage equality law in Ireland— and how its efforts to pass the bill were greatly aided by Atlantic funding.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_9501389c9b0011b759ac3fb036f516ce" level="file"><did><unittitle>Rosenthal, Jack</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Clark, Mary Marshall</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-09-28/2015-09-28">2015-09-28</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d16e1dc4ac3599e07cc49c0a35d7411c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Rosenthal discusses the work he undertook in cleaning up Atlantic's portfolio and the creation of his brainchild: the Journalism Institutes. Aimed at educating journalists from around the country on issues deemed to be bereft of coverage, these programs were both popular and informative, and raised awareness of the programs Atlantic was running. Rosenthal further explores his efforts to bring internet connection to people with low socio-economic status, something that he partnered with Atlantic to help raise funds to do. He concludes by touching upon his work in ReServe and Experience Corps, both of which are Atlantic grantees, as well as his friendship with Gara LaMarche.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_3929b054a6678bb3a9469643c5f90520" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sachs, Albie</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Gavrilis, George</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-05-19/2015-05-19">2015-05-19</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_eeb485e311db78c38e1358aeda93bba1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Sachs discusses South Africa in the 1990s, including the political violence present at that time, the creation of post-apartheid political processes, and Atlantic's growing involvement in supporting pre-existing advocacy efforts. He reflects on Atlantic's approaches, which included secrecy, flexibility, and initially a lack of measurement, which he describes as being surprisingly productive. Albie shares memories of his meetings with ex-political prisoners in Belfast from both sides of the conflict, and about critical cases in the post-apartheid Constitutional Court, in South Africa. Albie offers discussion of the human rights advocacy community and a comparison to attempts to create a Bill of Rights in Northern Ireland, supported by Atlantic. He wraps up with reflections on the work of Atlantic and the Ford Foundation in South Africa, and the present dearth of home-grown philanthropy in the country.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_101f1e9731d7a4c4180a601ed2ac34e7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Schwarz, Fritz</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Farber, Myron A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2014-11-12/2014-11-13" type="inclusive">2014-11-12-2014-11-13</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_44831deb5ae1f8815e68f60530ec4bed"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Schwarz discusses the diversification of Atlantic's grantgiving after the sale of Duty Free Shoppers, including reflections on targeted countries. He speaks about the arrival of John Healy, and the new organizational structures and programs funded for social change under his leadership. Schwarz then speaks about manageing Feeney's unbudgeted expenditure and his role as a head of the search committee that recommended Gara LaMarche. He discusses LaMarche's emphasis on social justice, collaborative funding, and efforts to diversify Atlantic's staff. He speaks about the impact of the economic recession on Atlantic, and Feeney's concern about the potential for debt and developing direction of the organization. Schwarz discusses the conflict that unfolded between Feeney and the Board, and LaMarche's eventual resignation as president, as well as his own from the Board.</p></scopecontent><processinfo id="aspace_4b1e2aa0d2fb22477ef0d3e2d3c80fb1"><head>Processing Information</head><p>Archivist redacted transcript: page 23</p></processinfo></c02><c02 id="aspace_6badd8ba3e7485e492e5caf7eaee57f8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sefali, Pharie</unittitle><origination audience="internal" label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="local">Fairhead, Jonathon Tyrrel</persname></origination></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4c2487d57c8a901cd4e0ae30d0355f3a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Sefali speaks about her upbringing and education in the townships and suburbs surrounding Cape Town, South Africa. She discusses her transition after the fall of apartheid between a well-resourced formerly white school to an under-resourced predominantly black school as leading to her politicization. Sefali reflects on the student march she lead to the Minister of Education as contributing to Equal Education's (EE) decision to approach her to organize a more measured campaign. Sefali speaks about her study of social work at the University of the Western Cape, and continued involvement in EE as one of their leading community organizers and organizers of their youth camps. She discusses her decision to move back to Llanga, a working class black township, and the initial skepticism she received from the community. She wraps up with a reflection on her recent training to become a sangoma and the present-day activism that is occurring in Llanga.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_9070c1e131d110e67f84334f59b32be9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sharry, Frank</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Thurner, Lance</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2014-11-18/2014-11-19" type="inclusive">2014-11-18-2014-11-19</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_228b6ca6f48b85736c4646ac8ac011cf"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Sharry discusses the struggle for immigration reform since 1990, concentrating on 2008 to 2014. He speaks about how activists interpreted the failure of the 2007 McCain-Kennedy bill and how they planned to reorganize themselves for the Obama administration. Sharry focuses on the growing capacity building of the movement, particularly the integration of grassroots and national-level activists, and their increasing political and tech savviness. He reflects on the role of Atlantic in creating the conditions for this movement, the movement's successes and failures, the role of evaluation, and the implications of limited life philanthropy for America's Voice. AV was not provided a large final grant from Atlantic to establish a more permanent source of funding and now is facing a nearly 50% reduction of its budget.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_f87bb570830b3c189ac30e44eb7ee564" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sheehan, Brian</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Gavrilis, George</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-09-07/2015-09-08" type="inclusive">2015-09-07-2015-09-08</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_224fb60793aa9bb714b95c650065e09b"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Like his GLEN colleagues Eoin Collins and Kieran Rose, Sheehan begins by painting a picture of the atmosphere and social context of Ireland during his upbringing and describing how he came to be involved with GLEN. He describes how a chance encounter brought GLEN in contact with Atlantic and how that partnership played out in a series of increasing grants. Sheehan discusses GLEN's work on the passage of the Civil Partnership Bill and its efforts to counter homophobic bullying in Irish schools, and repeatedly credits AP support for the above outcomes. Other topics include AP's involvement in the transgender rights movement in Ireland and the broader landscape of philanthropy in Ireland in general.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_dd61adb5f1e5529850a73b9fc1ec9fa6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sinte, Norma</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Gavrilis, George</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-03-31/2015-03-31">2015-03-31</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0a509e834a50167ae410cd8a24e70620"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Sinte speaks about her education at Queen's and how the university has changed over time, noting how the renovation of key buildings with Atlantic's support helped transform the quality of the campus. She discusses fundraising efforts in the late 1990s by Allan McClay and Sir George Bain, the latter of which helped encourage Chuck Feeney to consider donating to Northern Ireland's universities. She wraps up with insight into Atlantic's support of the creation of the Development office at Queen's and the centers the foundation helped establish in its extensive giving process.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_39c2914da12701b40cfa0d71afe17c12" level="file"><did><unittitle>Skorton, David</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Farber, Myron A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-02-11/2015-02-11">2015-02-11</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_060f97ea6d1185af91ae72b0e1869c7a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: At the time of his Skorton's arrival to Cornell in 2006, Chuck Feeney had already anonymously donated about $600 million to his alma mater. Devoting one-third of his time to fundraising, Skorton met with an enthusiastic Feeney soon into his term. After Atlantic concluded its funding of higher education and Cornell's endowment was impacted by the recession, Feeney remained receptive to Skorton's appeal for increased financial aid for students. Skorton discusses the range of Atlantic's expansive contributions to Cornell, including its $350 million commitment in 2011 to the Cornell Tech campus on Roosevelt Island in New York City. He speaks about the partnership of Cornell and Haifa-based Technion University to bring new graduate populations in STEM to the city, and his gratitude for Feeney's contribution to the cause, which has served as the largest single donation to Cornell in its history.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_55f4c60bb2d3ac37408b1184a61532ab" level="file"><did><unittitle>Smith, Brad</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Thurner, Lance</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2014-10-24/2014-10-30" type="inclusive">2014-10-24-2014-10-30</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_0815dc06cd13b5bf6b870b9044db1d0f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Smith traces changes in the role of American philanthropy at home and abroad, and how major transitions in information technology were visible throughout his long career in the field. He discusses transparency and Chuck Feeney's decision for anonymity, offering a comparison between Feeney's vision of Atlantic and the philanthropic work of other partners in Duty Free Shoppers, like Alan Parker of the Oak Foundation. Finally, Smith discusses the use of evaluation in philanthropy and changes in how philanthropists have approached and discussed evaluation throughout his career. He speaks about the institutional rearrangement between the Foundation Center and Atlantic Philanthropies, and ends with reflections on how the Giving Pledge might impact philanthropy in the future, especially after Atlantic sunsets.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_90c98562f42ebe56457f064602cca252" level="file"><did><unittitle>Smith, Dave</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Farber, Myron A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-04-30/2015-05-01" type="inclusive">2015-04-30-2015-05-01</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4efbdfddffa678b06c03320b38f127bf"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Smith speaks about his decision to leave Levi Strauss &amp; Co., where he was Vice President and Treasurer, to work with Chuck Feeney in 1986. He discusses his personal relationship with Feeney and their joint business ventures in California. Smith offers insight into Feeney's donations towards the University of California at San Francisco and Oakland School for the Arts. Smith goes on to discuss GAGL's efforts to liquidate all of its holdings for the benefit of Atlantic, and Feeney's equity investments through General Atlantic Partners. He reflects on Feeney's predilection towards donating buildings, and his perspectives on the leadership of Atlantic under Gara LaMarche and the Board during LaMarche's tenure. Smith wraps up with insight into Feeney's decision to invest in Cornell Tech on Roosevelt Island in New York City, his interest in the Giving Pledge, and considerations of legacy.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_29d0b81e0b97cc64b7446cef4fbd11d7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Smitham, Peter</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Gavrilis, George</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2016-03-17/2016-03-17">2016-03-17</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_9b5dc902b5945c0ad7b72e863d522f3d"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Smitham tells the story of the recruitment of Gara LaMarche to Atlantic and describes in detail and offers analysis of the 2009-2011 conflict within Atlantic leadership. He also discusses the Atlantic board's involvement in the grantmaking process, the overall impact of Atlantic grants in places like Texas, South Africa, Northern Ireland, and Vietnam, and the attitudes within Atlantic leadership on strategies for how the greatest impact is to be attained. Smitham then explains in great detail the designs of the spend-down process, including staff cuts and capstone grants. Also discussed is Atlantic's narrative about itself as it winds down towards the end, the Giving Pledge, and Smitham's advice to future philanthropists.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_64d87a94759c76364c858b7ce876958a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sovern, Michael</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Starecheski, Amy A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-06-02/2015-06-02">2015-06-02</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bc3743aa0bcc570518edb9a57c71e06f"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Previous sessions covered his experiences as a member of the Board prior to his resignation and a voluminous biographical interview is being reviewed for deposit in the archives. In this session, Sovern returns to his early years with Atlantic, including reflections on the role of the Foundation in advocacy efforts. He reflects on the notion of strategic philanthropy, the legacy of Atlantic, and longterm impact of their grantees. Sovern offers commentary on the impact of the economic recession on Atlantic, the process of spend-down, and the tension that developed between Feeney and the Board. He wraps up with a discussion of the transitions between John R. Healy, Gara LaMarche, and Chris Oechsli.</p></scopecontent><processinfo id="aspace_10ae5f58f8373b11761bc10b92d49898"><head>Processing Information</head><p>Archivist redacted transcript: pages 10-11, 48</p></processinfo></c02><c02 id="aspace_27f6af4a78f7183404256554bb436e52" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sternlieb, David</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Thurner, Lance</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-01-13/2015-01-20" type="inclusive">2015-01-13-2015-01-20</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ed08bd74edb6e452c5a2502b392cdcda"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: In these sessions, Sternlieb discusses preparations for the spend-down process, including adjusting investments and compensating for Chuck Feeney's unbudgeted gift-giving. He reflects on the formation of the Advocacy Fund in order to support U.S. social causes after Bipartisan Campaign Reform Act was passed and the impact of Citizens United on c(4) funding in national politics. Sternlieb offers insight into John Healey, Gara LaMarche, and Chris Oechsli's legacies at Atlantic, including organization, management, professionalization, bureaucracy, and spending cuts. He covers changes in the structure and role of the Board of Directors as Atlantic winds down. Finally, Sternlieb reflects on the process of closing of the programs in Vietnam and South Africa.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_1a72ec70b0471b959bd5bb5d4f18a1af" level="file"><did><unittitle>Stone, Chris</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Gavrilis, George</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-05-21/2015-05-21">2015-05-21</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_be2227c5d90673f06192b064eb0b24ac"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Stone begins with the story of his decision to become a public defender and his work in that field, especially in South Africa. He speaks in detail about Atlantic's leaders over the years, including Harvey Dale, Chris Oeschli, John Healy, and Gara LaMarche, as well as Stone's and OSF's relationship with OSF and some similarities and differences to Chuck Feeney's relationship with Atlantic. Other topics include the challenges of working with a living donor, the downside of spend-down philanthropy, and Atlantic's impact in South Africa.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_577de33e6e344fb71d1b71551c1ac51f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sutton, Mary</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Thurner, Lance</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-03-24/2015-06-02" type="inclusive">2015-03-24-2015-06-02</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_14fb2450ed3d5700f38ef325facdbb81"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Sutton speaks first about her upbringing, including her experiences with the progressive and outspoken Catholic social teachings of the time. Sutton reflects on the initial interview she had with Atlantic for a new position and her eventual hire by Irish Aid, which made a turn toward evaluative measures short after her arrival. She offers insight into the changing international development community, reflecting on the role of the United Nations Millennium Development Goals and local governments. Sutton speaks about her experiences as Atlantic's Program Director for Ageing, emphasizing the shift from palliative care to dementia research. She discusses the administrative transitions between Gara LaMarche and Chris Oechsli, and the impact the internal review process had on honing the vision of Atlantic in light of the spend-down. Sutton wraps up with reflections on the process of closing the Dublin office and the achievements of Atlantic at large.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_12b150fd80ea0a092f5420510db8db93" level="file"><did><unittitle>Walsh, Dave</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Farber, Myron A.</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-04-16/2015-04-17" type="inclusive">2015-04-16-2015-04-17</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_bc719a9d1759e43aad40bfa5197884fa"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Walsh gives a brief overview of his career history as an accountant and how it led him to Atlantic in the 1990s, while Atlantic was still operating anonymously. Walsh describes his working relationship with Chuck Feeney and gives some insight to Feeney's business and leadership style and how it translated into the internal structure of Atlantic. Walsh speaks about the respective leadership regimes of John Healy, Harvey Dale, Gara LaMarche, and Chris Oeschli, including the 2009-2011 conflict within the Atlantic leadership that occurred during LaMarche's tenure. Other topics include the Giving Pledge and the Alantic spend-down process.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_43016a74b6828f1cefa86e17bc670014" level="file"><did><unittitle>Young, Ian</unittitle><origination label="creator"><persname role="ivr" source="ingest">Bertin-Mahieux, Caitlin</persname></origination><unitdate normal="2015-07-15/2015-07-15">2015-07-15</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_24e1e51b2e82a548cab6723e07ab2856"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Topics discussed during interview: Young speaks about growing up in Belfast and the importance of education in his family. He discusses his experiences of coming of age during The Troubles, and witnessing the tension and violence present in Northern Ireland at the time. Young reflects on the transitions that occurred in Belfast throughout his professional career, nearly the entire of which was spent at Queens. He offers insight into how, through his early focus on diseases of older age, came a natural interest in ageing. Young then speaks about his initial work with Atlantic in developing a long-term ageing study in Northern Ireland, in part, to explore the long-term effects of The Troubles. He discusses Atlantic's contributions to NICOLA both in terms of supporting the infrastructure and research, which has since allowed him to leverage significant funding from other sources.</p></scopecontent></c02></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
